<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
<atom:link href="http://origin.augusta.com/masters/app/coursetour.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
<title>Masters  Course Tour</title>
<link>http://origin.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour</link>
<description>The Masters at Augusta National Golf Club </description>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 1 - Tea Olive</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole1/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 445 yards:  The slight dogleg right is not the easiest tee shot golfers will face. Carrying the fairway bunker will require a drive of 300 yards, and shorter hitters will face an uphill shot to the undulating green. </description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 1</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 2 - Dogwood</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole2/index.html</link>
<description>Par 5, 575 yards: A slight draw off the tee sets up a chance to reach the par-5 green in two. Bunkers in front of the green often come into play. </description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 2</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 3 - Flowering Peach</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole3/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 350 yards: Most players opt for position off the tee with a long iron or a fairway wood. The small green, which slopes from right to left, is not entirely visible from the fairway. </description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 3</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 4 - Flowering Crabapple</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole4/index.html</link>
<description>Par 3, 240 yards: This tough par-3 requires a long-iron shot to the green, which is guarded by a pair of bunkers.  </description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 4</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 5 - Magnolia</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole5/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 455 yards: The deep fairway bunkers on the left require a carry of 315 yards around the dogleg. Large humps in the green make it a challenging putting surface. </description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 5</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 6 - Juniper</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole6/index.html</link>
<description>Par 3, 180 yards: This downhill par-3 usually requires no more than a medium iron to the large, undulating green. Put the ball on the wrong part of the green, however, and a three-putt is likely.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 6</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 7 - Pampas</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole7/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 450 yards: The new tee installed in 2002 puts a driver back into most players&#039; hands. The hole features a narrow fairway to an elevated, well-bunkered green.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 7</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 8 - Yellow Jasmine</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole8/index.html</link>
<description>Par 5, 570 yards: A large fairway bunker makes this par-5 difficult to reach in two shots. A blind uphill shot awaits those who are tempted to go for it in two.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 8</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 9 - Carolina Cherry</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole9/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 460 yards: The severely sloped green makes par a challenge. Accuracy off the tee is required, and approach shots that are short of the target often roll off the green.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 9</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 10 - Camelia</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole10/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 495 yards: Historically the toughest hole at Augusta National, the tee shot requires a hard hook to gain extra distance. Drives that go too far right will leave a long second shot; if they go too far left, trees are a problem.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 10</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 11 - White Dogwood</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole11/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 505 yards: The start of Amen Corner is the most difficult hole in recent years because of its added length. A slight fade off the tee is necessary to reach the fairway. The greenside pond is more of a factor, because players have longer shots into the green.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 11</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 12 - Golden Bell</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole12/index.html</link>
<description>Par 3, 155 yards: The shortest hole is a bear to play because of swirling winds. It&#039;s usually a medium- or short-iron shot to a narrow green that is protected by Rae?s Creek in front and azaleas behind.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 12</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 13 - Azalea</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole13/index.html</link>
<description>Par 5, 510 yards: The classic risk-reward hole became more challenging with a new tee added in 2002. A slight draw is required to get into position for the second shot to the par-5, but a tributary of the creek catches shots that come up short.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 13</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 14 - Chinese Fir</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole14/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 440 yards: It&#039;s the only hole on the course without a bunker, but a severe green provides plenty of problems. Players often have to hit driver instead of a 3-wood, and a sloping fairway kicks shots into trouble on the right. Large undulations on the green make this the trickiest to putt.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 14</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 15 - Fire Thorn</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole15/index.html</link>
<description>Par 5, 530 yards: Changes made in the last decade make reaching this par-5 hole in two shots a challenge, but plenty of birdies will be had. A pond guards the green in front, but those who lay up face a hard shot from a downhill lie.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 15</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 16 - Redbud</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole16/index.html</link>
<description>Par 3, 170 yards: This par-3 requires anything from a short- to medium-iron shot. The green is the hole&#039;s main defense; being below the hole is a must. The back bunker and a pond on the left also pose hazards.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 16</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 17 - Nandina</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole17/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 440 yards:  For most players, No. 17 is a short-iron second shot into a rock-hard green.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 17</guid>
</item>

<item>
<title>Hole No. 18 - Holly</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/mobile/coursetour/hole18/index.html</link>
<description>Par 4, 465 yards: The closing hole has become a 465-yard challenge with the extension of the tee in 2002. An accurate drive is a must, and an expanded bunker complex requires a clout of 335 yards to carry. Trees to the left of the bunkers prevent a bailout on that side, and the elevated green is guarded by bunkers.</description>
<guid isPermaLink="false">hole id 18</guid>
</item>
</channel>

</rss>
