<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.augusta.com/mrss/feed/21" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
<title></title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/feeds/21.xml</link>
<description></description>
<language>en</language>
<item>
<title>Back issues force Woods to skip Bay Hill</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/back-issues-force-woods-skip-bay-hill</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/tiger-withdraw.jpg" /></div><p> ORLANDO, Fla. &nbsp;&mdash; Tiger Woods withdrew from the Arnold Palmer Invitational on Tuesday because of persistent pain in his back, creating even more uncertainty for golf's No. 1 player with the Masters Tournament only three weeks away.</p><p> And that's if Woods can even play in the Masters, where he has won four times.</p><p> "I personally called Arnold today to tell him that, sadly, I won't be able to play in his tournament this year," Woods said on his Web site.</p><p> "I would like to express my regrets to the Orlando fans, the volunteers, the tournament staff and the sponsors for having to miss the event. Unfortunately, my back spasms and the pain haven't subsided."</p><p> Woods had to withdraw after 13 holes of the final round at the Honda Classic three weeks ago because of what he called back spasms and pain in his lower back. He tried to defend his title the following week at Doral, only for his back to flare up again in the final round. He closed with a 78, the highest Sunday score of his PGA Tour career and the first final round without a birdie.</p><p> After a week of rest and treatment, he didn't feel fit to play Bay Hill, where he is an eight-time winner, including the past two years.</p><p> "I am certainly sorry that Tiger is not able to play," Palmer said. "Quite obviously, we will miss having him here this week. He called me to tell me that his back was still giving him a lot of trouble and he didn't feel he should play. I told him I understood and wished him well."</p><p> This is only the second time that Woods has not played Bay Hill. He also missed in 2010 when he sat out more than four months during the scandal in his personal life.</p><p> The Masters, which is April 10-13, is the only major Woods has never missed.</p><p> "It's too early to know about the Masters, and I will continue to be evaluable and work closely with my doctors," Woods said. "I feel badly that I won't be able to play in this great tournament this week."</p><p> Woods first showed signs of back pain at Bethpage Black at The Barclays in 2012, which he attributed to a soft bed at his hotel. He felt twinges during the final round of the PGA Championship last year, and when his back bothered him in the final round of The Barclays two weeks later, he said it was unrelated.</p><p> This has been the longest sustained problem with the lower back. "A bad back is no joke," Woods said at Doral.</p><p> Woods is off to the worst start of his 18 years on tour.</p><p> At Torrey Pines, where his eight victories included a U.S. Open, Woods shot his highest score on American soil with a 79 to miss the 54-hole cut. He tied for 41st in the Dubai Desert Classic a week later for his worst finish in that event.</p><p> Woods had said he spent his offseason working on his body and didn't spend enough time on his game, so it was troubling for him to then deal with yet another injury. He shot a 65 in the third round of the Honda Classic before having what he described as back spasms similar to The Barclays last year.</p><p> At Doral, he was only three shots out of the lead going into the final round and in the penultimate group when he said an awkward stance while playing out of a bunker on the sixth fairway of the Blue Monster caused his back to start hurting again.</p><p> "That's what set it off and then it was done after that," Woods said at Doral. "Just see if I could actually manage ... keep the spasms at bay."</p><p> Woods had said at the start of the Florida swing that he was taking a look at his schedule leading up to the Masters, though he never made it clear if he intended to add another tournament. Woods rarely gives a "yes" or "no" to questions pertaining to his plans.</p><p> He has never played the week before any major except for the PGA Championship.</p><p> In 2010, after revelations of extramarital affairs, Woods had gone 145 days without hitting a meaningful shot when he arrived at Augusta National. He opened with a 68, his lowest first-round score ever at the Masters, and wound up in a tie for fourth.</p><p> Swing coach Sean Foley said he would not read too much into how Woods can prepare for the Masters if he can play.</p><p> "I've been coaching on tour long enough now to know that Tuesday doesn't affect Wednesday. There's no rhyme or reason to performance," Foley said in a telephone interview. "Tiger is always about the majors, and he's solely about the majors now. He's got to do the right thing. He's just doing the right due diligence about it."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 19:44:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2647 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>John Senden wins Valspar Championship, earns Masters invite</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/john-senden-wins-valspar-championship-earns-masters-invite</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p><p>PALM HARBOR, Fla. &mdash; More than seven years without a victory. A trip to Augusta National riding on the outcome. A three-way tie for the lead going into a daunting three-hole closing stretch called "The Snake Pit&rdquo; on the Copperhead course of Innisbrook.</p><p>John Senden was trying to keep his mind off all of that Sunday in the Valspar Championship.</p><p>The finish will be hard for him to forget.</p><p>Senden chipped in for birdie from 70 feet on the 16th hole, one of only two birdies in the final round at the toughest hole on the course. He followed that with a 20-foot birdie putt to build a two-shot lead, then made it tough for Kevin Na to catch him with perfect pace on a 40-foot putt on the 18th that left him only a tap-in for par.</p><p>Senden closed with a 1-under 70 and had enough strength left to hoist a trophy he said felt like 50 pounds.</p><p>"I didn't turn my phone on because I know there's going to be 4,000 messages,&rdquo; Senden said. "It feels good to do it again after seven years. Lot of good things to come.&rdquo;</p><p>One of them is next month &ndash; the Masters Tournament.</p><p>The 42-year-old Australian was No. 123 in the world and his only hope of returning to Augusta National for a third straight year was to win. That didn't look likely after opening with rounds of 71-72, leaving him in the middle of the pack. He had a bogey-free 64 on Saturday to get back into contention, then closed it off on a wild and windy final round with Innisbrook as tough as it had been all week.</p><p>"If I could just stay in the moment, I knew I was swinging well enough to give it a shake,&rdquo; Senden said.</p><p>Na recovered from an atrocious finish to his front nine &lt;0x2014&gt; including a double bogey when he missed a 3-foot putt &lt;0x2014&gt; to make it interesting. He nearly drove into the water on the 16th and escaped with par. He holed a 15-foot birdie putt on the 17th to get within one shot. But his pitching wedge out of the first cut of rough on the 18th hole sailed long, and 40-foot birdie putt to force a playoff never came close.</p><p>Na closed with a 72 and finished one shot behind.</p><p>"I knew coming into today that I felt like if I shot par I had a chance to win,&rdquo; Na said. "If I break par, I felt like it was going to be a lock.&rdquo;</p><p>He did neither, though his runner-up finish was his best PGA Tour result since he won in Las Vegas toward the end of the 2011 season. And there were no issues with pace of play that brought Na the wrong kind of attention &lt;0x2014&gt; again &lt;0x2014&gt; on Saturday.</p><p>Senden finished at 7-under 277, the third straight tournament on the Florida swing won with a single-digit score under par.</p><p>Scott Langley, hitting superb shots to account for the wind, didn't hit a green over the final four holes and still managed to save par on three of them. The one bogey on the 16th hole, when he went long of the green from the middle of the fairway, proved costly.</p><p>Langley was the only player who shot par or better all four days. He closed with a 70 to finish alone in third.</p><p>Robert Garrigus started the final round with a one-shot lead, and that didn't last long. His tee shot on the third hole bounced off a lawn chair and against a tree, leading to a double bogey. He made another double bogey on No. 6 and went out in 41. And he went 26 holes without a birdie. By the time he made a birdie, it was too late. Garrigus, now 0-4 with at least a share of the 54-hole lead, had a 75 to tie for fourth at 4 under.</p><p>"I know what I'm not going to be doing next year &lt;0x2014&gt; fishing,&rdquo; said Garrigus, who figures he caught three dozen large-mouth bass this week. "I'm going to bring a damn chain saw out to the place and cut a few trees down. I kept hitting it behind them all day. I just didn't get any breaks.&rdquo;</p><p>Will MacKenzie ran off four birdies in a five-hole stretch around the turn and closed with a 69. He tied for fourth with Luke Donald (70) and Garrigus.</p><p>Justin Rose had five bogeys over seven holes in the middle of his round and shot 74, a disappointing day for the world's No. 7 player who had started the final round just three shots out of the lead. In a fitting end, he missed a 4-foot birdie putt on his last hole.</p><p>Senden last won a tournament at Royal Sydney at the end of 2006 in the Australian Open. Earlier that year, he picked up his first PGA Tour win at the John Deere Classic. He didn't imagine going more than seven years until his next win.</p><p>"It's something that makes you believe more than you can get it done again, rather than just once and thinking back then in &lsquo;06, &lsquo;Was it a flash in the pan ' I don't believe so,&rdquo; Senden said. "But now it makes me feel (validated) from the John Deere.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:45:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2642 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Patrick Reed gets third PGA Tour win</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/patrick-reed-gets-third-pga-tour-win</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>DORAL, Fla. - The guy in the red shirt won again.</p><p>Patrick Reed, that is, not his hero Tiger Woods, the No. 1-ranked player in the world who never challenged Reed on Sunday.</p><p>Reed, a former Augusta State All-American, hung on to win the WGC-Cadillac Championship by a shot over Bubba Watson and Wales' Jamie Donaldson for his third career PGA Tour victory in his past 14 starts - all the wins coming while wearing a final-round red shirt.</p><p>That's the same color shirt Woods, a 79-time winner on the PGA Tour, has worn in final rounds for his entire career, which includes 14 major championship victories. </p><p>Reed, 23, was solid and steady in Sunday's final round at Trump National Doral's Blue Monster course, striking for three birdies against three bogeys for even-par 72. Watson had 68 and Donaldson shot 70.</p><p>Woods, three back heading into the final round and playing in the group directly in front of Reed, struggled to 78 and tied for 25th place.</p><p>Reed said he always wears a red shirt and black pants in final rounds because that's what Woods does.</p><p>"Well, the best player ever to live when I was growing up wore black pants and a red shirt," Reed said. " I was growing up watching him, I always thought, "you know, it would be cool to wear black and red come down Sunday.' I did it when I was in juniors, I did it in amateur golf, and you know, it's worked.  Obviously there's something behind it."</p><p>Of his three career victories, this was Reed's only in which Woods was in the field. Woods appeared in position to challenge Reed on Sunday after a third-round 66 left him three shots off the lead. But Woods, who afterward said he was battling the same back pain that forced him to withdraw at last week's final round of the Honda Classic after eight holes, was 3-over after six holes on Sunday and did not make a birdie.</p><p>"Of course it does," Reed said when asked if the win was special because Woods was in the field. "It's Tiger Woods.  He's the best golfer probably ever to live, and it's one of those things that whenever he's in the field, you always are looking where his name is."</p><p>Reed, a Texas native who grew up in Baton Rouge, La., entered the final round with a two-shot lead. By the turn, he had extended it to four shots, then fell back on the back nine. He settled for bogey on the dangerous 18th hole for 2-over 38 on the back to become the youngest-ever World Golf Championships winner. </p><p>The previous youngest winner  That would be Woods.</p><p>With opening rounds of 68-75-69, Reed was a wire-to-wire winner, finishing at 4-under 284 for four trips over the Gil Hanese-redesigned course that saw the field - which featured 49 of the world's top 50 players - dunk 318 balls in the water for the week, including 113 in Friday's second round when the winds reached 36 mph.</p><p>In his second full year on the PGA Tour, Reed has now earned $3,492,000 for the trio of wins, all since August. He and Jimmy Walker, who has three victories this season, are the only players with more than one win this season.</p><p>How hot is Reed  He's won $3,492,000 for the trio of wins, and moved up to third on the PGA Tour money list this season, third in the FedEx Cup standings and to 20th in the world ranking. He was ranked 369th the week of this tournament last year and entered this week's event 44th.</p><p>After Sunday's victory, Reed said he believes he's among the top five players in the world because of all he's done in the past seven months.</p><p>The timing of the latest victory is perfect for Reed, who will be making his Masters Tournament debut on April 7 at Augusta National Golf Club, which is located 10 minutes from Augusta State, where he went to college for his sophomore and junior years, leading the Jaguars to national titles before turning pro.</p><p>"That's going to be a treat walking down that first fairway at Augusta," said Reed, who believes he can be in the mix to be the third player to win a green jacket in his first start.</p><p>Walker will also be making his debut in the Masters, which means he and Reed will be the first players since Denis Watson in 1984 to make their Masters debut after winning three times since the previous year's Masters.</p><p>On Sunday, Reed continued his prowess as a frontrunner, He also held or shared the lead going into the final round of both his other PGA Tour victories. In the Wyndham Championship in August, he had a piece of the lead, and at the Humana Challenge in mid-January, where he opened with three consecutive 63s and led by seven after three rounds and won by two. </p><p>At Augusta State, Reed had a 6-0 match-play record in the NCAA Championships that the Jaguars won in 2010 and 2011.</p><p>He also led his high school golf team - University High in Baton Rouge - to state championship in his junior and senior years.</p><p>It did get interesting at the end on Sunday. After three early birdies followed by nine consecutive pars, Reed made his second bogey of the day, on No. 14, missing a 4-footer. That cut his lead to two shots over Watson, who had just finished his round. A few minutes later, Donaldson birdied No. 17 to pull within one shot of Reed.</p><p>Reed saved par from the bunker on No. 15 to remain one shot ahead, then two-putted from 54 feet on No. 17 to save another par. Donaldson bunkered his approach on No. 18 and missed a 12-footer for par, meaning Reed had a two-shot going to No. 18, and he knew it.</p><p>On the 18th hole, he played the par-4 like a par 5, hitting and iron off the tee and hitting the green in three shots and two-putting for bogey and the one-shot victory.</p><p>"I just hit 3-iron to the right because I know that's not going to get into the trees," Reed said. "So I was playing for that right rough and laid up with 7-iron, had 80 yards, hit a little wedge to the middle of the green and easy 2 putt. </p><p> ]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 01:04:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2615 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott rebuilt whole approach with winning majors in mind</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/scott-rebuilt-whole-approach-winning-majors-mind</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406ADAM%20SCOTT%2011%20YEARS.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>GOLD COAST, Australia &ndash; Where did the spark come from to become the first Australian to win the Masters Tournament </p><p>Perhaps it started as an 8-year-old taking his first swings on a par-3 course in Adelaide.</p><p>Maybe it percolated through formative years watching countryman Greg Norman suffer repeated Augusta heartbreaks.</p><p>Or it might spring from the disappointment of losing a four-shot lead with four to play at the 2012 British Open.</p><p>All of these things certainly added up in the evolution of Adam Scott from prodigy to Masters champion. But his ultimate triumph grew from his deepest slump.</p><p>"It's like the politician saying it's the recession we have to have,&rdquo; Scott said. "I think those things have to happen. It might have been for me.&rdquo;</p><p>The bottom wasn't the 2009 PGA Championship at Hazeltine when Scott shot 82-79 and beat only five club professionals. It wasn't even the four-and-a-half months he went without breaking 70.</p><p>He reached bottom in the form of an ordinary 64th-place check at the 2009 Colonial, three months before Hazeltine.</p><p>"That was the point where I actually made the cut for the first time in a few months and it was still rubbish,&rdquo; Scott said. "I finally made one there and it was just rubbish anyway. I just thought I'm not doing the right stuff here. Something's not in place and it's not going to change just by making a cut.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott's carefully crafted career trajectory was slipping away faster than a putt on Augusta National's greens. He was losing his grip on the promise to be one of golf's greatest players.</p><p>In 16 months that bridged 2008 and most of 2009, Scott went from No. 3 in the world &ndash; featured in the marquee pairing with Nos. 1 and 2 Tiger Woods and Phil Mickelson in the U.S. Open at Torrey Pines &ndash; to No. 65, requiring a charitable captain's pick into the Presidents Cup from his hero and mentor Norman. His status for the next year's Masters was unqualified.</p><p>Scott was "a statistical mess&rdquo; and mired in what he bluntly admits was "the worst year of my life.&rdquo;</p><p>"I was kind of out of my depth, which is what it felt like,&rdquo; he said of the only slump of his career. "I was just treading water and slowly kind of drowning out there.&rdquo;</p><p>Many factors contributed to his professional free fall &ndash; a broken hand that got smashed in a car door before the U.S. Open; a break-up with his longtime girlfriend, Marie Kojzar; a "mystery illness&rdquo; that haunted him with recurring throat infections doctors could best attribute to fatigue; and a kneecap he dislocated running out of the surf in Queensland at the end of 2008.</p><p>It all added up to what Scott called "bad habits&rdquo; that invaded his once pristine swing and eroded his confidence. He missed 10 of 15 cuts on the PGA Tour, including six in a row and three of the four majors.</p><p>Of course, it's not how you hit rock bottom that matters &ndash; it's how you climb out of it. Scott took the opportunity to come back better than he was before &ndash; to rethink, retool and rebuild his whole approach toward a single-minded goal of winning major championships.</p><p>"I wanted to show everyone how good a golfer I was,&rdquo; Scott said.</p><p>Scott emerged as an improved version of his early self. And his journey to Masters Tournament champion is an Australian tale unlike any other.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> BEFORE THE FALL</p><p>Most golfers' full careers are less accomplished than Scott's was by age 28 &ndash; seven PGA Tour wins including the 2004 Players Championship and 2006 Tour Championship; six more European Tour victories; and two wins in Asia for a combined 15 worldwide in nine seasons since turning pro in 2000.</p><p>He was already a member of three Presidents Cup teams and a fixture in the world's top 10.</p><p>"I hope he breaks all my records,&rdquo; Norman said after Scott won the Players at age 23. "His swing is technically better at this point than Tiger Woods at this stage. He can be doing what Tiger did, soon. He can go along and eclipse all of us.&rdquo;</p><p>No pressure there.</p><p>"At the age I was and where I was at when winning the Players Championship in 2004, it all just happened kind of easily,&rdquo; Scott told The Australian in 2008. "You just expect it to keep happening.&rdquo;</p><p>Everybody had expected as much since he was a teenager.</p><p>Geoff Ogilvy, the 2006 U.S. Open champion from Victoria, was three years older than a 14-year-old Scott when they first met in a junior team match.</p><p>"He was actually carrying drinks at the start of the week, and by the end of the week he was one of their best players,&rdquo; Ogilvy said. "There's a big difference between 14 and 17, too, so pretty immediately he looks like he was world class.&rdquo;</p><p>Michael Clayton, a former European Tour pro from Australia, first played with Scott at the Victorian Open. Clayton was a two-time champion of the event and interested to see what the young amateur had. On the opening hole, Scott snap hooked his drive into the trees and nearly whiffed en route to a double bogey.</p><p>"I remember saying, &lsquo;I guess he's not that good,' &rdquo; Clayton said.</p><p>Scott then birdied the next five holes with an impressive array of shots that left the seasoned pro in awe.</p><p>"I thought, &lsquo;How good is this guy ' &rdquo; Clayton said. "He shot 64. You could see he was incredible. You could see he was a star. He was always going to be a great player. He was smart and could smash it and had a great swing.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott played only one season at UNLV before turning pro in 2000 and quickly grew into that world-class label.</p><p>"There were a lot of really great things in my game then that I probably took for granted, which is what you do when you're young,&rdquo; he said. "When you're young, it's all about raw talent.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> LACKING FIRE</p><p>With blue-chip sponsorships and houses from Switzerland to Dubai and Sanctuary Cove in Australia and a private Gulfstream jet to ferry him around the globe, Scott was set financially.</p><p>The young Australian was tabloid fodder with pictures of him palling on the beach with actress Kate Hudson or splashing in the surf with tennis star girlfriend Ana Ivanovic.</p><p>Life could have been worse.</p><p>Scott's critics' only argument was that he's too nice for his own good.</p><p>Former coach Butch Harmon suggested as far back as 2003 that Scott needed to be meaner and tougher to develop the killer instinct that Woods had. Former Aussie great Jack Newton, runner-up at the 1980 Masters, was vocal during Scott's slump with emphatic declarations that he lacked the "mongrel&rdquo; nerve to ever win a major.</p><p>"There's no doubting about the guy's ability,&rdquo; Newton said in April 2009, "but it seems to me that his head is not there. You could ask questions at times whether he loses his nerve. I've always thought he didn't have enough mongrel in him week-in, week-out.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott's father, Phil, rejected the argument.</p><p>"Why do you have to be a mongrel to win a major &rdquo; he said. "I don't believe it. What I believe is when you're at peace and you have the utmost belief in yourself and confidence, you can do anything you want. For some people that will be being really hard and mongrel. And for others it will be really focused. Justin Rose is a nice guy with a slightly different streak than Adam, but you can't say he needed to get more mongrel to win that (U.S. Open). Maybe that's a modern era thing because we've seen Woods be a mongrel since the day he played pro golf and maybe people started thinking that's what you do. But did Phil Mickelson become a mongrel to win his five  No.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott accepted the criticism as a compliment regarding his potential. He believes the place to show toughness isn't necessarily where everyone sees it between the ropes.</p><p>"I know it's inside me,&rdquo; Scott said. "That was the big thing that turned it around and put me in that position more. When you're in that position more you can see the want and desire in me to win. You saw it at Augusta, you saw it at the Players Championship or any big tournament that you win.</p><p>"You make a big putt at the last, you're willing that ball into the hole. You want it badly. To get into that position more to become a great player takes something. It takes that sacrifice, that mongrel that will just do what he has to do. That's where it needed to be applied, not necessarily on the golf course.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> HITTING BOTTOM</p><p>Even the best players can lose form and never retrieve it.</p><p>Scott fans had to look no further for an example than fellow Queenslander Ian Baker-Finch, the 1991 British Open champion. Three years later, after tinkering with his game, Baker-Finch lost all confidence as he failed to make cut after cut on the PGA Tour. Despite a 10-year exemption for his Open win, a 37-year-old Baker-Finch retired from tournament golf in 1997 after a 92 in the first round of the British Open at Troon that left him crying in the locker room.</p><p>"There's always a fear,&rdquo; said Clayton. "So many guys like (former Masters champion) Ralph Guldahl, who completely lost it. The game is littered with guys like that. But I don't think anybody thought Adam would ever have gone that way. He was too strong and too sound and too good a player. I don't think anybody thought he was going to go away like Finchy went away. Adam was just having a bad run.&rdquo;</p><p>His father agrees, but not that it didn't come without worry.</p><p>"I won't say that it never crossed my mind because it honestly did,&rdquo; Phil Scott said. "Was I concerned he wouldn't come back  No. Was I concerned it was possible  Yes.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott wondered himself where he was heading.</p><p>"Yeah, I was worried that the trigger wouldn't happen and that it wouldn't come back because I had not had to deal with that situation before,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Said brother-in-law Brad Malone: "Until that point his career had only ever gone in one direction. So there was no question it was not a good place to be in. He always thought he could get out of it, but how quickly was gonna be the test to him. In a way I feel that season of 2009 it helped him focus and ask questions of what I need to do to contend in major championships.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> NORMAN'S LIFELINE</p><p>The 2009 Presidents Cup at Harding Park was a turning point. Critics questioned Norman's wisdom in picking a player who hadn't finished better than 35th on the PGA Tour since January.</p><p>"I didn't know what was affecting Adam but I just knew that getting him out on the golf course and giving him a shot of confidence would do him a world of good,&rdquo; Norman said.</p><p>Harmon, who mutually parted ways with Scott in the midst of the slump, was particularly worried when his former prodigy got the call from captain Norman to put his struggling game on the world stage in the 2009 Presidents Cup.</p><p>"Adam is very fragile at the moment, mentally and emotionally, confidence wise,&rdquo; Harmon said.</p><p>Scott, however, was inspired by the opportunity and used it as a motivator.</p><p>"I think that was smart of Greg. He threw me a bone, but he had a lot of faith in me,&rdquo; Scott said. "He knew that if he gave me that pick I wouldn't let him down. I wouldn't just let my bad attitude continue and not practice and treat it with a grain of salt. A captain's pick to a Presidents Cup is a big deal and an honor and shouldn't be treated lightly. And I was given it on the back of very little form. But he knew I would take it seriously and I worked really hard to play the best I possibly could at that Presidents Cup.&rdquo;</p><p>Unlike the Ryder Cup, where a weak player can be hidden on the bench, the Presidents Cup requires every player to play every day. This was the biggest jolt for Scott, who hadn't figured that prominently since the 2008 U.S. Open with Tiger and Phil. He called it "gut-check time.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott prepared aggressively, including officially working with Malone as his swing coach. This was a fresh start.</p><p>"It was a kick back up to playing world-class golf again,&rdquo; he said. "For most of the year I played down the back of the field early on Saturdays and Sunday and you could hide. Your bad golf isn't looked at. But you don't want to play bad golf when every shot you're going to hit that week counts toward the team.&rdquo;</p><p>One teammate's endorsement that week stuck with Scott. Angel Cabrera, the Argentine who won the Masters that April, told Norman he wanted to play with Scott. Despite losing their four-ball match, Cabrera took Scott aside and told him, "You are a great player.&rdquo;</p><p>"Something I didn't forget,&rdquo; Scott said after beating Cabrera in last year's Masters playoff, "and really nice of him.&rdquo;</p><p>The week didn't turn out well for the International team, which lost resoundingly 19.5-14.5. Scott's match record was 1-4.</p><p>"I didn't play my best golf that week but it wasn't far away,&rdquo; Scott said.</p><p>The faith that Norman offered him was a catalyst that paid immediate dividends. He finished third in his next start at the Singapore Open and followed it with a sixth in the Australian Masters and seventh in Dubai. Then at the New South Wales Golf Club in Sydney, he won his first professional event in his home country at the Australian Open.</p><p>"On the back of such a poor year in the states where his confidence was at the lowest he'd ever been, he managed to find form very quickly,&rdquo; Malone said.</p><p>Norman handed him the trophy.</p><p>"A journey of a thousand miles starts with a single step,&rdquo; Norman said. "His journey of a thousand miles starting from where he was, started with a single step of winning the Australian Open. That was just a first step of getting him back. That was easy for me to sit there and say, &lsquo;Hey, well done. This is what you wanted to get back to, now push and push and push.' That was just a catalyst to keep him going.&rdquo;</p><p>The victory pushed Scott back into the top 50 and secured his return to the Masters just before the season-ending deadline.</p><p>"It's amazing how quickly things can turn around,&rdquo; he said. "And at the time, it's a childhood dream come true to win your national open. For me to win that and Greg was there to present the trophy, certainly it was an amazing turnaround somewhat orchestrated by him.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> REBOOTING</p><p>When Scott debuted at the 2002 Masters and shot a Sunday 70 to finish tied for ninth, it seemed like the start of great things in majors.</p><p>However, through 2010 he only had four top 10s in 39 major starts &ndash; never seriously threatening in any of them. His best finish was a backdoor tie for third at the 2006 PGA Championship at Medinah when a final-round 67 moved him into the top-10 for the first time all week. That came a month after loitering in the top 10 for four days in the British Open at Hoylake without ever really challenging, finishing nine shots behind Woods.</p><p>"It was glaringly obvious that my results in big events didn't match that in other events,&rdquo; Scott said. "So changes had to be made.&rdquo;</p><p>The first piece in turning that majors record around was getting his swing back in order after his slump. He put his full faith in Malone, and they worked on getting a more consistent higher ball flight with more spin rate conducive to firm and fast major setups.</p><p>"He'd been giving advice for a couple of months within the guidelines of what I gave him because I didn't have enough trust in myself to make a big change,&rdquo; Scott said of Malone. "I was so out of my comfort level at the time. But after the Presidents Cup I said we've got to do what we've got to do. He made me do some drastic things that felt really uncomfortable. But it got results. It wasn't like a complete rebuild where you write off six months until you're competitive again.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott's father, who taught him his original swing before Harmon took the baton for 10 years, liked the simplicity of the restoration.</p><p>"From the point Adam was at his worst he obviously needed some work to get it back,&rdquo; his father said. "Brad was very clever to realize that it didn't have to be new. Just had to take it back and keep it in tune. You have this great Ferrari. The leads had got on the wrong thing. Once you got it back you had to just keep it in tune. He's got a way with Adam of making sure Adam likes the tune of his own engine. That simpleness allows for clarity.&rdquo;</p><p>The next step was fixing his putting. In 2004, the first year the PGA Tour started measuring strokes gained putting, Scott ranked No. 1 ahead of Tiger Woods. But it was never really his strength. By 2008 he was outside the top 175, bottoming out in 2010 at 186th.</p><p>So he came to the WGC-Match Play in 2011 sporting a long putter at the suggestion of Malone.</p><p>"He's never done this before and never used a long putter,&rdquo; Malone reasoned. "There's not going to be any thoughts of technique it's just going to be instinct and using natural ability. Just let him roll a putt freely with no thought. &hellip; From the word go, because it was a completely new method, it gave him a new feeling of freedom and something to work on.&rdquo;</p><p>"I worked really hard on my putting,&rdquo; Scott said. "I tried a completely new method of putting, which, you know, I had five weeks to get right. I've never putted like that before, and I had five weeks to get it right before I brought it on tour. Some of these guys have been putting the way they putt for their whole life. So I had to make a big adjustment there.&rdquo;</p><p>The adjustment went well, with Scott making his first legitimate challenge at a major at the 2011 Masters, leading down the stretch before tying for second when Charl Schwartzel birdied the last four holes.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> CHASING MAJORS</p><p>While Scott regained his footing in 2010 with wins in Texas and Singapore, it was not enough. The majors remained a mystery to him and he was determined to silence the critics who questioned his motivation and nerve.</p><p>"For nine years, I thought I could win anywhere, and I would just fall into a major one of these years,&rdquo; Scott said. "It was hard to comprehend why this was happening.&rdquo;</p><p>To prepare for the majors as he entered his 30s, Scott decided to overhaul his schedule. In his first 10 seasons on tour, he averaged 26 starts worldwide per year. He decided that was about 20 percent too much.</p><p>"I just was so frustrated, it was time to do something radically different for me,&rdquo; Scott said. "I think I just got stuck in a pattern. That can easily happen out here. And there's a lot to play for every week out here. There are massive purses and a lot of prestigious tournaments to play for, but you've got to make some sacrifices maybe for a big reward.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott played 21, 21 and 20 tournaments the last three years to earn the designation of "part-time golfer&rdquo; from the media despite competing at an annual rate similar to what Woods played during his peak from 2000-07. He took six weeks off this season between Hawaii and the Florida Swing.</p><p>It also was a matter or working harder and smarter between those starts.</p><p>"Just to be disciplined to stick with my plan of practicing a lot when I'm at home, I found that quite easy to do it actually because I enjoyed it a lot more because I knew what I was working towards,&rdquo; Scott said. "I wasn't working towards just playing a lot of tournaments. I was working towards the Masters or the World Golf Championship or the U.S. Open. There was a specific time when I really wanted to peak, and the other tournaments, yes, they're important, but they were part of the process.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>The last piece of the remake puzzle was caddie. A few weeks after his 2011 runner-up at the Masters, Scott decided to part ways with veteran caddie Tony Navarro, who had worked for years with Norman. In the process of auditioning new guys, Steve Williams became available for the U.S. Open when Woods was injured. When Woods and Williams split permanently two weeks later, Scott hired the New Zealander full time.</p><p>Williams had worked for Ray Floyd and Greg Norman before winning 13 majors with Tiger, so his expectations of what his player could achieve were quite high.</p><p>"He wanted me to win big tournaments and he couldn't understand why I hadn't,&rdquo; Scott said. "He'd seen me play a fair bit. With him being so focused and committed to those big tournaments it was the little bit more we needed to get there.&rdquo;</p><p>It's exactly what Scott needed in his ear.</p><p>"If Steve does anything as a caddie, he makes his player feel like the best player in the world, just by the way he talks to them, by the way he carries himself,&rdquo; Ogilvy said. "You can go way, way back to the early '80s, anyone (Williams) caddied for thinks he's the best caddie because they feel a better player, straight away from the first tee. And that's probably one of the most important things a caddie can do.&rdquo;</p><p>A win at the WGC event at Firestone followed by a seventh-place finish in the PGA the next week validated that Scott was on the right trajectory toward his major goals.</p><p>"I certainly know that Steve believed that Adam could win majors and that's what he wanted to be a part of,&rdquo; Phil Scott said. "In that year period everyone around him was of the same mind view &ndash; it could be done, it should be done, it will be done. Let's follow this path and that's why it's been successful.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> OPEN LOSS</p><p>With his new team and plan, Scott went from under-performing in majors to contending regularly. He finished eighth at the 2012 Masters with a confidence-inducing Sunday 66 punctuated by an ace on No. 16. He rallied with three consecutive 70s to finish 15th in the U.S. Open at Olympic.</p><p>He showed up for the British Open at Royal Lytham & St. Annes brimming with confidence and opened with a course-record tying 64 for his first career overnight lead in a major. He led by four strokes heading into the final round and maintained that margin through 14 holes Sunday.</p><p>Then it slowly unraveled. Scott made bogey from the bunker on 15 and three-putted for another on 16. After hearing the roar of Ernie Els' birdie on 18, Scott pulled his approach on 17 into the rough and made another bogey to fall into a tie. He hit into a fairway bunker on 18 and he dropped into a crouch when his 8-footer for par missed and handed the claret jug to Els.</p><p>"It wasn't one of those things where he carved it out of bounds and made 7 and suddenly the lead's gone,&rdquo; said Phil Scott, who watched the demise unfold from outside the ropes as he tried to console his daughter, Kasey. "He didn't do a lot wrong and had these dribbling little bogeys and suddenly it's all over. It was concerning to watch it. You could understand it in golf because it's so easy to make bogeys.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott seemed in shock as he stoically but gracefully handled his interview obligations and swore he would take the positives away from his disappointment.</p><p>Norman told him as much that night in a phone call.</p><p>"I said when you think about it you led this British Open for 70 holes,&rdquo; Norman said. "Take the positive out of the 70 and not the negative out of the two. When you break it down into simplistic terms, you outplayed everybody. So take it, use it and move on with it. Other guys have done the same thing. Jack Nicklaus has done it, Arnold Palmer's done it, I've done it, Woods has done it. Every player that plays stumbles sometimes. It's part of the game.&rdquo;</p><p>When it was time to leave, his father changed plans and flew home with his son to Switzerland for support.</p><p>"That was very much a non-golf, parental move,&rdquo; his father said. "I didn't want him to go to bed on his own and we had some great chats. I thought by Wednesday he was sorted. I didn't really think Adam would go sit in the corner and cry and that was the end of his career. Because it's just not how he is. It's more how badly will this affect him for a little while. Is he going to be down on himself or angry. And he just got it all out quick.&rdquo;</p><p>Said Scott: "It was great that he was there. It probably would have been worse going by myself. We didn't even talk it out that much. We didn't have much to analyze. Just the last four holes.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott insisted he was encouraged more than discouraged, but few were convinced.</p><p>"Trust me, I was really disappointed,&rdquo; Scott said. "But I still think that's the best 68 holes of golf I think I will ever play. It was superb. The ball striking was out of this world good. Everything else was good. And I played conservative on the last day and made a couple of mistakes at the end. I took so much good stuff out of being able to play like that finally at the biggest stage in the world after trying for 12 years that I didn't want to let the result put me off track. It was gutting not to walk away with the claret jug, absolutely, but I meant what I said.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> MASTERS PAYOFF</p><p>Instead of emotional scarring, Scott came to the Masters the next spring convinced that he was ready to kick the door in on his major roadblock. Augusta National seemed the perfect place for him.</p><p>"Stuff had started happening for me at Augusta &hellip; so when I went there (in 2013) I felt like I'd done everything possible, especially in the four months of the new year,&rdquo; he said. "I've got everything where I want it to be. I've done all the work. Now I just have to go and do it.&rdquo;</p><p>So when opportunity knocked again with four holes to play Sunday, Scott was ready to handle it better then he did in 2011 when Schwartzel caught him at Augusta or in 2012 when he let it go at Royal Lytham.</p><p>"From my experience in being close at majors, you've got to go and win it,&rdquo; he said. "They're not going to be handed to you. The Schwartzel thing, what can you do  It's the best finish ever in a major. But that's what you've got to do to win a major. You've got to show that you want it. That's what I did.&rdquo;</p><p>Trailing fellow Aussie Jason Day by two as he played No. 15 in a steady rain, Scott knocked it to 20 feet and two-putted for birdie coinciding with Day's bogey at 16.</p><p>"That's when it starts becoming gut-check time,&rdquo; he said. "I'd played the whole day cruising and not thinking about winning whatsoever. I didn't think about winning at that moment but I just knew that if you want a chance you have to hit a great shot into 15 there. Against Schwartzel I didn't and it was ultimately pretty costly. I stood over that 4-iron at 15 and thought just put the best shot you can on this thing and show them how much you want to get in there.&rdquo;</p><p>An even bigger shot came in the playoff with his 6-iron approach into 10 that set up the winning putt.</p><p>"Instinct would have been to play the shorter club and swing pretty hard with his draw,&rdquo; Malone said. "But the ideal shot was a 6-iron held. That shot for him would have been out of the question in the past. For him to hit that shot was a huge moment. Under that pressure you've got one chance and you know Cabrera is on the green. To pull that off was an awesome shot.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> ADDING IT ALL UP</p><p>Everything Scott was working on for three years was validated in those final holes and the playoff.</p><p>"In the playoff, all the hard work really came off then,&rdquo; Malone said. "The things he's really worked on over the years came together.&rdquo;</p><p>The smooth swing he'd worked on with Malone held up under pressure with clutch drives and approaches.</p><p>The focus that produced the best cumulative performance in majors for two consecutive seasons.</p><p>The long putter that delivered the dramatic birdies on the 72nd hole and playoff.</p><p>And the experienced caddie who gave Scott the perfect read he needed to end it as rain and darkness fell on the second playoff hole.</p><p>"For a while the process wasn't about results, it was about just doing the work and the results would come,&rdquo; Scott said. "Now the results are coming, we're going to keep doing that same thing and see how far I can take it.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott has come a long way from his rock bottom in a short time. He's No. 2 in the world and eager to see what the future holds.</p><p>"While the modern era has produced guys winning young, what seems to be the case is guys still produce their best golf in their 30s,&rdquo; said his father. "In the old days you had this mentality that you had to dig around for 10 years and earn your stripes. Adam came along in his 20s and made a lot of money and Sergio (Garcia) was awesome and Justin (Rose) was awesome. Now here we are a decade later and they really are better players. I think we're probably going to see his best five or six years now. He'll certainly give it his best shot.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott believes it.</p><p>"Well, I've spoken quite openly that I think my time to achieve is now, so I need to make the most of it,&rdquo; he said. "If I'm to achieve what I dreamt of as a kid I've got a lot of work to do still. I need to get busy and I need to keep winning majors and winning tournaments and keep working this process or this plan that I've got in place to do that.</p><p>"As long as I keep the intensity and practice and preparation, I think I can win more majors, win another Masters, win the Open, hopefully U.S. Opens and PGAs. I'd love to win the career Grand Slam or the career slam, whatever they call it, and put myself in that really small group of players who have won all four majors. I think that would be a good goal, but that's a long way off at the moment. I've only got one, so there's a lot of work to do.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 16:44:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2592 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Architect builds Lego replica of Augusta National clubhouse</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/architect-builds-lego-replica-augusta-national-clubhouse</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0302MastersLegoJMS%2002.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Replicating one of golf's most recognizable landmarks invites a commitment to perfection.</p><p>Architect Andy Duckett tapped into his propensity for accuracy and precision to construct a small-scale model of the iconic clubhouse at Au&shy;gusta National Golf Club from 3,000 Lego blocks. In a matter of months, he continuously built, tore down and reconstructed his replica until satisfied with the job.</p><p>On Saturday, the Stone Moun&shy;tain, Ga., man delivered the replica to Augusta, where it will be displayed at Trends & Traditions Antique Mall on Washington Road through the Masters Tournament.</p><p>"I finally got it to where proportionally, I thought it represented the clubhouse very well,&rdquo; Duckett said. "What made this thing do-able is that it's not a complicated building.&rdquo;</p><p>Beginning in mid-November, Duckett searched online for photos of the clubhouse. He imported the photos into an architectural program and drew a view of the clubhouse.Then, he scattered his Lego collection on his diningroom table and ordered even more blocks to help create his masterpiece. He worked for several hours on the weekends and occasionally in the evenings after work.</p><p>"The clubhouse is simple. It's a square. If you do one side, you've done four sides,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Duckett, a 1979 graduate of Georgia Tech, is an avid collector of Masters memorabilia. What started as a collection of golf balls and bag tags from courses he visited grew into a collection of thousands of items, many of which are displayed at Trends & Traditions.</p><p>The idea to build a Lego model of the clubhouse arose after his architecture firm built a Lego replica of a Zaxby's restaurant for a client.Lego architecture has exploded as a greater variety and quantity of the tiny building blocks have become available. Ordering specialty blocks online made Duckett's task easier.</p><p>For the clubhouse model, Duck&shy;ett used smooth finishing tiles that conceal the Lego studs on traditional blocks. Other special pieces mimic the wooden railing on the clubhouse's second story.</p><p>He relied on trial and error to build the clubhouse, never settling for anything less than precision. He replaced the model's two chimneys after finding an aerial photo of the clubhouse and noticing that the smokestacks were not in the center of the roof as he had built them.</p><p>He repeatedly toyed with the roof design, making a pattern out of smaller blocks rather than using Lego's sloped roof piece because it was slightly steeper than he needed.</p><p>Last week, Duckett completed the model, which weighs 10 pounds and measures 16&frac12; inches on each side. He plans to make a careful inspection of the clubhouse when he visits Au&shy;gusta National for the tournament's Monday practice round tosee whether his model needs any minor adjustments.</p><p>Duckett documented each step of his process with photos in case anyone requests a second model. He'd consider selling his original or making additional ones.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 14:42:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2590 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mayor's Masters Reception won't be held this year</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/mayors-masters-reception-wont-be-held-year</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Mayor's Masters Reception will not be held this year, organizer Wayne Hawkins confirmed Tuesday.</p><p>The annual event, which was held Monday of Masters Week, could not find a Masters Tournament participant who would commit to attend. The event began in 1999 and had been held for 15 consecutive years.</p><p>"We never could get a yes,&rdquo; Hawkins said. "Got a whole lot of nos, and we ran out of time.&rdquo;</p><p>The reception featured a prominent golfer who was given a key to the city, and the event included a sampling of food from area businesses and restaurants.</p><p>Past participants included Arnold Palmer, Jack Nicklaus and Gary Player, and the 2013 honoree was Craig Stadler.</p><p>The Mayor's Masters Reception featured multiple golfers at its beginning, then shifted its format to honor a single golfer beginning in 2004, Hawkins said.</p><p>"There's not that many of the old ones left,&rdquo; Hawkins said.</p><p>He said he will try again for 2015 and will discuss with the committee at an upcoming meeting.</p><p>"We'll discuss what direction we want to go in,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 21:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2588 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Brilliant in its simplicity: Alister MacKenzie mirrored St. Andrews with Augusta National and Royal Melbourne courses</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/mackenzie-made-quite-impact-courses-australia</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p><p>CHELTENHAM, Australia &ndash; There are no towering pines or banks of azaleas to frame the outlines. It's not manicured to exacting standards, with natural scruffy patches that blend in with the gently rolling landscape. The visual cues seem completely different.</p><p>But a few holes into Royal Melbourne's West Course is enough to realize that it's just another version of Augusta National Golf Club that Alister MacKenzie drew up more than five years earlier on the opposite side of the world.</p><p>"Tom Doak had a great quote in the Confidential Guide to Golf Courses,&rdquo; said Michael Clayton of the man who currently serves as the house architect at the course that Golf Digest recently ranked No. 9 in the world. "He wrote, &lsquo;Royal Melbourne, I think, is the course Augusta wants to be: wide enough for anybody, but brilliantly routed to make use of the topography and bunkered to reward bold play and bold decisions.'&rdquo;</p><p>Clayton, a former European Tour pro from Australia turned architect, takes the strategic comparison one step further. Both Augusta National and Royal Melbourne are MacKenzie's attempts to reproduce all the challenges of St. Andrews' Old Course on far-flung continents.</p><p>"They're all the same golf course,&rdquo; Clayton said. "They look completely different, but it's the same golf, same course. MacKenzie obviously drew everything from St. Andrews so they're all obviously related to each other.</p><p>"The concept of St. Andrews is the course dictates nothing. The only thing you have to do at St. Andrews is the first hole you have to hit it over the burn, otherwise you can do anything you want.&rdquo;</p><p>Only one golfer has won championships on all three courses &ndash; Seve Ballesteros. The late great Spaniard won two Masters (1980 and 1983) at Augusta, the 1984 British Open at St. Andrews and the 1981 Australian PGA at Royal Melbourne. Clayton believes it's no coincidence that the modern golfer with the most imaginative game is the lone figure to pull off this trifecta.</p><p>"In MacKenzie's book he wrote about seeing an American player pitch into the 17th at St. Andrews and it was Walter Hagen,&rdquo; Clayton said. "That was the guy he was building golf courses for. That was the sort of play he wanted to encourage. He wanted to encourage that boldness, great flair and imagination, beautiful short game, nerveless putting. He wrote about it through Hagen who played the same way. He didn't know it, but he was designing courses for Seve Ballesteros.</p><p>"I watched (Seve) play Royal Melbourne and it was genius. You could see why he won at Augusta. It took the same thought patterns, same shots, same short game, the same putting. They were made for him.&rdquo;</p><p>The design formula that MacKenzie employed at both Royal Melbourne and Augusta is brilliant in its simplicity. The fairways are wide, with the premium on placement to allow the proper approach for particular pins. There is no thick rough to gouge shots out of, encouraging players to attempt recoveries. The greens are firm and large with big slopes. The bunkers are deep and dangerously placed.</p><p>"If you get out of position on any shot it is very hard to get back into the right place &ndash; but you can if you play a great shot,&rdquo; said Clayton, a design partner with Victoria native Geoff Ogilvy who grew up playing the Sandbelt courses. "The greens are very hard and fast &ndash; probably not as difficult to putt as Augusta but fearsome when they are quick. It's also really playable for average players, lots of room around the trouble. The better the player you are the harder the course is; and the poorer you are the easier it is to shoot 90.&rdquo;</p><p>Said Ogilvy: "Nearly every time you hit it to the wrong side of the green or the wrong side of the fairway you have no chance, but you are given a lot of space to find out for yourself.&rdquo;</p><p>MacKenzie traveled to Australia only once, in 1926, contracted to work explicitly on plans for the West Course at Royal Melbourne. But his side consultations with other courses from Royal Sydney and New South Wales in Sydney, Royal Queensland in Brisbane, Royal Adelaide in South Australia as well as other Melbourne Sandbelt jewels Kingston Heath, Victoria and Metropolitan left an indelible impact on Australian golf.</p><p>"Everyone wants to grab hold of the MacKenzie pedigree, but truth is he spent a day there and wrote a report,&rdquo; Clayton said. "There's a tremendous course here (in the Melbourne area) but he didn't go there for a day. If he had gone there it would be seen as the equivalent of the others.</p><p>"But his influence was long-lasting and dominant through his Australian partner, Alex Russell, and Mick Morcom, who was greenskeeper at Royal Melbourne and constructor of all his Melbourne work. He was lucky in that he found great constructors. It was his philosophy more than anything that changed the game here. Like Doak said, there was nothing any good before he came here and nothing any good after he left.&rdquo;</p><p>His hallmark features in the Sandbelt are inspiring bunkers that blend seamlessly into greens and fairways with no discernible apron. Find yourself out of position and certain pins could be impossible to reach.</p><p>"You have to figure out for yourself how best to play because it's so wide you can go anywhere you want,&rdquo; Clayton said. "Clearly the greens are designed to be played from an ideal place. It's not risk and reward but every yard you go further from the ideal place is a yard more difficult. You've got to hit the right trajectory and spin and land the ball in the right place so it runs where you want it to run to.&rdquo;</p><p>These strategic features that the top Australians grew up playing is what has made many of them so well suited for the challenges at Augusta and so frustrated that it took them so long to conquer.</p><p>"Royal Melbourne teaches you how to putt properly,&rdquo; Ogilvy said, "because they are the best greens in the world to learn how to putt on, with the big sweeping breaks, long putts, fast putts, slow putts and the best surfaces.&rdquo;</p><p>Royal Melbourne has other traits in common with Augusta National besides its MacKenzie course. The club feels a responsibility to the game, which it displays by playing host to major events on its Composite Course such as two Presidents Cups, last year's World Cup and various major Australian events.</p><p>This year it will partner with Augusta National and the R&A to host the Asia Pacific Amateur Championship.</p><p>"Why do we do it  We do it because we love to promote golf,&rdquo; said Paul Rak, the club's manager. "At the end of the day there's not a big financial return to it. Members lose out and lose corporate days and lose visitors. But No. 1 it helps golf, and we have a bit of responsibility to do that.&rdquo;</p><p>Rak said the club works hard to preserve MacKenzie's original intent for the course even as technology threatens its traditions.</p><p>"We try to be minimalists,&rdquo; he said. "Don't react to everything. My biggest challenge is to stop people changing the golf course.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 02:46:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2586 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Russell Henley wins 4-man playoff, qualifies for Masters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/russell-henley-wins-4-man-playoff-qualifies-masters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>PALM BEACH GARDENS, Fla. - Georgia's Russell Henley, Rory McIlroy and Tiger Woods were the stories Sunday in the Honda Classic, each for entirely different reasons.</p><p>Henley rallied for victory at PGA National in a four-man sudden-death playoff with a birdie to earn his coveted invitation to next month's Masters Tournament.</p><p>McIlroy self-destructed on the course, and Woods walked off it.</p><p>Henley, from Macon, Ga., hadn't qualified for next month's Masters after making his debut at Augusta National Golf Club last year.</p><p>"I just can't imagine not playing again. I just feel like that would hurt me really bad," said Henley, who was reminded that he wasn't in the field when he saw TV ads for the tournament or fans wearing Masters logo hats.</p><p>"It's going to be cool to go back," said Henley, whose 25th birthday will fall on the third round of the Masters.</p><p>McIlroy, the world's No. 8 player who was going for a wire-to-wire victory, was part of the playoff, but he couldn't salvage a victory after a tough day in regulation. He shot 3-over-par 38 on the back nine to finish with 4-over 74, while Henley had 72.</p><p>Scotland's Russell Knox (71) and Texan Ryan Palmer (69) were also in the playoff, which ended on the first playoff hole - the par-5 18th - when Henley made a two-putt birdie. They finished at 8-under 272.</p><p>Hours before the playoff, Woods, the world's No. 1-ranked player, withdrew with a ailing lower back. It cast doubt that he would play this week at Doral, where he is the defending champion.</p><p>In addition to his Masters invite, the victory earned Henley a spot at Doral for the Cadillac Championship, a World Golf Championship event.</p><p>"I think he's got a great future," Jack Nicklaus said of Henley while being interviewed during the NBC broadcast.</p><p>Henley, a former University of Georgia player who won the Sony Open in early 2013, completed a revival of sorts after a disappointing second half of 2013 and start of 2014. He had missed three of the past four cuts before this week, and tied for 52nd in the other start.</p><p>"This doesn't feel real," Henley said. "It wasn't what I expected at the start of the week."</p><p>He was an unlikely winner after the way events unfolded on the front nine Sunday. Two shots behind McIlroy at the start of the round, Henley trailed him by four shots after six holes, but hung in there to outlast the strong field by going back to basics with his swing.</p><p>McIlroy had been 4-0 worldwide while holding a 54-hole lead, but he had five bogeys and a double bogey Sunday and "couldn't get the job done," he said.</p><p>"Yeah, it's very disappointing," he said. "Look, it was a perfect opportunity to win. No one was really coming at me."</p><p>Woods, who felt back spasms while warming up Sunday, was 5-over for his round through 13 holes when he called it a day and headed to his nearby home in Jupiter. </p><p>At the time, he was tied for 46th after opening with rounds of 71-69-65. It continues an alarming trend for Woods: In three starts this season, he's yet to crack the top 40, which doesn't bode well with the Masters just more than a month away.</p><p> ]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 23:43:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2584 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A 65 and signs of life from Tiger in Florida</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/65-and-signs-life-tiger-florida</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>PALM BEACH GARDENS, Fla. &mdash; The first Saturday morning in March is the last place you expect to assess the Masters Tournament readiness of the world's best golfer. Then again, it's fortunate there was anything to assess at all.</p><p>Tiger Woods barely snuck into the weekend at the Honda Classic &ndash; his new hometown tournament. In the first twosome off in the morning with Luke Guthrie, he wasn't just chasing leader Rory McIlroy from 11 shots behind but also his first Sunday appearance of the year on the PGA Tour in what has been the slowest start of his 18-year career.</p><p>A 5-under-par 65 &ndash; his best round of the season &ndash; was a positive sign that the 38-year-old Woods has more than what he's shown so far as the weeks count down to the Masters.</p><p>"Absolutely. Absolutely,&rdquo; Woods said. "Today was a positive day, hit the ball well and made some putts and got myself back in the hunt.&rdquo;</p><p>The scrutiny that constantly envelops Woods has grown denser in 2014 as he returned showing little of the form that won him five events last year. His body looks bigger, his swing tighter and his results poorer.</p><p>He started with a tie for 80th at Torrey Pines &ndash; a place where he's won eight times including his last career major at the U.S. Open in 2008. A Saturday 79 sent him packing after the 54-hole secondary cut.</p><p>The next week in Dubai he failed to follow up an opening 68 and finished tied for 41st, 10 strokes behind winner Stephen Gallacher.</p><p>Sitting 66th when he arrived at PGA National in darkness Saturday morning, Woods was flirting with finishing 40th or worse in three consecutive starts for only the second time in his career. In 2012 he tied for 40th at the Masters, missed the cut in Charlotte and had another tied for 40th at the Players during a rare triple dip. But he bracketed that stretch on both sides with wins at Bay Hill and Memorial.</p><p>"I've had a long enough career where I've gone through periods like that, yeah, where it's tough,&rdquo; Woods said. "I've had situations where it just seems like no matter what you do, you play, nothing really goes your way. You can't get the feel of your swing, can't get the putter going, short game, just it's one thing after another. And it's like we can week after week after week, round after round after round like that, and next thing you know, couple months and half the season has gone by. I've been through sessions like that, you look at my career, it's gone in waves like that.&rdquo;</p><p>With only six weeks to the Masters that Woods hasn't won since 2005, the search was on for a spark. Despite hitting only six fairways (including just one of the front nine), Woods was making putts like he used to. Through the first 15 holes he had taken only 17 putts &ndash; with 11 one-putts and a chip-in. He missed birdie chances inside 15 feet on the last three holes or he could have posted something low enough for McIlroy to think about before he teed off.</p><p>"I just felt like I had good feel today,&rdquo; Woods said of his putting. "I missed my share of putts, too. The last couple holes it would have been nice to get one of those, too. But I played the par-3s in 3-under today, which was pretty nice.&rdquo;</p><p>It was a big turnaround from Friday afternoon when Woods "grinded it out&rdquo; to make the cut on the number &ndash; something Phil Mickelson failed to do. With not enough daylight to practice, Woods made the short 20-minute commute to his home in Jupiter and slept on it. It clicked as soon as he showed up on dawn patrol.</p><p>"I had a good range session this morning, it was good,&rdquo; he said. "Came out today and very first hole I hit it to 3 feet but it spun back to about 15 feet and I made that.&rdquo;</p><p>In the end a 65 probably isn't enough to reel in McIlroy or the other leaders. "Rory could run and hide,&rdquo; he admitted.</p><p>But Saturday's round was more of a big-picture boost. It was a sign of life. It's something to take to the rebuilt Doral and Bay Hill for what are expected to be his last tune-ups before Augusta.</p><p>Woods seems less concerned than everyone else about the state of his game that hasn't won a major in five years or a Masters in nine.</p><p>"It's going to turn around,&rdquo; he said before heading off holding hands with his 6-year-old daughter, Sam, and girlfriend, Lindsey Vonn.</p><p>"We are all going to have hot spells and we're going to have cold spells, especially the longer we stay out here. You try and get those hot spells and ride them as long as you can and get those cold spells as short as they can.&rdquo;</p><p>It's high time for his game to heat up.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 06:28:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2583 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jason Day outlasts Victor Dubuisson in epic Match Play Championship final</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/jason-day-outlasts-victor-dubuisson-epic-match-play-championship-fina</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>MARANA, Ariz. - Jason Day never stopped believing he would win the Match Play Championship, even in the midst of so many shots by Victor Dubuisson that simply defied belief.</p><p>With his ball at the base of a cactus, Dubuisson took an all-or-nothing swing though the sharp needles and a TV cable and incredibly hit it to 4 feet to save par. Seemingly out of it on the next playoff hole, the 23-year-old Frenchman somehow whacked a wedge through a desert bush and rocks and onto the green for another par.</p><p>Day finally ended the madness Sunday on the 23rd hole with a pitch to 4 feet on No. 15 for birdie.</p><p>It was the first time the championship match went overtime since the inaugural year in 1999 at La Costa, when Jeff Maggert chipped on the second extra hole of a 36-hole final. That was like watching paint dry compared to the show Dubuisson put on.</p><p>"Those two shots were amazing," Dubuisson said. "I just played it like I had nothing to lose."</p><p>Day, with his first World Golf Championship, walked away with his second PGA Tour title that will take the Australian to No. 4 in the world.</p><p>This tournament might better be remembered for Dubuisson's magical escapes.</p><p>"Vic, man, he has a lot of guts," Day said. "He has a great short game - straight out of the cactus twice. For a 23-year-old kid, he's got a lot of game. We're going to see a lot of him for years to come."</p><p>Two holes down with two holes to play, Dubuisson rapped in a 15-foot birdie putt on the 17th hole and then took advantage of a rare lapse by Day, who bogeyed the 18th hole with a three-putt from 50 feet on the upper tier. The Frenchman saved par from the bunker to force extra holes.</p><p>It looked like it would be over quickly.</p><p>From the first fairway, Dubuisson went so far long that bounced hard off the back of the green and into the desert, the ball nestled at the base of a cholla. During regulation, he would have taken a penalty drop. In this case, he felt he had no choice. He stepped up to the ball and, with nothing to lose, swung away. The club got caught on a TV cable, and the ball scooted up the slope of 3-inch grass and onto the green.</p><p>On the next extra hole, the par-5 ninth, Dubuisson tugged his shot left of the green, left of the bleachers and into a desert bush surrounded by rocks. He took another crack at it, and the shot came out perfectly through thick grass and onto the green.</p><p>"I kept shaking my head because there was a couple of times there where I thought he was absolutely dead - the tournament was mine," Day said.</p><p>It was - eventually.</p><p>After matching bogeys and pars on the next two holes - this time from the green grass - the match ended on the 333-yard 15th hole when Dubuisson's drive strayed too far right into side of a hill, leaving him an awkward pitch.</p><p>"I'm disappointed because I made some terrible shots," Dubuisson said, ignoring the two that were as close to a miracle as golf allows.</p><p> <p>LPGA TOUR: In Chonburi, Thailand, Anna Nordqvist won the LPGA Thailand to end a five-year victory drought, holding off top-ranked Inbee Park at Siam County Club.</p><p>Nordqvist, the LPGA Championship and LPGA Tour Championship winner in 2009, led wire-to-wire. The 26-year-old Swede closed with 4-under 68 to beat defending champion Park by two strokes.</p><p>Nordqvist finished at 15-under 273 on the Pattaya Old Course. Park, making her first start of the year, had a bogey-free 66. </p><p>The South Korean player won six times last year.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 04:30:23 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2578 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott enjoys year as champion, now ready to defend</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/scott-enjoys-year-champion-now-ready-defend</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/scott-recap_0.jpg" /></div><p>Not a day has gone by since last April that Adam Scott hasn't looked in his closet at the green jacket and thought about the Masters Tournament. But the urgency to repeat escalates now.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>Scott returns next week from a six-week break to begin his competitive run-up to Augusta, and there is much still to get done.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"That's really when my preparation and lead up to Augusta starts to get myself in shape to come and defend,&rdquo; Scott said on his Tuesday teleconference with Augusta National Golf Club.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>This last week of break will be spent not only honing his swing on his range in the Bahamas but trying to finalize his menu for the Champions Dinner.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"I'd like to serve something that everyone will really enjoy, and nothing too crazy so that they won't,&rdquo; he said. "But probably no surprise to anyone, there's definitely going to be an Australian theme toward every part of the dinner. Whether that means they are eating kangaroo, I'm not sure yet, but we'll see.&rdquo;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>Whatever he serves, Scott hopes it sets a tone for other Australians to join him now that he's broken through at Augusta where his hero Greg Norman and others had met with nothing but heartbreak and frustration.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"So hopefully the shackles are off and we're going to have a host of Aussies up there in the Champions Locker Room and serving dinners in the future,&rdquo; he said.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>The coming seven weeks before the 2014 Masters starts will include another very important element for Scott &ndash; getting over the emotions of returning to the scene of his greatest career triumph. While he traditionally makes a spring scouting trip to Augusta during the Florida swing, this year will be an entirely different experience that he'd like to share with his father, if possible.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"It's going to be hard,&rdquo; Scott said. "I'll probably need two days. I need a day to get my head right and get over the sentimental stuff, and then a day of work. But it's something that I'm looking forward to so much. It's an exciting time of year as a golfer, and for me this year, heading towards April is a real buzz and going to be something I'm really looking forward to.&rdquo;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>When he makes that trip, Scott is curious to see how the 17th hole looks without the famous Eisenhower Tree, which was removed over the weekend after suffering extensive ice damage. Scott won't necessarily miss seeing it.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"Whether they replace it or not, it was a pretty tight hole,&rdquo; he said. "So from a golfing standpoint, I kind of think seeing a little bit more of the fairway will be a nice thing.&rdquo;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>Ranked No. 2 in the world and coming off of a four-win season that helped him earn Player of the Year status from the Golf Writer's Association of America, Scott obviously built on his major breakthrough. But he still expects bigger things and more majors as he enters the prime of his career at age 33. His more limited schedule remains a focus on trying to peak at the right moments.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"I'm also keeping the big picture in mind and my priorities are the Masters and the other three majors later this year, and I think the break was necessary, even though I was playing well,&rdquo; he said of the end of 2013. "Although we didn't get another major last year, to win some other tournaments and have a good run back in Australia was really important to kind of take your confidence in anything that the Masters gave you and become a better player.&rdquo;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>Despite his preference for privacy, Scott has handled the added duties that come with being a Masters champion beautifully. His predecessor, Bubba Watson, struggled with some of that burden and went nearly two years before winning again on Sunday at Riviera.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"It's been an incredible experience being the Masters champion for the last 11, 12 months, and it's something I'll be trying to do again, for sure,&rdquo; he said. "To have that green jacket hanging in the closet is worth any bit of extra stuff you might have to deal with in your professional world.&rdquo;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>While the curtain is drawing closed on his year in the Masters spotlight, Scott said that he'd largely pulled it shut long before his green jacket tour made its homecoming to Australia in the fall. He has enjoyed it to the fullest extent without dwelling in the past.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"I think the interesting thing is, for me, as a competitor and someone who likes to win and desires to win and works hard to try and win tournaments, the feeling and sense of accomplishment doesn't last very long,&rdquo; he said. "You know, it basically goes through that night and you wake up the next day, and that event's over, and everyone's moving on.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"And you can kind of bask in the glory yourself for a little bit but as soon as you're back out to play again, everyone's moved on and there's a new trophy to play for. That's not undermining the sense of achievement of winning the Masters and the history of the event or any other major championship or any other tournament. But it's just kind of how it works, because 150 other guys didn't win and they are moving on to try and win the next week.</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>"You can't rest on your laurels and I think that's the interesting thing about it was that it probably lasted longer than any other tournament, but it doesn't last as long as you think considering it's something that you've kind of worked your whole life towards.&rdquo;</p> <p>&nbsp;</p> <p>Reach Scott Michaux at (706) 823-3219 or scott.michaux@augustachronicle.com.</p> ]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2014 20:43:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2574 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ike gets his wish thanks to Mother Nature</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/ike-gets-his-wish-thanks-mother-nature</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After nearly 60 years, the late Dwight D. Eisenhower appealed to a higher authority and finally got his wish.</p><p>Mother Nature did what original club chairman Clifford Roberts refused to do and tore down the most famous pine at Augusta National Golf Club &ndash; the Eisenhower Tree.</p><p>Masters Tournament chairman Billy Payne confirmed the news Sunday evening that the damage suffered from last week's major ice storm was too much for the nearly 125-year-old tree to handle.</p><p>With trees damaged all over Augusta by this week's destructive ice storm, it stood to reason that even Augusta National would not be immune to the harsh consequences.</p><p>"Like so many of our family, friends and neighbors in this community, Augusta National Golf Club has been busy cleaning up after the historic ice storm last week,&rdquo; Payne said. "Everyone affected remains in our hearts and prayers, and we likewise hope for a speedy and complete recovery for all.&rdquo;</p><p>Despite initial reports of minor damage, a picture surfaced over the weekend that showed significant damage to the majestic loblolly pine that guarded the left half of the 17th fairway.</p><p>It's a picture only the former President himself &ndash; who famously hated the tree that bore his name &ndash; might smile about.</p><p>Club workers are pictured cleaning up broken and pruned limbs from the loblolly pine that is the most defining feature of the 17th hole. Standing roughly 65 feet tall and situated about 210 yards from the Masters tee, the wide pine stood sentinel on the course throughout its history.</p><p>While the top-most branch seemed to be intact, gaping sections were missing from its once broad canopy &ndash; particularly on the left side which was almost stripped of all of its branches. The aging pine has been held together for years by numerous cables, but the latest scars were stark.</p><p>The damage proved too extensive for the club to salvage and the landmark was removed over the weekend.</p><p>Sources have claimed for years that Augusta National already has a reserve loblolly pine picked out and awaiting the call at an undisclosed location in Georgia. But whether the backup tree survived the ice storm intact is unknown, as are the club's plans for the 17th hole.</p><p>"We have begun deliberations of the best way to address the future of the 17th hole and to pay tribute to this iconic symbol of our history &ndash; rest assured, we will do both appropriately,&rdquo; Payne said.</p><p>Payne said "the golf course sustained no major damage otherwise. We are now open for member play and we will be unaffected in our preparations for the 2014 Masters Tournament.&rdquo;</p><p>The famous pine tree on No. 17 got its name from Eisenhower, who was a club member from 1948 until his death in 1969. Eisenhower reportedly hit into the tree so often that he campaigned to have it removed. At the club's 1956 governors meeting, the sitting president proposed cutting it down only to have Roberts promptly rule him out of order and adjourn the meeting. The pine has been known as Eisenhower's Tree ever since.</p><p>The tree has played a role in the outcome of many Masters through the years. Tommy Aaron, the 1973 Masters champion, once hit his drive into the top of the tree and never saw it come down, forcing him to take a lost-ball penalty. The next day, his marked Pinnacle fell out of the tree as he was walking past it.</p><p>Jose Maria Olazabal famously punched a 5-iron onto the green from under the tree to preserve his win in 1999.</p><p>The tree's most recent impact occurred in 2011 when Tiger Woods' drive got snagged by the tree and he injured his Achilles tendon hitting his recovery shot from an awkward stance in the pine straw underneath the low-hanging branches.</p><p>One of the first player reactions to the news regarding Ike's Tree came from 2012 Masters champion Bubba Watson after he won Sunday at Riviera: "Let's be honest, that tree was never in my way.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 07:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2572 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Augusta National's Eisenhower Tree removed after storm damage</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/augusta-nationals-eisenhower-tree-removed-after-storm-damage</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0217IkesTree1.jpg" /></div>Golf's most famous pine tree is no longer guarding the 17th hole at Augusta National Golf Club.&nbsp;The Eisenhower Tree suffered major damage in an ice storm and was removed over the weekend, the club confirmed Sunday.&nbsp;Photos showed major limb damage, particularly on the left side and top of the tree.&nbsp;"The loss of the Eisen&shy;hower Tree is difficult news to accept,&rdquo; Augusta National and Masters Chairman Billy Payne said in a prepared statement. "We obtained opinions from the best arborists available and, unfortunately, were advised that no recovery was possible.&rdquo;&nbsp;The Masters landmark, also known as Ike's Tree, was about 210 yards from the tee on the left side of the par-4 hole. The loblolly pine stood 65 feet high and was believed to be 100 to 125 years old.&nbsp;The tree was named because the former president and Augusta National member often hit into it, and at a club meeting in 1956 he proposed cutting it down. Masters co-founder Clifford Roberts ruled him out of order and adjourned the meeting, and the tree has been linked to Eisenhower ever since.&nbsp;"We have begun deliberations of the best way to address the future of the 17th hole and to pay tribute to this iconic symbol of our history &ndash; rest assured, we will do both appropriately,&rdquo; Payne said.&nbsp;Sleet and freezing rain began pelting the Augusta area Tuesday night and continued throughout Wednesday, and photos of Magnolia Lane showed several limbs and branches down as nearly an inch of ice accumulated.&nbsp;Payne said that Augusta National's layout did not receive any other major damage, and is open for member play.&nbsp;Six-time Masters winner Jack Nicklaus issued a statement Sunday about the loss of the tree."The Eisenhower Tree is such an iconic fixture and symbol of tradition at Au&shy;gus&shy;ta National,&rdquo; he said. "It was such an integral part of the game and one that will be sorely missed &hellip; I hit it so many times over the years that I don't care to comment on the names I called myself and the names I might have called the tree. &lsquo;Ike's Tree' was a kind choice. But looking back, Ike's Tree will be greatly missed.&rdquo;&nbsp;Ike's Tree isn't the only notable landmark created by Mother Nature at Augusta National.&nbsp;The magnolia trees that line the club's famous entrance date to the late 1850s, as does the "big oak tree&rdquo; behind the clubhouse. It's a popular gathering spot during Masters Week for players, officials and club members.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CLUB STATEMENT&nbsp;Billy Payne, chairman of Augusta National and the Masters, released a statement Sunday:&nbsp;"Like so many of our family, friends and neighbors in this community, Augusta National Golf Club has been busy cleaning up after the historic ice storm last week. Everyone affected remains in our hearts and prayers, and we likewise hope for a speedy and complete recovery for all.&nbsp;"The loss of the Eisenhower Tree is difficult news to accept. We obtained opinions from the best arborists available and, unfortunately, were advised that no recovery was possible.&nbsp;"We have begun deliberations of the best way to address the future of the 17th hole and to pay tribute to this iconic symbol of our history &ndash; rest assured, we will do both appropriately.&nbsp;"I can report that the golf course sustained no major damage otherwise. We are now open for Member play and we will be unaffected in our preparations for the 2014 Masters Tournament.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;VIGNETTES ABOUT IKE'S TREE&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;LOST BALL&nbsp;1973 Masters champion Tommy Aaron had a memorable encounter with the tree one year.&nbsp;Here's Aaron's story:&nbsp;"I hit a drive there, and it hit in top of the Eisenhower pine and pollen went everywhere. And nobody moved. So I said, &lsquo;That ball stayed in the tree.' The local caddie with us said they don't stay in the tree. And I said, &lsquo;That ball stayed in the tree.'&nbsp;So we couldn't find it. We looked around, and I go back and I play another under the lost ball rule. And the next day we're walking by the tree and a ball drops out of the tree, and I know it's my ball because it had a marking on it and it was a Pinnacle.&nbsp;"So I know it was my ball. Someone told Jack Nicklaus that story and he said, &lsquo;I'm not sure I believe it.'&nbsp;But I've got a witness, my caddie, Rhett Sinclair.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;TIGER'S INJURY&nbsp;Tiger Woods, a four-time Masters winner, was sidelined for much of 2011 by injuries to his left knee and left Achilles tendon. He suffered those injuries while squatting to hit a shot under the Eisenhower Tree on the 17th hole in the third round of the Masters.&nbsp;His left foot got caught in the pine straw as the momentum of the swing carried him backward, he said. Woods' shot wound up in the front bunker and he saved par,&nbsp;Woods held a share of the lead in the final round and finished tied for fourth.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 22:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2571 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Walker makes it interesting at Pebble Beach</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/walker-makes-it-interesting-pebble-beach</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p> PEBBLE BEACH, Calif. - The finish wasn't what Jimmy Walker wanted. The result is what he's come to expect.</p><p>Walker led by as many as six shots Sunday in the AT&T Pebble Beach National Pro-Am, only for it to be decided by his final putt. He ran his birdie attempt 5 feet by the hole, and had to make that for par to close with a 2-over 74 and a one-shot win over Dustin Johnson and Jim Renner.</p><p>"It's drama, man," Walker said on the 18th green. "It was too much for me."</p><p>But it was a familiar outcome for Walker, a 35-year-old Texan who only four months ago was regarded as one of the best players to have never won on the PGA Tour. This was his third win of the PGA Tour season, a streak that began in October about an hour away at the Frys.com Open.</p><p>Walker joined some exclusive company. He is only the fourth player in the last 20 years to win three times in his first eight starts to a season. The others are Tiger Woods (who has done it eight times), Phil Mickelson and David Duval.</p><p>For a brief moment, it looked as though Walker might have a chance to join Greg Norman and Sergio Garcia as players to lose a six-shot lead in the final round.</p><p>He was never seriously challenged until Johnson, and then Renner, put together a strong finish. Johnson, a two-time winner at Pebble Beach, closed with a 66 on a card that included three bogeys. Renner, who had yet to make a cut all year, made five birdies on the back nine for a 67.</p><p>Walker made a 10-foot birdie on the 11th hole and was seemingly on his way.</p><p>But he hit a poor chip on the par-3 12th for a bogey. He three-putted the 13th for a bogey. He settled down for three simple pars and was two shots clear with two to play. Walker three-putted the 17th, missing a 3½-foot par putt. He tried to play it safe on the 18th with an iron off the tee that found the right rough.</p><p>From 25 feet above the hole, he hit the birdie putt too hard and had one anxious moment.</p><p>"I hate three-putting," Walker said. "I had two of them back there, and definitely didn't want another one on the last."</p><p>Walker finished on 11-under 277 and earned $1.188 million, expanding his lead in the Ryder Cup standings to more than $1 million over Mickelson in second place. The Ryder Cup is based on PGA Tour earnings, though there are still four majors (which count double), three World Golf Championships and The Players Championship remaining.</p><p>For now, the stars are aligned for Walker better than anything he sees through his high-powered telescope.</p><p>"I just go out and play golf," Walker said. "This is what I want to do and I've worked really hard to do it, to be here, and to be in this position and it's really cool."</p><p>Jordan Spieth had to return Sunday morning to complete his third round, which ended with his sixth three-putt of the round for a 78. He faced Pebble at its most vicious throughout the third round, though he bounced back with a bogey-free 67 to at least tie for fourth with Kevin Na (69).</p><p>And he hasn't lost his sense of humor.</p><p>"Yesterday was a day where you want to play Pebble Beach in that weather once in your life," Spieth said. "You just don't want it be Saturday when you're in the lead."</p><p>Chalk it up to another learning experience for Spieth, who said his 36 putts were more a product of not having the speed than the less-than-smooth quality.</p><p>"I felt like I needed birdies when I didn't," he said.</p><p>Another strong finish belonged to Graeme McDowell, returning to Pebble for the first time since his U.S. Open title in 2010. He closed with a 67, happy with a week in which he would have settled for just knocking some rust off his game before heading to Riviera next week.</p><p>Outside of Walker, however, the big winner was Renner.</p><p>He was among the Web.com Tour graduates who played poorly in the four "finals" event that determine priority ranking, and struggled to get into tournaments. In his fifth start, he not only made his first cut, Renner earned a spot at Riviera next week and will be in better position to get into events over the next couple of months.</p><p>"It was pretty big," Renner said. "I just knew I needed a good week. My back was up against the wall, and that's something I'm familiar with and I don't mind it. But I'm happy that I freed myself up a little bit for the rest of the year."</p><p>DIVOTS: Jim Renner and John Harkey Jr., the CEO of Consolidated Restaurant Operations, Inc., won the pro-am portion of the tournament. ... Tim Wilkinson, playing in the final group with Jimmy Walker, closed with a 73 and tied for seventh. That gets him into the Northern Trust Open next week at Riviera. ... Walker was the fourth Pebble Beach winner since 1994 to shoot 74 in the final round &lt;0x2014&gt; Johnny Miller in 1994, Dustin Johnson in 2010, and Graeme McDowell in the 2010 U.S. Open.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2014 02:38:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2568 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Kevin Stadler wins Phoenix Open as Bubba Watson falters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/kevin-stadler-wins-phoenix-open-bubba-watson-falters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p><p>SCOTTSDALE, Ariz. &mdash; The Smallrus finally hoisted a big PGA Tour trophy.</p><p>Kevin Stadler, the 33-year-old son of major champion Craig "The Walrus&rdquo; Stadler, won the Phoenix Open on Sunday for his first PGA Tour victory.</p><p>Stadler won when playing partner Bubba Watson missed a 5-foot par putt on 18.</p><p>"I was a little weird way to win a golf tournament,&rdquo; Stadler said. "I fully expected him to make the putt. I would have rather made mine to win it.&rdquo;</p><p>Stadler closed with 3-under-par 68 for a one-stroke victory over Watson and Graham DeLaet. Watson shot 71, and DeLaet had 65.</p><p>"He beat me,&rdquo; Watson said. "He's a great player.&rdquo;</p><p>Stadler won in his 239th tour start, earning a spot in the Masters Tournament &ndash; a tournament his father won in 1982. The Stadlers are the ninth father-son winners in tour history and will be the first to play in the same Masters.</p><p>"It's going to great for me because it's really my last one,&rdquo; said Craig Stadler, a 13-time PGA Tour winner with nine Champions Tour victories. "I kept saying, &lsquo;When he gets in, that's my last one.' ... I'm proud of him. It's awesome.&rdquo;</p><p>Kevin Stadler finished at 16-under 268 at TPC Scottsdale, his home course. Raised in Colorado, he played in Denver Broncos colors, wearing an orange shirt and blue pants and hat.</p><p>What was he thinking when Watson was standing over his par putt on 18 </p><p>"How long the playoff was going to take and how long until I can watch the football game &rdquo; Stadler said.</p><p>After Stadler and Watson each saved par after hitting into the water on the par-5 15th, Stadler tied Watson for the lead with a par on the par-3 16th hole. Watson hit into the front left bunker on the stadium hole and his 6-footer missed to the left.</p><p>At the 347-yard 17th, they each drove the green and two-putted for birdie from 90 feet &ndash; Watson holing out from 18 feet and Stadler from 5.</p><p>On the par-4 18th, Stadler hit his 110-yard approach to the back right pin to 10 feet. Watson drove into the right rough and hammered his 120-yard second over the green.</p><p>Watson bladed his shot from the trampled rough into the bank next to the green and it ran 5 feet past the hole. After Stadler missed his birdie try and tapped in for par, Watson's par try slid by the left side.</p><p>Watson is winless since the 2012 Masters.</p><p>"I was a challenging day,&rdquo; Watson said. "Again, it's the same thing, just waiting on every tee box and waiting on every shot.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2014 04:14:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2564 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott Stallings rallies to win at Torrey Pines, earn Masters invite</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/scott-stallings-rallies-win-torrey-pines-earn-masters-invite</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>&nbsp;</p><p>SAN DIEGO &mdash; In a tournament that was up for grabs, Scott Stallings hit a 4-iron worthy of a winner Sunday in the Farmers Insurance Open.</p><p>Stallings was in a five-way tie for the lead when he hit his second shot on the par-5 18th hole as hard as he could. It was enough to barely clear the water, and he took two putts from 40 feet for birdie and 4-under 68 at Torrey Pines.</p><p>That was enough for a one-shot victory when no one could catch him.</p><p>It was the third career PGA Tour victory for Stallings, who earned a return trip to the Masters Tournament and should move high enough in the world ranking to qualify for the Match Play Championship next month in Arizona.</p><p>K.J. Choi had the best score of the week on the South Course with a 66 and was among those who tied for second. The pins were set up in favorable positions for birdies, making the course play the easiest it had all week.</p><p>But that didn't make it easy &ndash; not for Gary Woodland, Jordan Spieth, Pat Perez and so many others who squandered a good chance to win.</p><p>Woodland appeared to have the best chance to catch Stallings. He was one shot behind &ndash; with plenty of length to reach the 18th in two &ndash; until he chose fairway metal off the tee on No. 17 and hooked it into the canyon. He felt he had to make his 45-foot par putt to have any chance, and three-putted for double bogey. Woodland, who had a one-shot lead going into the final round, missed an easy birdie attempt on the 18th and closed with 74.</p><p>"This will be hard to swallow,&rdquo; Woodland said. "I felt like I kind of gave one away today.&rdquo;</p><p>Marc Leishman of Australia had the last chance to force a playoff, but his drive on the 18th went well right and bounced off the cart path and a fan. He had no shot at the green in two, and his wedge for an eagle stopped a few feet to the side of the hole. His tap-in birdie gave him a 71 and a share of second.</p><p>Stallings finished at 9-under 279.</p><p>Jason Day (68) and Graham DeLaet of Canada (68) each made birdie on the last hole to tie for second. So did Perez, the San Diego native who grew up at Torrey Pines and whose father is the longtime starter on the first tee at the Farmers Insurance Open. Perez missed a 10-foot birdie chance on the 17th. He closed with 70.</p><p>"It's great and bad,&rdquo; Perez said about his runner-up finish. "This is the one I want to win more than anything in the world, and I came up short. ... I thought today would have been my day. I would like to be in that position again.&rdquo;</p><p>Spieth didn't make a birdie over the last 15 holes, and he fell back with back-to-back birdies late in the round. The 20-year-old Texan made a meaningless bogey on the last hole that only cost him a spot in the top 10. By then, his day was over. He closed with 75.</p><p>"I just lost control of the golf ball,&rdquo; Spieth said.</p><p>He also revealed that he tweaked his ankle Friday and felt it kept him from getting into the right position on his back swing.</p><p>Woodland went from a chance to win to a tie for 10th.</p><p>Deep into tournament, nearly 20 players were separated by only two shots. It was similar to when Jimmy Walker won the Sony Open two weeks ago in Honolulu, emerging from the pack with a late burst of birdies.</p><p>Stallings made six birdies over his last 11 holes, along with a pair of bogeys. Most remarkable is that he managed to hit only four fairways in the final round. But one that he did was important &ndash; the 537-yard closing hole, giving him a chance to get home in two for a birdie at worst.</p><p>He said caddie Jon Yarbrough &ndash; fired by Woodland late last year &ndash; told him in the 18th fairway, "Let's see what you've got. You've worked your butt off.&rdquo;</p><p>"I hit 4-iron as hard as I could,&rdquo; Stallings said.</p><p>It was just enough to clear the water, and while it trickled off the front of the green, he could still use his putter. He lagged it up to 30 inches for a short birdie putt that turned out to be the winner.</p><p>Charley Hoffman, another San Diego native, made a hole-in-one on the third hole and closed with 67 to tie for seventh, along with Ryo Ishikawa of Japan and Will MacKenzie, who each had a 70.</p><p>Six players finished in the top 10 that are not in the Phoenix Open next week. Ordinarily, a top 10 gets a player into the next open tournament. In this case, the field already is full and they only can be alternates. That list includes Justin Thomas, who was playing this week on his fourth out of seven allotted sponsor exemptions. Thomas shot 69.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2014 00:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2563 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Growth of game goes south of the border</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/growth-game-goes-south-border</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Augusta National Golf Club's global growth initiatives are spreading as quickly as kudzu.</p><p>With the 5-year-old Asian-Pacific Amateur already producing banner headline stars, the club will partner with the R&A and the USGA to bring the model to Latin America - which for the purposes of this new endeavor stretches from Bermuda to Tierra del Fuego.</p><p>Masters Tournament chairman Billy Payne and his cohorts from golf's governing bodies announced on Wednesday in Argentina the formation of the new Latin America Amateur Championship. The first event will be played Jan. 15-18, 2015, at Pilar Golf outside Buenos Aires, with the champion earning an invitation into the 2015 Masters less than three months later.</p><p>"We believe this event will be motivating to current and future generations of golfers and, one day, create heroes that will inspire others to give the game a try," said Payne, who had one of those inspirations seated on the front row in a green jacket - 2009 Masters champion and 2013 runner-up Angel Cabrera. "This belief has guided us well through the early successes of the Asia-Pacific Amateur Championship and, with the collective expertise in guiding the game of golf provided by the R&A and the USGA, we are hopeful in achieving equally exciting results."</p><p>Whatever skepticism there was that a neophyte competition in a relative golfing outpost could provide worthy competitors for Augusta in April were squashed by the success of Payne's first foray. The Asian version that started in 2009 has, as R&A chief executive Peter Dawson put it, "exceeded our wildest expectations." The 2010 and '11 winner, Hideki Matsuyama of Japan, made the Masters cut twice and has already risen to No, 24 in the world at the tender age of 21. The 2012 winner, Tianlang Guan, became the youngest golfer in history to make the cut in a major when he was 14 last April and finished tied for 58th at Augusta.</p><p>"Combine opportunity with inspiration, some miracles are going to happen," Payne said.</p><p>The Latin America Amateur champion will get even more opportunities to create miracles, with the USGA stepping in to offer extra incentives. The winner and runner-up will get exemptions into the final stages of qualifying for the U.S. and British Opens, while the champion will receive full exemptions to the U.S. and British Amateurs as well as any other USGA amateur events for which is he eligible.</p><p>"We've proven that golf can create role models," Payne said, saying this venture will "attempt to duplicate - no, to do better - than what we've accomplished in Asia."</p><p>While Argentina and several other Latin nations have a rich golfing history dating back a century, most of the 27 nations that will be represented in the LAAC have little tradition in the game. Combine this with golf's return to the Olympics in 2016 in Brazil, and that one-two punch could provide the spark of inspiration where it had no chance of igniting before.</p><p>"By partnering together we believe we can positively impact this region of the world where golf is already growing," said USGA executive director Mike Davis.</p><p>Payne hinted five years ago that expansion of Bobby Jones' beloved amateur opportunities would extend to other regions, but he believed that might come at the hands of future club chairmen. After launching the Asia-Pacific Amateur in a market where Augusta National has focused most of its growth efforts with numerous special exemptions the last decade, he called that an "initial target."</p><p>With Masters invitations now being handed to champions in the U.S., British, Asia-Pacific and Latin America amateurs, the only remaining global market without a dedicated entry into Augusta is Africa.</p><p>"To the extent we have adequate resources and partners to help us accomplish that goal, we will not be restricted geographically in the future," Payne said in 2009. "However, that also presupposes that this first attempt through time will in fact produce the results that we think it will and in fact bring some converts and enthusiasm among the next generation to the game of golf. So if this Asian effort proves that theory correct, than I think it's logical to assume that - given if we stand the test of resources and partners - we would at least entertain the thought of going other places."</p><p>Little did he know then how quickly his growth mission would accelerate. Payne has made growing the game a hallmark of his term at chairman. Since taking over from Hootie Johnson in 2006, Payne has helped launched two major amateur events and, along with the USGA and PGA of America, created the junior Drive, Chip & Putt Championship that will conclude its first competition at Augusta National the Sunday before Masters week.</p><p>He also developed a program for junior golfers to attend the Masters with badge holders and launched a video game to support the charitable Masters Tournament Foundation he established. In 2012, Payne ended Augusta National's long-standing policy of exclusive male membership by inviting Condoleezza Rice and Darla Moore to join the club.</p><p>It all adds up to an impressive resume of leadership in trying to build the game of golf globally.</p><p>Now the Latin America Amateur is "kind of a logical extension of ways that these three organizations feel we ought to be investing in the future of the game on a global basis," Payne said.</p><p>"So a lot going on in the world of development. But I think importantly, we've adopted, I believe, a better strategy in that we are all doing it together."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 23:37:56 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2562 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Masters helps create Latin America Amateur Championship</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/masters-helps-create-latin-america-amateur-championship</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>Golf's efforts to grow the game will extend a little further south of the United States beginning in 2015.</p><p>The Latin America Amateur Championship will strive to promote the game throughout South America, Central America, Mexico and the Caribbean. The creation of the tournament was announced Wednesday morning in Buenos Aires by the Masters Tournament, the R&A and the U.S. Golf Association.</p><p>The inaugural tournament will be held Jan. 15-18 at Pilar Golf Club, located near Buenos Aires. The format will be 72 holes of stroke play with a field of 120 players made up of the region's top male amateurs.</p><p>Hoping to emulate the success of the Asia-Pacific Amateur Championship, which began in 2009, the three founding partners are targeting the 27 IOC-recognized countries and territories in the Latin America region.</p><p>The winner will receive an invitation to the Masters, an exemption into the British Amateur and an exemption into the U.S. Amateur and any other USGA Amateur championship for which he is eligible.</p><p>The champion and runner-up will receive exemptions into final qualifying for both the British Open and U.S. Open.</p><p>With major champions Roberto de Vicenzo and Angel Cabrera, the 2009 Masters winner, hailing from the region, the game's leaders see great potential in Latin America. Cabrera and fellow pro golfer Eduardo Romero attended Wednesday's news conference along with several other dignitaries.</p><p>Billy Payne, chairman of Augusta National Golf Club and the Masters, said some countries in the region have a rich history with golf and others do not.</p><p>"I think what we propose to bring to the table is opportunity and see where that opportunity, the way the kids react to it, see where that takes us, hoping for a result akin to what we have experienced in Asia," Payne said.</p><p>With golf returning to the Olympics in 2016 in Rio de Janeiro, the game will get considerable attention in Latin America.</p><p>"I think it's a happy coincidence starting this event in 2015," said Peter Dawson, chief executive of The R&A. "It's going to be a double boost for golf in this region."</p><p>While there is a speculation that a test event will be held at the course in Brazil before the Olympics, Dawson said no decision has been made on the 2016 venue for the Latin America Amateur.</p><p>"It's one of several options being considered," he said.</p><p>Payne said discussions about expanding to other geographical regions began a couple of years ago. </p><p>"So it's been in the works, and I think just kind of a logical extension of ways that these three organizations feel we ought to be investing in the future of the game on a global basis," Payne said.</p><p>Former Asia-Pacific Amateur champions Hideki Matsuyama and Tianlang Guan have both achieved success following their wins.</p><p>Matsuyama, who won the tournament in 2010 and 2011, has risen to No. 24 in the Official World Golf Rankings. Guan, who was victorious in 2012, became the youngest Masters participant at age 14 and made the 36-hole cut at Augusta National last year.</p><p>Mike Davis, executive director of the USGA, said the new event should boost interest in the game.</p><p>"When you think about elite competitive golf, whether it's elite amateur golf or touring professionals, it has a way of growing the game," Davis said. "Recreational players watch that, and it inspires them. And we think that will absolutely happen here."</p><p>While the Masters prefers to keep its field size at no more than 100, Payne said the addition of the Latin American champion will "have no real impact."</p><p>Plus, the U.S. Amateur Public Links will be discontinued after this year, removing one of the six slots traditionally reserved for amateurs at the Masters.</p><p>"We haven't slotted it in exchange for any spot," Payne said. "We're wild and crazy about field size and we watch it like a hawk. You want exactly the right number. We're going to figure out how to make it work no matter how many qualify."</p><p>The collaboration from three of the major golf organizations is just the latest effort to grow the game. This April, Augusta National will hold the inaugural Drive, Chip & Putt Championship for youngsters. The Masters Tournament Foundation, USGA and PGA of America are partners in that initiative.</p><p>"I think importantly we've adopted, I believe, a better strategy in that we are all doing it together," Payne said. "I think that portends well for the future and what we may be able to do down the road."</p><p> ]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2014 23:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2561 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Former Augusta State star Patrick Reed wins Humana Challenge</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/former-augusta-state-star-patrick-reed-wins-humana-challenge</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>LA QUINTA, Calif. - Patrick Reed lost his putting touch for a few hours in the final round of the Humana Challenge. He found it when things were getting interesting.</p><p> <p>After shooting three straight 9-under 63s to open a seven-stroke lead, Reed had a 1-under 71 on Sunday at PGA West's Arnold Palmer Private Course to beat Ryan Palmer by two strokes.</p><p> <p>Finally resembling the guy who talked Saturday about being in a "putting coma," Reed ran in an 18-footer for birdie on the par-3 15th to push his advantage to three strokes and parred the final three holes. He completed the wire-to-wire victory at 28-under 260.</p><p> <p>The 23-year-old Reed has two victories in his first 46 PGA Tour starts, winning the Wyndham Championship in a playoff in August. He was projected to jump from 73rd to 42nd in the world ranking, enough to lock up a spot next month in the 64-man Match Play Championship field.</p><p> <p>Palmer made a 15-foot eagle putt on the final hole for a 63.</p><p> <p>Zach Johnson and Justin Leonard tied for third at 25 under. Johnson birdied the final five holes for a 62, the best round of the week. Leonard parred his last two for a 65.</p><p> <p>Other than key 18-footer on No. 15, the longest putt Reed holed was a 5-footer for a par save on the par-4 13th. That also was a crucial putt after he played the previous eight holes in 1 over with four bogeys, three birdies and a par.</p><p> <p>In that eight-hole stretch, Todd missed two 6-foot par putts and an 8-footer and dropped another stroke with a poor bunker shot on the par-3 12th. He two-putted for birdie on two par 5s and made a 4-footer on the par-4 eighth for the other birdie.</p><p> <p>Reed also two-putted from 12 feet for a birdie on the par-5 second hole, but his eagle putt near had a chance - signaling that his putter had cooled off overnight.</p><p> <p>On Saturday, Reed broke the PGA Tour record for relation to par for the first 54 holes, finishing at 27 under. He also became the first player in tour history to open with three rounds of 63 or better.</p><p> <p>Reed's wife, Justine, is pregnant with their first child, forcing her to turn over caddying duties to her brother, Kessler Karain. She has walked every hole this year and plans to caddie again after the baby arrives around Memorial Day.</p><p> <p>After helping Augusta State win NCAA titles in 2010 and 2011, Reed drew attention in 2012 when he successfully Monday-qualified for six events and made 12 starts. The former Baton Rouge, La., high school champion earned his PGA Tour card in December 2012, surviving six rounds of Q-school at PGA West.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:34:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2560 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Stulb, architect who designed Eisenhower Cabin and Sarazen Bridge  at Augusta National, dies at 96</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/stulb-architect-who-designed-eisenhower-cabin-and-sarazen-bridge-augu</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>H. Lowrey Stulb, the architect responsible for designing the Eisenhower Cabin and the Sarazen Bridge at Augusta National Golf Club, didn't go around bragging about his accomplishments at the home of the Masters Tournament.</p><p>After all, they were just a small part of a much larger body of work. His firm, Eve and Stulb, designed many prominent buildings around Augusta after World War II, including the Augusta Richmond County Library on Greene Street, Butler High School, Langford Junior High School, a research and education building at the Medical College of Georgia, the Convent of Saint Helena and Saint Augustine of Canterbury Episcopal Church.</p><p>But Stulb, who died Wednesday at 96, was mighty proud of his affiliation with the private club.</p><p>"He was very modest," his son, Franklin Stulb, said Thursday.</p><p>"He got the work at Augusta National because his father-in-law was Ed Dudley (the club's first professional)."</p><p>A funeral service will be held 11 a.m. Saturday at Saint Augustine of Canterbury Episcopal Church with interment following at Westover Cemetery.</p><p>Lowrey Stulb's love affair with the Masters began in 1934 when he was a student at Richmond Academy and served as a gallery guard for the first Augusta National Invitation Tournament.</p><p>On the Wednesday before the 1934 tournament, players competed in an alternate-shot format event. Stulb followed Bobby Jones that day and held one end of a cane pole while another cadet held the other end to prevent patrons from walking too close to the players.</p><p>Stulb kept the scorecard from that round, and discovered it years later when he found his old cadet uniform.</p><p>Stulb was at the tournament the following year when Gene Sarazen recorded his famous double eagle on the 15th hole. Stulb said he heard the loud roar, but, "I'm the only person who didn't see it," he said.</p><p>Stulb received his architecture degree from Georgia Tech and received a fellowship to the Princeton Graduate School. He joined the Army Corps of Engineers during World War II and opened his architectural firm with partner William Eve in 1945.</p><p>He married Elizabeth Dudley and that led to him getting a call to design quarters for President Eisenhower and his family for their frequent visits to Augusta.</p><p>In 1953, the Eisenhower Cabin - some call it Ike's Cabin, Stulb always called it Mamie's Cabin - was built near the 10th tee at Augusta National.</p><p>It consisted of three floors, including a basement that was used by the Secret Service as its headquarters in Augusta.</p><p>During an interview with The Augusta Chronicle, Stulb said the president kept a red phone next to his bed, presumably the presidential hot line in case of an emergency.</p><p>"We started Monday morning at 8 o'clock after the tournament that year," Stulb said. </p><p>"We had construction crews in there that morning. We had until Oct. 1. On Oct. 1, they turned keys over right on time."</p><p>The cabin wasn't Stulb's only project at Augusta National. He also designed the Sarazen Bridge; the golf shop, a suite above it, and an office used by Eisenhower; and the wine cellar underneath the clubhouse.</p><p>Stulb came up with the idea for the Sarazen Bridge, which runs to the left of the pond fronting the 15th green, to commemorate Sarazen's "Shot Heard "Round the World." </p><p>The flat footbridge was dedicated on the 20th anniversary of the famous shot.</p><p>"It isn't a bridge," he said, "but we'll call it that."</p><p>His son said Stulb had been in a nursing home for the past 15 months, but he still enjoyed talking about his work at Augusta National.</p><p>"He was proud of the work he did," Franklin Stulb said. "That was a bright topic for him to talk about."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 23:27:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2559 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Masters winner Adam Scott edges Tiger Woods for player of year honors</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/masters-winner-adam-scott-edges-tiger-woods-player-year-honors</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>KAPALUA, Hawaii - Masters Tournament champion Adam Scott narrowly beat out Tiger Woods as the male player of the year in voting by the Golf Writers Association of America.</p><p>The GWAA takes into account more than just a player's performance on the PGA Tour. Scott won four times around the world, none bigger than his playoff victory at Augusta National Golf Club to become the first Australian in a green jacket. He also won a FedEx Cup playoff event and twice in Australia, and he joined Jason Day to win the portion of the World Cup for Australia at Royal Melbourne.</p><p>Out of 218 ballots, Scott won by five votes.</p><p>"It is an honor to be recognized as the most consistent male golfer of 2013 and it is appreciated to have the respect of the Golf Writers of America. Thank you," Scott said from Kapalua, where he is playing in the Hyundai Tournament of Champions.</p><p>Woods won five times on the PGA Tour, including The Players Championship and two World Golf Championships, though he went a fifth consecutive year without winning a major. Woods also won the PGA Tour money title and the Vardon Trophy for the lowest scoring average.</p><p>Woods won player of the year from the PGA Tour (a vote of players) and PGA of America (based on points). Those awards consider only a player's PGA Tour record. The PGA Tour does not disclose vote totals.</p><p>The other GWAA awards were landslides.</p><p>Inbee Park, who had three consecutive majors among her six victories on the LPGA Tour, received 91 percent of the vote to win female player of the year. Women's British Open champion Stacy Lewis and Evian Championship winner Suzann Pettersen received the other votes.</p><p>Kenny Perry, who won two majors on the Champions Tour and captured the Schwab Cup, also had 91 percent of the vote for senior player of the year over Bernhard Langer and David Frost.</p><p>"It is my highest honor, from the players or the writers, to be named player of the year," Perry said. "Here I am at 53 doing stuff I probably shouldn't be doing, so I'm honored that the writers are paying attention to me."</p><p>They will be honored April 9 at the annual GWAA Awards Dinner in Augusta.</p><p>Scott received 75 votes, or 34 percent of the vote, compared with 70 votes for Woods. In a season that had so many players accomplish so much, Phil Mickelson received 17 percent, while Henrik Stenson got 16 percent. Mickelson won the British Open for the third leg of the Grand Slam, along with the Phoenix Open and the Scottish Open. Stenson became the first player to win the FedEx Cup and the Race to Dubai in the same season.</p><p>Scott played 20 times around the world. Along with his four wins, he had the lead briefly on the back nine of the British Open, where he tied for third, and he tied for fifth in the PGA Championship. Woods had two top 10s in the majors, a tie for fourth at the Masters and a tie for sixth in the British Open.</p><p>Park rose to No. 1 in the women's world ranking shortly after winning the Kraft Nabisco Championship. She won the LPGA Championship, and then made it three straight majors at the U.S. Women's Open. She failed in her bid to become the first player to win four majors in one season, but still led women's golf with six victories and captured the LPGA Tour money title for the second straight year.</p><p>"Last year was a year that I could never forget," Park said. "I was able to put my name among the greatest players around the world. Now, on top of that, I am being recognized and honored by golf writers. They are those who know what has just happened last year in every detail. I can almost say that they know me better than I know myself. That's why this honor is very special and means a lot to me."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2014 23:49:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2558 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>14 added to Masters field through world ranking</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/14-added-masters-field-through-world-ranking</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> Augusta National Golf Club added 14 players to the field for the Masters Tournament when the final world ranking of the year was published Monday.</p><p> That brings the field to 90 players who are expected to compete April 10-13, and again raises the possibility of the Masters exceeding 100 players for the first time in nearly 50 years. Augusta National has the smallest field of the four majors and prefers to keep it under 100 to enhance the overall experience at its tournament.</p><p> This is the third time in the last four years that the field was at least 90 players going into a new calendar year. There were 99 players for the 2011 Masters, the most since 103 players competed in 1966.</p><p> Those who qualified by being in the top 50 of the final ranking were Hideki Matsuyama, Thomas Bjorn, Jamie Donaldson, Victor Dubuisson, Gonzalo Fernandez-Castano, Miguel Angel Jimenez, Francesco Molinari, Rickie Fowler, Matteo Manassero, David Lynn, Thongchai Jaidee, Peter Hanson, Joost Luiten and Branden Grace.</p><p> Players can still qualify by winning a PGA Tour event (except for the Puerto Rico Open) or being in the top 50 on March 30, a full week before the Masters.</p><p> Matsuyama qualified at No. 23. It will be his third appearance at the Masters, and his first as a pro. Matsuyama was a two-time winner of the Asia-Pacific Amateur, which awards an exemption to the Masters. He made the cut both times as an amateur.</p><p> "I'm ecstatic I qualified for the Masters through my play for this year,&rdquo; Matsuyama said through an interpreter in October, when it was clear he would be in the top 50.</p><p> He won four times this year on the Japan Golf Tour and had a pair of top 10s in the majors.</p><p> Fowler was the only American of the 14 from the world ranking, though two other players (Peter Hanson, David Lynn) were PGA Tour members, who have more options available to them during the year.</p><p> The Masters changed the criteria for the 2014 tournament, though that appears to have little bearing on the number of qualified players. Because the PGA Tour went to a wraparound season (October through September), the Masters awarded spots to the winners of tournaments held in the fall. Jimmy Walker, Ryan Moore and Chris Kirk qualified by winning those events. The other winners of fall events &mdash; Webb Simpson, Dustin Johnson and Harris English &mdash; previously were eligible for the Masters.</p><p> Augusta National eliminated the category for top 30 on the money list, though that didn't keep out any player who qualified.</p><p> The club now takes the top 12 and ties from the previous Masters (instead of the top 16) and the top four and ties from the U.S. Open (instead of the top eight). That eliminated only one player &mdash; David Toms &mdash; who would have been eligible under the previous category. The others would have made it through other criteria.</p><p> When the FedEx Cup was created in 2007, Augusta National returned to its practice of inviting PGA Tour winners (at events that offered full FedEx Cup points). Since then, the largest increase in the field from January until the Masters was the addition of 11 players for this year's tournament.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2013 21:35:29 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2557 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Chris Kirk wins McGladrey Classic</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/chris-kirk-wins-mcgladrey-classic</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>ST. SIMONS ISLAND, Ga. - Chris Kirk survived a wild back nine Sunday to win the McGladrey Classic, thanks to one big mistake by Briny Baird that kept him winless in 365 starts on the PGA Tour.</p><p>Kirk closed with 4-under 66 for his second career win, though he received plenty of help from Baird. They were tied for the lead playing the 18th hole at Sea Island when Baird drove into a fairway bunker, the ball blow his feet. He topped a 4-iron that went about 90 yards and into a hazard.</p><p>Kirk only had to make par for a one-shot win over Baird (67) and Tim Clark (62).</p><p>"He was making 4 from where he was," Baird said. "I didn't have a really good like but it was a doable shot. My foot just slipped. It was a doable shot. It really was. I didn't do a good job."</p><p>The victory sends Kirk to the Masters for the first time. He had been living at Sea Island for the last six years until moving back to Atlanta.</p><p>He had reason to exhale when it was over. Kirk made birdies on the 11th and 12th holes to build a two-shot lead, only to find himself trailing two holes later. Baird made a long birdie putt on the 13th, and Kirk hit into the hazard on the 14th and had to scramble for bogey.</p><p>Baird looked like the winner as they walked toward the green on the par-5 15th. He had 40 feet for eagle, while Kirk pulled his approach into the water left of the green, and slammed his wedge into the turf when his chip settled 20 feet away.</p><p>Baird ran his eagle attempt 4 feet by the cup and three-putted for par, while Kirk made his 20-foot par putt to stay one shot behind. Kirk caught him with a 15-foot birdie putt on the 17th, setting the stage for an 18th hole where the tournament was lost as much as it was won.</p><p>It was a crushing loss for Baird, who now has six runner-up finishes since the 41-year-old first joined the PGA Tour in 1999.</p><p>Baird has talked for years about how he would rather have a consistent year of top finishes and a trip to the Tour Championship than one win and no other tournaments in contention. Even this week, he spoke about golf being more about making money than winning trophies.</p><p>"It's not all about winning," Baird said Sunday after his finish. "I've said that, but this hurts. This really does. This is very disappointing."</p><p>The only consolation was how he finished after his topped shot into the hazard. Baird made a 25-foot bogey putt to share second place with Clark. That gave him $484,000, which secures his card for the rest of the season. Baird was exempt on a major medical extension from having surgery on both shoulders at the end of 2012.</p><p>The bogey putt was worth a difference of $220,000.</p><p>Clark birdied his last three holes for a 62, the best score of the final round, and was on the practice range in case Kirk and Baird stumbled. Only one of them did.</p><p>Kirk finished at 14-under 266. It was the fourth straight year since the McGladrey Classic began that it was decided by one shot.</p><p>Scott Brown (66), Brian Gay (67) and John Senden (67) were two shots behind.</p><p> ]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 23:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2542 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>If the PGA of America is looking, Australia is interested</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/if-pga-america-looking-australia-interested</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>GOLD COAST, Australia &mdash; The rare inspired notion from part of golf's entrenched establishment has created a major buzz in Australia and other far eastern points on the leading edge of the International Date Line.</p><p>News a few weeks ago that the PGA of America was analyzing the potential to take its almost 100-year-old PGA Championship overseas perhaps once or twice a decade was greeted with enthusiasm in Australia &ndash; where the conditions would be perfect for playing host to one of golf's four majors to alleviate the scheduling stress in an Olympic year.</p><p>"If they're serious, we're serious,&rdquo; said Brian Thorburn, the chief executive for the PGA of Australia. "We'll be putting our hands up and trying to be at the front of the queue.&rdquo;</p><p>Thorburn has already been in touch with PGA of America chief executive Pete Bevacqua and they plan to have a chat in a couple weeks when they get together at an industry conference. Bevacqua told The Associated Press this week that the PGA was "more than halfway through a serious analysis&rdquo; of the concept, but said it was "far from a fait accompli&rdquo; that an occasional international stop would happen.</p><p>It should happen, however. There is no reason that three of golf's four major championships have to be in the United States every single year. It's a big world out there, and the growing global nature of the game makes spreading the major profile to different markets a no brainer.</p><p>Especially if golf develops a permanent place in the Olympics. In 2016, when the PGA celebrates its 98th championship at Baltusrol, the season's fourth major will be forced to move out of its traditional early August window to make room for a two-week global break while golf makes its return to the Olympics in Brazil.</p><p>Pushing the PGA up to the end of July creates all manner of scheduling headaches. The British Open is already pinched by Wimbledon moving its finish a week later starting in 2015. So it's possible that the schedule could take the game's best players from the British to the WGC-Bridgestone to the PGA in consecutive weeks leading right into the Olympics. Other tournaments on the schedule will suffer.</p><p>If the PGA opted for an international move during Olympic years, it could shift to the Southern Hemisphere and play anywhere from October to February and separate itself from the summer clutter. Australia marks the perfect option, because a 9 a.m. to 3 p.m. final-round playing block Down Under would translate into a 6 p.m. to midnight TV window on Saturday night on the East Coast in America &ndash; a more desirable viewing window than the morning to early afternoon slot that the British Open features.</p><p>"There's no reason we couldn't deliver a U.S. broadcast,&rdquo; Thorburn said. "I imagine that would make the networks pretty happy. So bring it on.&rdquo;</p><p>The PGA venues have been booked out through the 2019 event at Bethpage Black, which coincides with the expiration of the major's current contract with CBS. So the 2020 event &ndash; when the Olympics will be staged in Tokyo &ndash; makes a potentially perfect time to stage this grand experiment.</p><p>"It would need to work for the PGA Tour, and it would need to work for the PGA tour players,&rdquo; Bevacqua said of the feasibility checklist. "Another would be the PGA in the particular area we would consider. We would want the international PGAs to be a part of this and share in this. Many pieces would have to fall in place.&rdquo;</p><p>Australia already has a perfect major venue equipped to handle something on the scale of the PGA. Royal Melbourne &ndash; rated 13th in the world according to the latest Golf Magazine rankings &ndash; has played host to two Presidents Cups and will stage the Australian Masters and World Cup in the next two weeks on its composite course. The renowned Alister MacKenzie design &ndash; which top golfers including Tiger Woods and Phil Mickelson count among their favorites &ndash; has massive space for all the infrastructure required to host a major, including its lease of the public Sandringham Golf Course directly across the street from the club's entrance.</p><p>"Clearly it's got the credentials and the Sandbelt is a great place for golf,&rdquo; Thorburn said. "Australia is known as a great place to play golf and we can run great events from Olympic Games to Commonwealth Games to Rugby World Cups and in the golf context the Presidents Cup twice. So we would step up to the challenge. To have a MAJOR in Australia would be huge.&rdquo;</p><p>Australia's star players agree.</p><p>"I think the PGA of America is really forward thinking in the way they approach everything,&rdquo; said Adam Scott, the reigning Masters Tournament champion. "They're obviously exploring every avenue and I think that's the right thing to do. I think it's the right thing that PGA of Australia then gets involved, absolutely. If there was a chance of hosting a major in Australia, that would be incredible. I have no idea about the details of any of that kind of stuff, but if I was with the PGA of Australia I'd be giving them a call pretty quick smart.&rdquo;</p><p>Said Marc Leishman: "I mean, that would be unbelievable if they could. I'd probably be surprised if they did, just being the U.S. PGA Championship, you'd think it would be in America. But I guess if it was to go somewhere, this would be a great place for it to be. There's plenty of unbelievable golf courses throughout the whole country, so they could get whatever weather conditions they wanted. It would be awesome. I'm sure the crowds would be huge and they'd get a great field being a major, it would be awesome for Australian golf and good exposure for the PGA.&rdquo;</p><p>Even American Rickie Fowler had no objections to playing a second major far afield every four years or so.</p><p>"It would be cool if there was a way some of the PGAs around the world could make it where it could become more of a global major,&rdquo; Fowler said. "That's the only one that has a chance to travel. With the game growing globally the way it is, it could help grow he game around the world.&rdquo;</p><p>And it could help distinguish the season's fourth major as one of the progressive leaders in the game.</p><p>"What's important is we boil down our missions to two pillars &ndash; serve our members and grow the game,&rdquo; Bevacqua said. "The ultimate test will be can we check both boxes  Does it make sense to occasionally play the PGA Championship overseas  Would growing the brand globally help our members  Would it grow the game  Part two is easy.&rdquo;</p><p>The whole thing could be easy. All it takes is the vision to commit.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2013 23:35:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2541 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott plans to bring Down Under flavor to Champions Dinner</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/scott-plans-bring-down-under-flavor-champions-dinner</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> GOLD COAST, Australia &ndash; For all the emotion Adam Scott showed when he won the Masters Tournament and all the fun he's had sporting the green jacket, the tastiest fruits of his Masters bounty still lie ahead.</p><p> "All of the greatest stuff about winning the Masters is yet to come,&rdquo; Scott said this week as he makes his homecoming at the Australian PGA Championship. "I really believe that for me, I think all of the stuff that I'll personally enjoy the most is yet to come. Going back (to Augusta), going to the dinner, being up in the Champions Locker Room with legends of the game but also some of my friends who've won it, too &ndash; I think it is going to be an incredible experience for the rest of my life.&rdquo;</p><p> The biggest order of business upon his return in April will be playing host to the Champions Dinner on Tuesday night before the tournament. Masters winners have survived exotic fare through the years such as haggis and monkey gland sauce, so perhaps "dog's eye and dead horse&rdquo; or Moreton Bay Bugs on the menu won't be too much of a shock to the system.</p><p> Scott hasn't finalized the menu he'll serve in April, but the first Australian winner in the history of the tournament promises to bring a Down Under flare to the evening.</p><p> "There's going to be a pretty strong Australian theme to this dinner,&rdquo; Scott said on the eve of the Aussie PGA in his home state of Queensland. "I'm going to serve up stuff that hopefully everyone will enjoy but I haven't got too far into exactly what is happening.&rdquo;</p><p> One thing that probably won't make it to the table is vegemite &ndash; the popular Australian spreadable brown paste that commonly makes it onto toast or sandwiches. It's on the bitter side, so a thin smear is recommended.</p><p> "I don't think I can serve Arnold Palmer vegemite on toast,&rdquo; Scott said with a laugh. "I'd like to for the laugh but I'm not sure I'm going to do that. I have a little respect for those guys and everything.&rdquo;</p><p> Australia doesn't really have a recognizable national cuisine, but meat pies would be the most ubiquitous item akin to a hot dog in America. In the traditional rhyming slang of the nation, the locals would call a meat pie with sauce a "dog's eye and dead horse.&rdquo;</p><p> "I don't know that I can get away with serving meat pies unfortunately,&rdquo; Scott told cocktail guests at a function held by Tourism and Events Queensland. "But I will definitely get something from Queensland and the rest will be Australian as well.&rdquo;</p><p> While there is no shortage of quality grain-fed beef in Australia &ndash; including Wagyu and Cape Grim &ndash; it's a seafood item from the waters off Brisbane that has the best chance of finding its way to Augusta.</p><p> Moreton Bay Bugs &ndash; a crustacean that falls somewhere between a crayfish and a lobster &ndash; is a favored local delicacy.</p><p> "I think Moreton Bay Bugs are definitely going to get a run, they're my favorite,&rdquo; Scott said.</p><p> The only thing Scott will guarantee is a prime assortment of Australian wines such as a shiraz or Sauvignon blanc.</p><p> "Definitely there's going to be some good wines because we have some good wines in Australia,&rdquo; he said. "They have that to look forward to at the very least.&rdquo;</p><p> Scott has already made the traditional donation of a club used in his victory to the Augusta National Golf Club archives, but it's not one that might require constructing a special display case.</p><p> Despite becoming the only player to win a green jacket using a long putter &ndash; making unforgettable putts on the 72nd hole and the clincher on the 10th green in the playoff &ndash; it was his Titleist driver that got left behind for posterity. The putter is still in Scott's bag &ndash; probably through 2015 before the use of anchored clubs becomes illegal in 2016.</p><p> "I really should've (given them the putter),&rdquo; Scott admitted. "I've given them the driver because it was kind of hard to part ways with the putter that I'd just won the Masters with &ndash; as much as I would like to put the putter in there.</p><p> "Maybe I'll switch it out (one day). But I've given them the driver because I thought I drove it so well as well, especially on 18 in the playoff. But the putter would have been cool to give them. I'm still using that same one. Maybe when it gets a rest it might get there.&rdquo;</p><p> By then, Scott will have had two more chances to win at Augusta with his broomstick putter before either retiring it or learning how to use it without holding it against his chest.</p><p> If he keeps winning green jackets, they can eventually use it to spread the vegemite on toast.</p><p> &nbsp;</p><p> Reach Scott Michaux at (706) 823-3219</p><p> or scott.michaux@augustachronicle.com.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2013 19:12:26 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2540 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Masters winner Scott relishes 'green jacket roadshow' </title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/masters-winner-scott-relishes-green-jacket-roadshow</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/12786959.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>GOLD COAST, Australia &mdash; On the same Tuesday a sports-obsessed nation annually takes the day off to celebrate a horse race, some invited guests got the rarest of all Australian sporting gifts &ndash; a glimpse of the green jacket.</p><p>Masters Tournament champion Adam Scott donned the jacket for the first time publicly on Australian soil at a corporate dinner with fellow golf stars at Royal Pines Resort before this week's Australian PGA Championship. It is the most significant sporting prize an Australian had never won until Scott's historic playoff victory over Angel Cabrera in April.</p><p>Scott welcomed all comers.</p><p>"I think this is the best part about it, is hearing where everyone was when I made the putt or how they felt,&rdquo; Scott said. "That's what makes it even more special for me is hearing their stories or getting to see the jacket because just as a golf fan myself, seeing it for the first time was amazing. I like the fact that I can share that with everyone else.&rdquo;</p><p>It's hard to convey the magnitude of Scott's win on the Australian sports psyche. The first Australian to play in the Masters was Jim Ferrier in 1940, and the Sydney native blew a four-shot lead after three rounds in 1950.</p><p>But the Australian complex regarding the Masters really began when Greg Norman became the poster figure for Aussie heartbreak at Augusta with nine top-10 showings, including excruciating runner-up finishes in 1986, '87 and '96.</p><p>"It became a thing the top Aussie players had to deal with every year,&rdquo; said Peter Lonard, who played in five Masters.</p><p>Golf is one of the sports Australians consider themselves good at, and the green jacket became the most elusive prize.</p><p>"We'd won the Ashes in cricket, World Cups (rugby and cricket), all the tennis grand slams, all the other golf majors, Olympic gold medals, America's Cup sailing, Cadel Evans even won the Tour de France,&rdquo; said Marc Leishman, who played with Scott in the final round at Augusta National Golf Club and joined the eventual winner in a "C'mon Aussie!&rdquo; fist pump after he holed a dramatic birdie putt on the 72nd hole. "We'd won everything but hadn't won the Masters. It was obviously a huge moment to get that monkey off Australia's back and get the green jacket.&rdquo;</p><p>Seeing it take place on television 15 time zones away last April was one thing, but seeing the green jacket up close was something to be savored.</p><p>Making his first homecoming trip, Scott promised his native land what the local media are calling a four-week "green jacket roadshow.&rdquo; Starting with this week's Australian PGA in his boyhood home of Queensland, through the Aussie Masters and World Cup in consecutive weeks at Royal Melbourne and capped at the Australian Open at Royal Sydney, Scott will sweep through his country's three largest states in a monthlong celebration.</p><p>"I'm really going to enjoy it,&rdquo; Scott told Australian golf commentator Luke Elvy upon his arrival home last Friday. "It's the first time that I don't have to prove myself. &hellip; I don't feel like I'm coming back for a parade. My focus is to win each event.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott's mates and colleagues enjoyed the first look at the iconic blazer. He put it on before walking into his Adam Scott Co. offices in Sanctuary Cove the day after his arrival. Friends and family saw it at his home.</p><p>"I don't get sick of it, and I've seen it a lot,&rdquo; said Phil Scott, his father.</p><p>The real show started Tuesday night, when he wore it to a pair of corporate events. Scott was presented the keys to the city today by Gold Coast Mayor Tom Tate in a ceremony immediately after his pro-am round.</p><p>"I love the reaction people get when they see it,&rdquo; Scott said before the week started. "I might just put it on after the rounds and sign away. &hellip; I want to make sure I get to share it with as many people as possible.&rdquo;</p><p>That's a far cry from last year's winner, Bubba Watson, who aside from a post-Masters media blitz and a brief pre-Masters photo shoot always kept the jacket closeted.</p><p>"None of my friends have seen it,&rdquo; Watson said in March. "I don't let anybody see it or take pictures of it out of respect for the tournament and &hellip; for the members of Augusta National.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott, however, has relished his time that only the reigning Masters champion gets with the coat.</p><p>"He is so proud of wearing that jacket. He's very happy to put it on,&rdquo; his father said. "I think he's very, very happy to be home and putting that jacket on and showing people. You only get it by winning that tournament. You can't buy one. Why wouldn't you be proud of it and sharing it out there  He's extremely comfortable in it.&rdquo;</p><p>The master of ceremonies for Tuesday's dinner, Mark Howard, was a little awestruck when Scott sat down in the coat.</p><p>"It's real,&rdquo; Scott told him, offering a sleeve to touch.</p><p>Scott discussed some of the preferred rules of "jacket etiquette,&rdquo; such as not taking it to the local dry cleaners or a night "out on the turps&rdquo; &ndash; Australian slang for drinking alcohol.</p><p>"Nothing stopping me from wearing it around the house at all points of the day and certainly to functions like this,&rdquo; Scott said.</p><p>The jacket display was a treat that drew generous applause.</p><p>"Truth is there hasn't been one down here before. We've not seen it,&rdquo; his father said. "We've seen the claret jug. We've seen the U.S. Open trophy. We've seen the &ndash; what is it  &ndash; Wanamaker Trophy. We haven't seen the jacket. So now we have. I think it's a great thing for Aussie golfers to see it and feel it.&rdquo;</p><p>Leishman agrees: "Just seeing it will give people a bit of a tingle. I've seen it a couple times now. He took it to a dinner one night at the Presidents Cup. To have something with that much history behind it, it's pretty cool that he can do that.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott is reluctant to return it to Augusta National when he goes back in April.</p><p>"The goal is to win it again and I'll get to parade around for another year,&rdquo; he said.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2013 06:07:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2539 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Dustin Johnson cruises to victory in WGC event in China</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/dustin-johnson-cruises-victory-wgc-event-china</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>SHANGHAI - It only took four holes over two days for Dustin Johnson to lose a six-shot lead in the HSBC Champions. All that mattered was the high-powered kick down the stretch Sunday at Sheshan International that brought him the biggest win of his career.</p><p>In what felt like the end of a long year and beginning of a new season, Johnson broke loose from a three-way battle on the back nine by playing a five-hole stretch in 5-under par. He closed with a 6-under 66 for a three-shot win over Ian Poulter to capture his first World Golf Championship title.</p><p>"It's the biggest win I've had in my career so far," he said. "Those guys put a lot of pressure on me. I'm really proud of the way I handled myself."</p><p>This one required a little bit of everything.</p><p>One shot behind with six holes to play, he smashed his drive over the corner of a dogleg on the 13th hole that left him a short wedge into 5 feet for birdie to catch Poulter. Right when it looked as though he would fall behind again, Johnson holed a 20-foot birdie putt on the next hole.</p><p>It was a pitch-in for eagle that effectively won the tournament.</p><p>With a one-shot lead playing the par-4 16th, Johnson hit a 3-iron about 25 yards short of the green with a front pin. The pitch was perfect, rolling into the cup like it was a putt. Johnson raised his left hand and pumped his right fist. And when he waved to acknowledge the Chinese fans, they instinctively waved back, as if Johnson were the star attraction in a parade.</p><p>That he was, and there were plenty of stars.</p><p>For most of the back nine, the top seven players on the leaderboards consisted of Johnson and half of Europe's winning Ryder Cup team from Medinah.</p><p>Poulter and Graeme McDowell, who each had a share of the lead at some point, looked capable of winning until Johnson's late heroics. Right behind them were Sergio Garcia, Justin Rose, Rory McIlroy and Martin Kaymer, all firing away with birdies on a soft course but unable to catch up.</p><p>Poulter and McDowell each closed with a 66, the same score as Johnson.</p><p>McDowell went 64-64 on the weekend without making a bogey and still lost by four. It was the start of that amazing stretch by Johnson that he recalled most clearly.</p><p>"He trenches one 350 down the middle and has the hands to that 70-yard shot to the front pin and make the putt," McDowell said. "He's just a quality, talented, very athletic, classy player. Yeah, he makes mistakes. But when you've got a game as good as him, you can get away with a few mistakes. He's just got a great wedge game to go with just an outrageously good driving game."</p><p>Johnson set the tournament record at 24-under 264.</p><p>He was six shots clear Saturday afternoon when he hit his tee shot in the water for a double bogey on the par-5 18th hole. Poulter had made birdie on the 18th, so the lead was cut to three shots going into the final round. Poulter started birdie-birdie. McDowell did one better, opening with three straight birdies. Johnson three-putted the first hole for bogey, and then failed to make birdie on the par-5 second hole even though he had a 6-iron for his second shot.</p><p>Just like that, there was a three-way tie for the lead.</p><p>"The first five holes were not fun," Johnson said. "I wasn't having too much fun at the start, especially when Graeme and Ian were birdieing every hole, it seemed like. But I knew I just needed to keep playing my game."</p><p>Poulter, still tied for the lead, reached the green in two with a fairway metal. Johnson missed the fairway and had to lay up, while McDowell was stuck in the thick collar on the top side of a bunker, and he did well to hit a chunk-and-run onto the green about 40 feet away. Poulter lagged to tap-in range for birdie. McDowell's long birdie putt banged into the back of the cup and disappeared. Johnson calmly made his 20-foot birdie.</p><p>"That was a big putt there," Johnson said.</p><p>Poulter fell out of the lead with a bogey from the bunker on the 15th, and he never caught up. He at least stayed within two shots with a birdie on the 16th, but it was demoralizing to see Johnson follow his eagle with a 5-iron into 8 feet for birdie on the 17th that wrapped it up.</p><p>"A little disappointed not to put my hands back on the trophy," said Poulter, who won the HSBC Champions last year at Mission Hills. "But 15 birdies and an eagle at the weekend is some pretty good golf. Dustin finished the job. It was good golf and it was good fun to play in that group."</p><p>Garcia closed with a 63 to finish fourth, followed by Rose (68). McIlroy and Graham DeLaet each shot 69 to tie for sixth.</p><p>It was the second consecutive PGA Tour season that Johnson won the first tournament he played - even though it was in the same year. His last win was the Tournament of Championship at Kapalua in January. This is the first time the tour has gone to a wraparound season, which began a month ago.</p><p>Johnson now has won in each of his first seven seasons on the PGA Tour, the most by any player since Woods in his first 14 seasons through 2009. The next step is to win a major, and he already has had plenty of chances in those.</p><p>"You know what " Johnson said. "If I play like I did this week, I'm going to win one, for sure." </p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2013 00:51:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2538 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Lee wins Asia-Pacific Amateur to earn Masters invite</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/lee-wins-asia-pacific-amateur-earn-masters-invite</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> LONGKOU CITY, China &mdash; Chang-woo Lee of South Korea won the Asia-Pacific Amateur by three shots Sunday to earn a trip to the Masters Tournament in April.</p><p> Lee was worried that he would think more about going to Augusta National Golf Club than his golf at Nanshan International. That was never a problem. He stretched his lead to as many as six shots on the back nine. Even with a double bogey on the last hole, he finished with 1-under 70 to win by three over Shohei Hasegawa of Japan.</p><p> The winner of the Asia-Pacific gets an invitation to the Masters and is exempt until the final qualifying stage for the British Open. Hasegawa also gets into final qualifying for the British Open.</p><p> Defending champion Tianlang Guan shot 73 and finished eight shots behind.</p><p> Lee tied for second along with Rory McIlroy last week in the Korea Open, and he kept his form all week in tough conditions at Nanshan. He finished at 3-under 281, the only player to break par. Hasegawa birdied two of the last three holes for 71.</p><p> "Playing in the Masters has been my dream since I started playing golf,&rdquo; said Lee, who won the Dongbu Promi Open on the Korean tour last month. "I didn't think I would have an opportunity, so this is a great honor, as is playing in International Final Qualifying for the (British) Open Championship. I have never been so excited.&rdquo;</p><p> Lee made bogey on the second hole to briefly fall into a tie for the lead with 16-year-old Zecheng Dou of China. Dou bogeyed the next two holes, however, and Lee began to pull away. He went 10 consecutive holes without a bogey as his lead expanded, closing with a double bogey that only affected the final margin.</p><p> "I have been looking at the leaderboard since the third round and I was a bit nervous,&rdquo; Lee said. "I just tried to keep calm and it seemed to work. I knew I was going to win after the tee shot on the 17th hole. Everything worked well during the last two rounds.</p><p> "I can't believe I am going to go to the Masters,&rdquo; he said. "I think I will only realize it tomorrow.&rdquo;</p><p> Hasegawa made a 15-foot birdie putt on the final hole to win the silver medal as the runner-up.</p><p> "My putting let me down over the weekend, and I hope to return next year to get the trophy,&rdquo; Hasegawa said. "But I'm very glad to have a chance to qualify for the (British) Open. I think this is a great chance for my golfing career.&rdquo;</p><p> Since the Asia-Pacific Amateur began in 2009, all but one winner has made the cut at the Masters &mdash; Hideki Matsuyama twice and Guan last year. Guan was 14 in April, making him the youngest player to make the cut in any major held over 72 holes.</p><p> Starting the final round five shots back, Guan failed to make a birdie Sunday.</p><p> Oliver Goss, already in the Masters as the runner-up at the U.S. Amateur, was making a move with a 34 on the front nine until taking a triple bogey on the 10th hole and a bogey on the 11th. His 72 left him seven shots behind.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2013 16:07:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2537 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Webb Simpson runs away with Shriners title</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/webb-simpson-runs-away-shriners-title</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>LAS VEGAS -Webb Simpson cruised to victory Sunday at TPC Summerlin, pulling away for a six-stroke win in the second event of the PGA Tour's new wraparound season.</p><p>Winning for the first time since the 2012 U.S. Open, Simpson closed with 5-under 66 in the Shriners Hospitals for Children Open. </p><p>He finished at 24-under 260 after opening with rounds of 64, 63 and 67 to take a four-stroke lead into the final round.</p><p>"As we were going kind of middle of the round, pins were tough, greens were drying out and I knew it would take a really special round for somebody to shoot 7, 8 under," Simpson said.</p><p>"So, I felt like I was in control, and I asked my caddie, once I hit it on the green on 17 where we stood. And I was just thankful that I was able to kind of manage my golf ball the last couple rounds."</p><p>Simpson earned $1.08 million for his fourth PGA Tour title. </p><p>In addition to the U.S. Open last year at The Olympic Club, he captured the Wyndham Championship and Deutsche Bank Championship in 2011.</p><p>Ryo Ishikawa and Jason Bohn tied for second. Ishikawa, the Japanese player who had to play the Web.com Tour Finals to regain his PGA Tour card, shot 65. Bohn had 66.</p><p>Charley Hoffman finished fourth at 17 under after shooting 64.</p><p>"When you get that far up the leaderboard every putt you make is worth big dollars and big FedEx Cup points," Hoffman said. "So, to get the year started off on the right foot, you always want to make those putts."</p><p>Chesson Hadley, second entering the final round, had 70 to drop into a tie for fifth at 16 under with Luke Guthrie, Troy Matteson and Augusta native Charles Howell. Guthrie and Matteson shot 64, and Howell closed with 65.</p><p>Matteson had seven consecutive birdies - on Nos. 9-15 - to fall one short of the tournament record set by Jerry Kelly in 2003.</p><p>"It was a really good ball-striking round," Matteson said. "As a matter of fact, when I got to 16, I thought I was going to get that eighth one and I ended up hitting the pin and almost going into the lake, so I would have had a tap-in there. But you know what, all in all it's a great end to my week. I didn't quite figure it out in the middle (of the tournament), but I certainly put it together today."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2013 01:54:04 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2536 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jimmy Walker earns first win, Masters invite </title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/jimmy-walker-earns-first-win-masters-invite</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>SAN MARTIN, Calif. - Jimmy Walker's first PGA Tour trophy came with a special gift tucked inside.</p><p>A yellow "Masters 2014" flag.</p><p>It was a not-so-subtle reminder that the Frys.com Open is no longer a Fall Series event for players to chase their Tour cards at the end of the year, but the start of the PGA Tour's new 2013-14 season that comes with all the perks.</p><p>And it was a reminder to Walker that he gets to go places where he always felt he belonged.</p><p>In his eighth season and his 188th tournament - and with a little help from 23-year-old Brooks Koepka - Walker won a back-nine duel Sunday by making a 6-foot birdie putt on the 15th hole and closing with three pars for 5-under 66. That was more than enough for the 34-year-old Texan to win by two shots.</p><p>"This was the final stepping stone," said Walker, who has played on more tours than he can remember to get to the big leagues.</p><p>It turned out to be a learning experience for Koepka, who had a four-shot lead with 11 holes remaining until he began missing short putts, all of them to the left. It started with a 3-foot par putt that he missed on the ninth hole. The most significant was a 6-foot birdie attempt on the 15th hole that would have matched birdies with Walker in the group ahead and regained a share of the lead.</p><p>Koepka bogeyed the next two holes and closed with 72 to tie for third.</p><p>"Things just weren't going my way," Koepka said. "I just didn't make the shots I needed to win. Congrats to Jimmy on that. He played very well. But just try to learn from the whole experience. Any time you can put yourself in that kind of pressure, it's always good. It you take something from it, that's even better."</p><p>Walker finished at 17-under 267 and cracked the top 50 in the world ranking for the first time.</p><p>Vijay Singh closed with 68 and wound up with the 27th runner-up finish of his Hall of Fame career, and his best result since he sued the PGA Tour in May over its procedure in investigating Singh's admission that he used deer antler spray.</p><p>Koepka tied for third with Kevin Na (64), North Augusta native Scott Brown (64) and Hideki Matsuyama. Matsuyama, who played in the Presidents Cup last week, birdied his last three holes for 66.</p><p>Along with the Masters Tournament, Walker also gets to go to Maui in January for the Tournament of Champions, another place he has never been, and he is assured a spot in the PGA Championship for only the fourth time in his career.</p><p>"I felt like I was good enough to be in them, play in them," Walker said. "There's always this big pressure to get into Augusta, and I would press here, press there. You want to be playing in the big stuff. That's what I'm aspiring to do - play against the world's best."</p><p>It won't be his first trip to Augusta National.</p><p>Club member Paul Sarvadi invited Walker and his father about five years ago, one of Walker's favorite memories even in the chill of winter and a light rain. His father, a scratch golfer who once shot 60, birdied three of the par 5s. Walker shot 72 one day, and played the back nine in 35.</p><p>"A cool experience," he called it.</p><p>Koepka was playing on a sponsor's exemption that he received without asking. Tournament officials identified him as a potential star when he started the year with no status on any tour, and then won three times on the Challenge Tour to earn his European Tour card. He qualified for the British Open the day after his third Challenge Tour win.</p><p>He was between stops in Scotland and Shanghai, and now his plans are slightly altered. Koepka's finish gets him into Las Vegas next week before he goes back to the European Tour for the BMW Masters in China.</p><p>Billy Hurley III closed with a 68 and NCAA champion Max Homa from Cal birdied two of the last three holes to tie for ninth. That gets them in Las Vegas.</p><p>Koepka won all of his Challenge Tour events in Europe with the 54-hole lead, experience he figured could only help. For eight holes, he was on the verge of running away from the field. He rammed in a 45-foot birdie putt on the sixth hole to reach 17 under, and when Singh in group ahead three-putted the seventh for bogey from about the same range, Koepka had a four-shot lead.</p><p>It was gone in four holes.</p><p>Koepka had about a 15-foot birdie putt from the collar of the par-5 ninth green that went about 3 feet by the hole. But the stroke on his par putt looked a little quick, and it caught the left lip and spun out for a bogey. On the par-3 11th, he pulled a 6-foot par putt. That dropped him into a tie for the lead with Walker, who was in the group ahead and had made a 15-foot birdie on the eighth and a two-putt birdie from long range on the ninth.</p><p>Asked if there was a putt that unsettled him, Koepka said, "Maybe the putt on 9. That wasn't very good."</p><p>They traded birdies - Koepka with a 3-footer on the par-5 12th, Walker with a 30-foot putt from the fringe on the 13th, setting the stage for the decisive stretch at CordeValle - the par-5 15th that could be reached in two, the par-4 17th that played 297 yards over the water.</p><p>And that's where it was decided.</p><p>"I can't get too down on this week," Koepka said. "I know I'll be criticized. But this year has been amazing. This week I played well. It happens to the best of them."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2013 03:57:38 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2535 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Henrik Stenson wins Tour Championship and FedEx Cup </title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/henrik-stenson-wins-tour-championship-and-fedex-cup</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/12649512.jpg" /></div><p> <p>ATLANTA - Henrik Stenson capped off the best stretch of his career Sunday with the biggest payoff in golf.</p><p> <p>Stenson held off a brief challenge by 20-year-old Jordan Spieth and closed with a 2-under 68 to win the Tour Championship by three shots over Spieth and Steve Stricker. The 37-year-old Swede also captured the FedEx Cup and its $10 million bonus. Stenson earned $1.44 million for winning the tournament.</p><p> <p>Stenson, who two years ago was outside the top 200, moved to No. 4 in the world.</p><p> <p>Spieth left one lasting impression on his remarkable rookie season. The youngest player in Tour Championship history ran off four straight birdies on the back nine at East Lake and pulled within one shot of Stenson with his 10-footer on the 16th.</p><p> <p>Spieth caught a buried lie in the bunker short of the 17th green and made bogey, while Stenson steadied himself with an 8-foot birdie on the par-5 15th to return his lead to three shots. Stenson only made it easy at the end with three pars - nearly holing out from the bunker right of the 16th green, hitting a scary shot from the right fairway bunker on the 17th to the middle of the green, and saving par from another bunker on the 18th.</p><p> <p>Spieth closed with a 64, while Stricker had a 65.</p><p> <p>Stenson, who finished at 13-under 267, became the first European to win the Tour Championship and the FedEx Cup.</p><p> <p>His amazing summer began with a tie for third in the Scottish Open. Stenson followed with a runner-up at the British Open and the World Golf Championship at Firestone, third place at the PGA Championship and a win at the Deutsche Bank Championship.</p><p> <p>The Tour Championship was his second win in three tournaments of the FedEx Cup playoffs.</p><p> <p>"Since the Scottish Open, it's been just an incredible run," he said. "I'm speechless. It was a tough day out there. To hang in there the way I did, I'm really satisfied. ... It hasn't quite sunk in yet. I had to fight hard mentally to keep all this aside, and I managed to do that. It's going to feel better as the week goes on. I'm pretty sure about that."</p><p> <p>Tiger Woods, the No. 1 seed going into the Tour Championship, never recovered from his 73-71 start. He closed with a 67 to tie for 22nd, his worst finish ever at East Lake, and wound up second in the FedEx Cup. That still was worth a $3 million bonus.</p><p> <p>Woods wrapped up the PGA of America's points-based award for player of the year, and he captured the PGA Tour money title and the Vardon Trophy for the lowest adjusted scoring title. Next up is a vote of the players for PGA Tour player of the year. He is the heavy favorite with five wins this year.</p><p> <p>The award is to be announced on Friday.</p><p> <p>Stricker had birdie chances on the last two holes, unaware that making one of them would have been worth an extra $1 million. He only cared about winning the tournament, knowing he needed birdies and for Stenson to make a mistake.</p><p> <p>"I knew the putt meant a lot. I didn't know it meant that much," he said with a smile.</p><p> <p>Instead of finishing second in the FedEx Cup, Stricker had to settle for third and the $2 million bonus.</p><p> <p>Spieth had a 55-foot birdie putt across the 18th green that stopped inches away. His season was simply remarkable. The young Texan started the year with no status on any tour, and wound up with a win, more than $3.8 million in earnings and a trip to the Presidents Cup in two weeks.</p><p> <p>"Henrik obviously was playing phenomenal golf," Spieth said. "I felt like once a few putts started falling, we have a shot at it."</p><p> <p>Stenson became the fifth player to win his debut at the Tour Championship, a list that starts with Tom Watson when the elite 30-man field began in 1987. He also became the first player to go wire-to-wire without ties since Watson.</p><p> <p>For much of the day, no one got closer to Stenson than three shots, and he answered that early challenge with an 8-iron to an elevated green at No. 7 to 2 feet for birdie. The Tour Championship came to life in the final hour, though, thanks to the youngest player in the field.</p><p> <p>Fearless as ever, Spieth began a run of birdies starting on the 13th hole that not only moved him into second place, it put pressure on Stenson not to drop any shots. Stenson's only bogey came on the 14th, when he caught a flyer over the green and missed a 20-foot putt.</p><p> <p>Spieth was between clubs on the 17th, however, tried to hammer a 9-iron and caught just enough heavy that it plugged in the bunker.</p><p> <p>The next challenge came from Stricker, who rolled in an eagle putt on the 15th to get within two shots. He never got any closer.</p><p> <p>Webb Simpson had the low round of the tournament with a 63 to finish fourth.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2013 22:34:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2534 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Masters Tournament champion Adam Scott doesn't leave home without his green jacket</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/masters-tournament-champion-adam-scott-doesnt-leave-home-without-his-</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>Masters Tournament champion Adam Scott talked earlier this year about the joy of waking up in his home in The Bahamas and having a green jacket in his closet.</p><p>It doesn't stay there.</p><p>Scott says he packs golf's most famous jacket for just about every trip, including the Tour Championship, whichstarts today in Atlanta.</p><p>"It's here with me," Scott said with a smile. "It comes pretty much everywhere. I wear it in my hotel room all the time just by myself."</p><p>He was kidding about the last part - maybe.</p><p>Scott said sometimes he packs the green jacket in his luggage, "but I don't mind carrying it around."</p><p>Scott also said that on his way to Chicago for last week's BMW Championship, he played a casual round at Shinnecock Hills and wound up setting the course record with 63. </p><p>Scott played the red tees, which are the tips on the Long Island course. He made a 12-foot putt on the last hole to beat by one the record set by Raymond Floyd during a recreational round in 1996.</p><p>"It's pretty cool," Scott said. "The members got pretty excited when I came off the course, and it's one of the best tracks in the world, for sure. No one has ever shot that score in over 100 years off the tees I played. So that's a pretty neat thing."</p><p>Scott had rounds of 75-75 to miss the cut when the U.S. Open was held AT Shinnecock in 2004. It returns there in 2018.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 01:38:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2533 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott opens FedEx Cup playoffs with win</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/scott-opens-fedex-cup-playoffs-win</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>JERSEY CITY, N.J. - Masters champion Adam Scott won The Barclays on Sunday after everyone around him did their best to lose it.</p><p> <p>Scott played bogey-free and closed with a 5-under 66. He finished an hour before the final group, and watched from the locker room at Liberty National.</p><p> <p>Kevin Chappell had a two-shot lead through 10 holes and went 7 over the rest of the way. Justin Rose three-putted the 18th. Tiger Woods dropped to his knees after a back spasm on the 13th hole when he hooked his approach into the water, leading to a bogey. Woods birdied the 16th and 17th to get within one, and his 25-foot birdie off the 18th green stopped just short.</p><p> <p>Gary Woodland had three straight birdie attempts inside 10 feet and missed them all.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2013 22:17:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2531 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Augusta State star Reed beats Spieth in playoff at Wyndham</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/augusta-state-star-reed-beats-spieth-playoff-wyndham</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>GREENSBORO, N.C. - In the span of a couple of strokes, Patrick Reed went from almost certain disaster to his first PGA Tour victory.</p><p> <p>Reed won the Wyndham Championship on Sunday for his first title, beating Jordan Spieth with a most improbable birdie on the second hole of a playoff.</p><p> <p>Reed recovered from a drive on the par-4 10th that came a few feet from going out of bounds and stopped in some pine needles in the woods near a television cable.</p><p> <p>Reed pulled out his 7-iron, uncorked a baseball swing from an uphill lie and sent the ball under a tree branch - yet away from the tree trunk - to land his second shot 7 feet from the pin.</p><p> <p>"It was the best shot of my life, that's for sure," Reed said.</p><p> <p>Spieth, who called it "one of the best shots I've ever witnessed," had reached the green in two strokes, but his 10-foot birdie putt trickled wide of the cup.</p><p> <p>Reed then sank his short birdie putt that "felt like it was 40" feet to end it.</p><p> <p>"Just to get my first win means everything to me," Reed said.</p><p> <p>Reed, who had his third straight top-10 finish, earned $954,000 in prize money and 500 FedEx Cup points for winning the final tournament before the playoffs.</p><p> <p>Reed and Spieth finished regulation at 14-under 266. Reed closed with a 4-under 66, and Spieth had a 65.</p><p> <p>The 20-year-old Spieth, the John Deere winner in a playoff last month, was denied in his bid to become youngest two-time champion in the modern era of the PGA Tour.</p><p> <p>John Huh and Brian Harman were two strokes behind. Harman had a 66, and Huh shot 68. Matt Jones matched the tournament record for a final round with a 62 and finished at 11 under along with Matt Every (67) and Zach Johnson (68).</p><p> <p>Reed - who let a three-stroke lead on the back nine slip away - missed a chance to win it on the first playoff hole, the par-4 18th.</p><p> <p>Spieth recovered from a terrible drive and saved par with a snaking 25-foot putt.</p><p> <p>Reed pushed his 7-foot birdie putt wide of the hole, sending it to a second extra hole.</p><p> <p>"I don't even know how I was still playing (the second playoff hole) after what happened on 18," Spieth said.</p><p> <p>Spieth and Huh both caught Reed at 14 under down the stretch in regulation.</p><p> <p>At roughly the same time Reed bogeyed the par-3 16th, Spieth birdied the par-4 17th and closed with a par. Huh quickly slipped off the pace after finishing with two bogeys.</p><p> <p>Reed, who led or shared the lead after the second and third rounds, also could have won it in regulation after landing his approach shot on the 18th in the center of the green.</p><p> <p>But he left his approximately 20-foot birdie putt short and tapped in to force the playoff.</p><p> <p>At the end of the day, the leaderboard looked much like it did at the start - tightly bunched. Eight players began the round within two strokes of the lead.</p><p> <p>Reed compared the scenario to a Monday qualifier, and he knows plenty about those: he earned his spots in six tournaments last year by playing well in those 18-hole Monday rounds.</p><p> <p>For the second straight day, organizers tried to beat the rain by starting the round early, sending players off in threesomes from the first and 10th tees. The skies were ominously overcast all day, but the saturated course didn't receive any rain.</p><p> <p>And unlike the third round - in which only 13 players broke par - scores were significantly lower on the water-logged Sedgefield course, and that turned the final 18 holes into a shootout.</p><p> <p>Jones birdied five consecutive holes and six of seven during his best round of the year.</p><p> <p>"Every golfer out here can go and shoot that," Jones said.</p><p> <p>Jones and Simpson, the 2011 winner who shot a 63, led the 52 players who shot better than even-par 70 during the final round.</p><p> <p>"You really couldn't tell that the greens got any rain," Simpson said. "They were still as fast today as I've ever seen them."</p><p> <p>At one point early in the round, five players - Reed, Every, Harman, Huh and Johnson - shared the lead at 10 under and six others were within two strokes of them.</p><p> <p>It wound up being a mostly fruitless week for the players on the playoff bubble who missed their last chance to push their way into The Barclays next week.</p><p> <p>Nobody who started the week outside the top 125 managed to make it in. Each of the players at Nos. 126-132 missed the cut, and No. 133 Robert Streb finished at 3 under but could only jump to 126th.</p><p> <p>"I was trying to put (the pressure) to the side as much as I could," Streb said. "You can't completely ignore it, but I just tried to play the best golf I could."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2013 22:30:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2530 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jason Dufner wins PGA Championship at Oak Hill</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/jason-dufner-wins-pga-championship-oak-hill</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>PITTSFORD, N.Y. - Jason Dufner has won his first major title with a two-stroke victory over Jim Furyk at the PGA Championship.</p><p> <p>Dufner bogeyed the final two holes Sunday for a 2-under 68 that was good enough to hold off the 2003 U.S. Open champion. The winning score was 10-under 270.</p><p> <p>Henrik Stenson finished three shots back.</p><p> <p>Dufner made up for the heartache of the 2011 PGA, when he went to the 15th tee with a four-stroke lead in Atlanta. He dunked that shot in the water, squandered the advantage and lost to Keegan Bradley in a playoff.</p><p> <p>There was no such collapse on another warm, sunny day at Oak Hill.</p><p> <p>From tee to green, Dufner was nearly perfect. If not for a bit of a shaky putter, the margin would've been even more.</p><p> <p>Furyk went into the final round with a one-shot lead, and it looked as if this might be his day when he rolled in a 40-footer across the sixth green for a birdie. But Dufner seized control just before the turn.</p><p> <p>With the final group tied at 10 under on the eighth hole, Furyk appeared to have a slight edge when his approach plopped down about 12 feet left of the flag. But, in quite a display of one-upmanship, Dufner's shot spun back from above the hole and came to a stop about a foot from the cup.</p><p> <p>Furyk missed his birdie try. Dufner tapped his in to edge back ahead.</p><p> <p>When Furyk made bogey at the ninth, Dufner had a two-stroke lead heading to the back side. Furyk never got any closer. They matched birdies at the 16th, where Furyk rolled in a 12-footer and Dufner tapped in again after another brilliant iron shot. They matched bogeys at the 17th, where Dufner three-putted and Furyk needed two shots to escape the thick rough ringing the green.</p><p> <p>Finally, at the 18th, Furyk's second shot found the rough again, leading to another bogey and a 71 total. Dufner also came up short with his second shot, chipped on and putted twice for the victory. He actually pumped both fists, about as much emotion as he'll ever show.</p><p> <p>Stenson closed with an even-par 70 and finished at 7 under, missing a chance to become the first Swedish male to capture a major championship. Countryman Jonas Blixt was another stroke back, also closing with a 70.</p><p> <p>The 43-year-old Furyk was trying to give golf another middle-aged champion. Three weeks ago, Phil Mickelson captured the British Open at age 43. The last time golf had back-to-back major champions in their 40s was 1986, when Jack Nicklaus won the Masters and Raymond Floyd followed with a victory in the U.S. Open.</p><p> <p>Instead, it was Dufner winning his first at age 36. Now he'll be known for something more than that memorable picture of him slumped against the wall of an elementary school during a charity appearance - arms stiffly at his side, eyes glazed over - which led to the craze known as "Dufnering."</p><p> <p>Mickelson wasn't a factor at Oak Hill. He shot 72 to finish 12 over, tied for 72nd position when he headed for home, his day done before the guys in contention for the Wanamaker Trophy even teed off.</p><p> <p>Tiger Woods was an also-ran, as well, wrapping up his fifth straight year without a major title. He did play well down the stretch, making birdies on three of the last six holes. But all that got him was a 70, leaving him at 4-over 284 for the week. He never shot in the 60s, despite much easier scoring conditions the first two days and warm, sunny weather the last two.</p><p> <p>Woods is 0 for 18 in the Grand Slam events since winning the U.S. Open in 2008, leaving him at 14 major championships in his career and still four behind the record held by Jack Nicklaus.</p><p> <p>Coming off his fifth PGA Tour victory of the year, a seven-stroke runaway at the Bridgestone, Woods never got anything going in the final major the year.</p><p> <p>Tim Clark had the shot of the day among the early starters, a hole-in-one at the 11th. He knocked it in from 220 yards with a hybrid.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 22:55:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2529 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Tiger Woods coasts to victory in Bridgestone Invitational</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/tiger-woods-coasts-victory-bridgestone-invitational</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>AKRON, Ohio - They say par is a good score in a major. If that's true next week at the PGA Championship, then Tiger Woods is already dialed in.</p><p>Woods played safe and smart with a big lead, parring 16 holes in an even-par 70 Sunday to coast to a seven-shot victory at the Bridgestone Invitational for his eighth win at the event - matching the PGA Tour record he shares for victories in a single tournament.</p><p>As he walked to the scorer's trailer to finalize his score, he scooped up young son Charlie.</p><p>After a second-round 61 in which he flirted with 59, Woods ended up at 15-under 265 to easily beat defending champ Keegan Bradley and Henrik Stenson.</p><p>Woods' mastery at Firestone Country Club allowed him to again match Sam Snead's PGA Tour record for wins in an event. Snead won the Greater Greensboro Open eight times. Earlier this year, Woods won at Bay Hill for the eighth time.</p><p>As if he weren't already the favorite next week in the PGA Championship at Oak Hill, the lopsided victory reinforced it.</p><p>No one ever got within six shots all day of the world's No. 1.</p><p>When he had a good shot at a pin, he took it. Otherwise, he took few, if any, risks.</p><p>He had birdied the short, par-4 first hole each of the first three days, and had played the second in 3 under as well. But he came up just short on the opening hole and chipped up for an easy par. At the second, he found a fairway bunker off the tee, blasted out and hit his approach to 10 feet but his birdie putt skidded off the edge. Tap-in par.</p><p>That's pretty much the way it went the first nine holes, until Woods stuffed his second shot at the par-4 10th inside 8 feet and then poured in the birdie putt to break up a string of pars.</p><p>That briefly pushed the lead to eight shots. It never fell below seven as the field had difficulty putting up many birdies as Firestone dried out, the greens got faster and the old course bared its fangs.</p><p>A three-putt at the 14th hole brought Woods' lone bogey, but by then most of the field was thinking about catching flights to Rochester instead of catching Woods.</p><p>Bradley, who won a year ago when Jim Furyk double-bogeyed the 72nd hole, shot 67 to get to 8 under along with Stenson, who had a 70 while playing with Woods.</p><p>Tied for fourth were Cleveland-born Jason Dufner (71), Miguel Angel Jimenez (69) and Zach Johnson (67) at 6 under, with Martin Kaymer, who matched the day's best round with a 66, at 4 under along with Furyk, Richard Sterne and Luke Donald.</p><p>For those betting Woods won't win next week at Oak Hill, keep in mind that he has already won both the Bridgestone and the PGA Championship in the same year three times in his career (2000, 2006, 2007).</p><p>Still, the odds do not favor him coming right back with another win. In the 19 times in which he has won his last start before a major, he's only followed up with a win four times: 2000 U.S. Open (after winning The Memorial), 2001 Masters (Players), 2006 PGA (Buick) and 2007 PGA (Bridgestone).</p><p>The victory was Woods' 79th on the PGA Tour, drawing him within three of Snead's record 82 triumphs.</p><p>Lest anyone think he'll have difficulty surpassing Snead's total, consider that Woods is over 10 years younger (he's 37½) than Snead was when he won his 82nd and final event, the 1965 Greater Greensboro.</p><p>Even though he's a California native, Woods has found a second home in Ohio where he's collected 13 victories - also including five at the Memorial Tournament.</p><p>Woods won the Bridgestone, and it's forerunner the NEC Invitational, about every way imaginable: overcoming a crazy shot that went onto the clubhouse roof, putting out in almost total darkness, running away early, outdueling a foe down the stretch.</p><p>Woods, who has five wins this year to have at least that many in a year for the 10th time, also has won 18 World Golf Championship series events in just 42 starts.</p><p>Really, he won the tournament in the rain on Friday.</p><p>The 61 he had in the second round &lt;0x2014&gt; he needed to go just 2 under over the final five holes to shoot a magical 59 &lt;0x2014&gt; matched his career best, mustered three previous times including once before at Firestone.</p><p>In the two previous times he won the Bridgestone and then played in the PGA Championship, he finished first at Southern Hills in 2007 and then placed second &lt;0x2014&gt; blowing a final-round lead to Y.E. Yang - in 2009 at Hazeltine.</p><p>He's far from a lock next week, however.</p><p>Woods has not won in his last 17 starts in a major, calling into question his shot at surpassing Jack Nicklaus' record 18 victories in majors. Woods has 14 &lt;0x2014&gt; and all eyes will be on him as he heads to Pittsford, N.Y.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2013 22:49:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2528 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Phil Mickelson surges to win first British Open</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/phil-mickelson-surges-win-first-british-open</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>GULLANE, Scotland - Phil Mickelson is mystified no more by links golf. He has his name etched in a silver claret jug to prove it.</p><p>Mickelson delivered his best closing round ever in a major Sunday - at the British Open, of all places - when he ran off four birdies over the last six holes for 5-under 66 at Muirfield to win the third leg of the career Grand Slam.</p><p>"This is such an accomplishment for me because I just never knew if I'd be able to develop the game to play links golf effectively," Mickelson said. "To play the best round arguably of my career, to putt better than I've ever putted, to shoot the round of my life "¦ it feels amazing to win the claret jug."</p><p>At the end of a rough-and-tumble week, Mickelson was the only player under par. He wound up with a three-shot win over Henrik Stenson, one of four players atop the leaderboard during a final round that was up for grabs until Mickelson seized control.</p><p>Lee Westwood, who started Sunday with a two-shot lead, fell behind for the first time all day with a bogey on the 13th and never recovered. He closed with 75. Masters Tournament champion Adam Scott took the lead with a 4-foot birdie on the 11th, and closed as sloppily as he did last year. He made four bogeys starting at the 13th, and a final birdie on the 18th gave him 72. At least he has a green jacket from the Masters to console him this year.</p><p>Mickelson had only contended twice in two decades at golf's oldest championship. One week after he won the Scottish Open in a playoff on the links-styled course of Castle Stuart, he was simply magical on the back nine.</p><p>Tied for the lead, Mickelson smashed a 3-wood onto the green at the par-5 17th to about 25 feet for a two-putt birdie, and finished in style with a 10-foot birdie putt on the 18th to match the lowest score of this championship.</p><p>Mickelson figured a par on the 18th would be tough for anyone to catch him. When the ball dropped in the center of the cup, he raised both arms in the air to celebrate his fifth career major, tying him with the likes of Seve Ballesteros and Byron Nelson.</p><p>"Best round I've ever seen him play," said his caddie, Jim "Bones" Mackay.</p><p>His final surge was right about the time Westwood and Scott began to fold.</p><p>Scott, trying to join an exclusive list of players who have won a green jacket and a claret jug in the same year, made a remarkable recovery from the dunes right of the par-3 13th hole, only to miss the 7-foot par putt. He took three putts for bogeys on the next two holes - from long range on the 14th, and from 20 feet on the 15th - and found a bunker on the next.</p><p>Westwood started to lose his grip on the jug with bogeys on the seventh and eighth, and failing to birdie the downwind, par-5 ninth. Presented with birdie chances early on the back nine, his putting stroke began to look tentative. He hit into the dunes on the right side of the 13th to make bogey and never caught up.</p><p>Westwood and Scott tied for third with Ian Poulter, who played a four-hole stretch in 5-under around the turn and closed with 67. At 1-over 285, he canceled a flight home in case of a playoff. Moments later, with Mickelson pulling away, the outcome was clear.</p><p>Making this even sweeter for Mickelson is that just one month ago he lost out on yet another chance to win the U.S. Open, the missing link of a career Grand Slam. Mickelson twice made bogey with wedge in his hand on the back nine at Merion and had his record sixth runner-up finish.</p><p>Mickelson joins an elite list of winners at Muirfield, which is considered the fairest of the links on the British Open rotation. All but two of the Open champions at Muirfield are in the World Hall of Fame. Mickelson is the only winner who already has been inducted.</p><p>It was the 43rd win of his PGA Tour career. The guy who once couldn't win the big one now has five majors in the past nine years. This one returns him to No. 2 in the world ranking for the first time in nearly three years.</p><p>Woods, meanwhile, now has gone 17 majors without winning, and that pursuit of Jack Nicklaus and his benchmark of 18 majors - Woods is stuck on 14 - doesn't look any closer. He three-putted twice in four holes and looked like just another contender Sunday.</p><p>He attributed his round to not getting the right pace on the greens, which he said were progressively slower.</p><p>"I felt like I was really playing well today, actually the whole week, " said Woods, who has not broken 70 in the final round of his past seven majors. "I really hit so many good shots and really had control of my ball this week. As I said, it was just trying to get the speed, and I just didn't get it."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2013 04:47:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2526 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Justin Rose wins U.S. Open</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/justin-rose-wins-us-open</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/12345020.jpg" /></div><p> <p>ARDMORE, Pa. - Justin Rose is the first Englishman to win the U.S. Open in 43 years.</p><p>Rose shot a closing 70 Sunday at Merion Golf Club for a 1-over 281 total and his first major championship. He finished two shots ahead of Phil Mickelson and Jason Day.</p><p>The 32-year-old Rose overcame his share of misadventures on a challenging course. He took the solo lead for good when Mickelson and Mahan both dropped shots at No. 15.</p><p>He finished with a tap-in for par at the 18th, a hole that didn't yield a birdie over the final two rounds.</p><p>It's been a long wait for England since Tony Jacklin won the trophy in 1970. Rose has been in contention before. He tied for fifth in 2003 and tied for 10th in 2007.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2013 23:54:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2514 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bobby Jones completed his Grand Slam at Merion Golf Club</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/bobby-jones-completed-his-grand-slam-merion-golf-club</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/12337222.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>ARDMORE, Pa. &mdash; It's only 693 miles from Merion Golf Club to Augusta National Golf Club, but for Bobby Jones the distance seemed much greater.</p><p>Merion, site of this week's U.S. Open, was the end of a long journey for Jones when he clinched the Grand Slam here in 1930.</p><p>Much attention has been paid this week to Ben Hogan's legendary 1-iron shot in the final round of the 1950 U.S. Open at Merion.</p><p>A distant second is the 1971 playoff between Lee Trevino and Jack Nicklaus, where the Merry Mex playfully tossed a rubber snake at the Golden Bear.</p><p>But the 11th hole, where Jones closed out Eugene Homans 8 and 7 to win the 1930 U.S. Amateur  Not so much.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>MORE ATTENTION has been paid to the Baffling Brook, which meanders down the 11th fairway and runs next to the green, as heavy rain pelted the course Thursday for the second time this week. Flooding of the 11th green has been a concern, and the U.S. Golf Association even came up with a "doomsday scenario&rdquo; should the green become unplayable.</p><p>At 367 yards, the 11th hole isn't even the shortest par-4 at Merion. Four other par-4s on the East Course play shorter than the hole.</p><p>Players face a blind tee shot to a downhill fairway, and most will use an iron or hybrid. The hole's main defense is Baffling Brook, which slants across the hole from the left and winds around the front and right side of the green.</p><p>The only reminder of Jones' feat is a plaque that is affixed to a stone next to the tee. It reads:</p><p>"On September 27, 1930 and on this hole ROBERT TYRE JONES JR. completed his &lsquo;Grand Slam' by winning the U.S. Amateur Championship.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>LEGEND HAS IT that the plaque had to be changed because originally the name was Robert Trent Jones, the golf course architect.</p><p>Jones, the legendary amateur and not the designer, was only 28 when he retired from competitive golf. But he had spent half his life on the national stage, and was weary of the burden of carrying lofty expectations every time he teed it up.</p><p>Merion played multiple major roles in Jones' career. It was in 1916 that Jones made his national debut, at the U.S. Amateur, as a 14-year-old. It was at Merion in 1924 that Jones won the first of his five U.S. Amateur titles.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>THE BIGGEST EVENT for Jones and Merion, though, came in the fall of 1930. Playing a limited schedule, he had already won the British Amateur, British Open and U.S. Open in succession. He only needed a victory at Merion to complete the unprecedented sweep of golf's four major titles at the time.</p><p>With a two-month gap between his U.S. Open win and the U.S. Amateur, Jones was under enormous pressure. His adoring public turned out in record numbers, but they didn't know what Jones and only a few others did: This would be his last hurrah.</p><p>Jones won medalist honors in qualifying with rounds of 69 and 73. He won his first three matches by convincing margins, then he knocked off Jess Sweetser, 9 and 8, in the semifinals.</p><p>Jones met Homans in the final, which was contested over 36 holes. Jones built a commanding lead and closed out Homans on the 11th hole of the second 18 for an 8 and 7 victory.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>THE GRAND SLAM &ndash; also labeled the Impregnable Quadrilateral &ndash; was finally complete.</p><p>According to the USGA, Jones told friend and fellow competitor Jimmy Johnston in the locker room that day he was through competing.</p><p>"The strain of golf is wrecking my health, stunting me in my business ambitions, and I'm dead tired of it,&rdquo; Jones said to Johnston.</p><p>During the trophy presentation, Jones was less emphatic about his plans.</p><p>"I expect to continue to play golf, but just when and where I cannot say now,&rdquo; Jones said. "I have no definite plans either to retire or as to when and where I may continue in competitions. I might stay out of the battle next season and feel like another tournament the following year. That's all I can say about it now.&rdquo;</p><p>Two months later, Jones announced his retirement and then he set out to build his dream course. His desire was to spend time with friends, and Augusta turned out to be the perfect location for his private club, Augusta National, and the invitation-only event, the Masters Tournament, that would soon follow.</p><p>Jones' journey was finally complete.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2013 00:57:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2513 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ex-Bulldog Harris English wins St. Jude Classic</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/ex-bulldog-harris-english-wins-st-jude-classic</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> <p>MEMPHIS, Tenn. - Harris English won the St. Jude Classic on Sunday for his first PGA Tour title, birdieing two of the final three holes to hold off Phil Mickelson and Scott Stallings by two strokes.</p><p>The 23-year-old former Georgia star in his second year on tour survived a final round where he had six birdies and five bogeys to shoot 1-under 69. He finished at 12-under 268.</p><p>English made a 5-foot birdie putt on No. 16 to tie Stallings for the lead, but Stallings bogeyed No. 18 to give English the lead to himself. English made a 17-foot birdie putt on No. 17, and two-putted No. 18 to pick up the winner's check of $1,026,000.</p><p>Mickelson shot 67, and Stallings had 68.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 22:21:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2511 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>