<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.augusta.com/mrss/feed/21" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
<title></title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/feeds/22.xml</link>
<description></description>
<language>en</language>
<item>
<title>Clifford Roberts was a master of innovations</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/clifford-roberts-was-master-innovations</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/Clifford_Roberts.jpg" /></div><p>Clifford Roberts, the co-founder of Augusta National and the longest-serving chairman of the Masters, was born on March 6, 1894.</p><p>Known for his gruff exterior and no-nonsense approach to tournament administration, Roberts set the bar high. Through numerous innovations implemented under Roberts, the Masters is considered the premier sporting event in the world.</p><p>He also enjoyed a close relationship with Dwight D. Eisenhower, and helped the general in his successful bid for president. Eisenhower also became an Augusta National member.</p><p>Roberts served as chairman from 1931 to 1976, and after his death in September 1977 he was named chairman in memoriam.&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 15:01:14 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2593 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>2014 Masters badge features par-3 12th hole</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/2014-masters-badge-features-par-3-12th-hole</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/badge.JPG" /></div><p>The 2014 Masters Tournament badge features an image of the par-3 12th hole.</p><p>One of the most famous par-3 holes in golf, the 12th at Augusta National Golf Club is nicknamed Golden Bell for the abundance of that plant on the hill behind the green.</p><p>The photo shows Rae's Creek, which protects the small green, and the reflection of the foliage on the water.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 14:57:43 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2587 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>How big of a Masters fan are you?</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/how-big-masters-fan-are-you</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/Masters.JPG" /></div><p>Do you collect badges, autographs or other tournament paraphernalia  Or do you display flags, photos and other Masters items in your home  Send us a photo and your Masters memorabilia could be featured in The Augusta Chronicle.</p><p>Send us the info at this link.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 14:54:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2582 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>McIlroy playing well as Masters approaches</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/mcilroy-playing-well-masters-approaches</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/McIlroy%202011.jpg" /></div><p>Rory McIlroy generated plenty of buzz Thursday with his opening-round 63 at the Honda Classic.</p><p>And if he goes on to win, he'll come into the Masters next month as a popular pick.</p><p>The two-time major champion has had a mixed bag in five Masters appearances. He looked like a winner in 2011, but a final-round 80 pushed him all the way down to a tie for 15th.</p><p>Last year, McIlroy tied for 25th as he struggled with changes in his equipment.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2014 14:45:32 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2581 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Champions Dinner will include Mum's dessert, 'bugs'</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/champions-dinner-will-include-mums-dessert-bugs</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/MAS40_Champions_Dinner_RLC.jpg" /></div><p>Adam Scott says he has finalized his Australian-themed menu for the Champions Dinner, but the reigning Masters Tournament champion wasn't ready to reveal all of it just yet.But he did offer a couple of clues."My mom's dessert's on there," Scott said after practicing his putting on Tuesday at PGA National, where he's preparing to return from a six-week break to play in the Honda Classic. "Mum's Pavlova is on there. It's kind of a meringue."A Pavlova is considered a fresh fruit pie with a meringue crust. It's named after a Russian ballerina, Anna Pavlova, who toured Australia and New Zealand in 1926. The dessert is considered "as light as Pavlova."According to Linda Stradley in What's Cooking America, the origin of the dessert is yet another point of contention between Australia and New Zealand."While it has been suggested this dessert was created in New Zealand, it has also become recognized as a popular Australian dish," she wrote. "Both countries claim to have invented this dessert and claim it as their national dish."So perhaps it's a tip of the cap to Scott's caddie Steve Williams, the New Zealander who gave Scott the correct read on the Masters winning putt on the second playoff hole.Scott's mother, Pam, will not be personally making the treats that will end the Champions Dinner."It's her recipe, but she's not actually going to be there making it," Scott said. "I don't know if I want her up there with Arnold (Palmer) and Jack (Nicklaus). I don't know if she can handle the pressure."</p><p>As for the rest of Scott's menu, he lit up when asked specifically if Moreton Bay Bugs would be served. The "bugs" are really a specia of slipper lobster found in Moreton Bay near Brisbane, the capital city in Queensland where Scott grew up on the Gold Coast. Locals liken it to crayfish."Moreton Bay Bugs is one of my favorites," Scott said. "It's a good guess. It's a very good guess. I hope (the other champions) won't be put off by the bugs. They'll like it."</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2014 17:06:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2580 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Frenchman has already qualified for Masters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/frenchman-has-already-qualified-masters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/Match%20Play%20Golf_Boye.jpg" /></div><p>Yes, Victor Dubuisson is already qualified for this year's Masters Tournament.</p><p>He will be part of an impressive rookie class that includes Jordan Spieth, Graham DeLaet, Harris English, Patrick Reed and Jimmy Walker.</p><p>Dubuisson, who is from France, qualified at the end of 2013 thanks to being in the top 50 in the Official World Golf Ranking.</p><p>France has not produced many top-notch golfers through the years, and Jean Van de Velde, Thomas Levet&nbsp;and Gregory Havret seem to be the most notable ones of the past 20 years.</p><p>Dubuisson, though, has plenty of star power. The 23-year-old played impressive golf in reaching the finals of the Match Play Championship, and he made a pair of incredible par saves in his loss to Jason Day.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2014 16:53:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2579 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Canada has a champion at the Masters, too</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/canada-has-champion-masters-too</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/FLYERS_MAPLE_LEAFS_3841220.jpg" /></div><p>With all of the talk this week about the hockey rivalry between the U.S. and Canada, it brought back memories of the first Canadian to win the Masters.</p><p>Mike Weir got the best of American Len Mattiace in the 2003 Masters.&nbsp;</p><p>The Canadian women rallied to stun the U.S. women for the gold medal in Olympic hockey on Thursday. Today, the men square off with a spot in Sunday's gold medal game up for grabs.</p><p>Weir also was the first left-hander to win the Masters, beating Phil Mickelson to the punch by a year.&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2014 17:11:49 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2577 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>A look at the biggest upsets in Masters history</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/look-biggest-upsets-masters-history</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/1987_MIZE_MASTERS_4_M.jpg" /></div><p>The PGA Tour is holding its annual Match Play Championship this week, and there were plenty of upsets in Thursday's first round.</p><p>That brings to mind some of the biggest shockers in Masters Tournament history:</p><p>1946, Herman Kaiser: He and Ben Hogan each three-putted the final hole, and Keiser held on to win by one.</p><p>1971, Charles Coody: Jack Nicklaus was the heavy favorite to win, but the Texan held on for a two-stroke victory.</p><p>1987, Larry Mize: The hometown hero defeated Greg Norman and Seve Ballesteros in a sudden-death playoff.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 15:01:24 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2576 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>No. 4 was toughest hole at 2013 Masters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/no-4-was-toughest-hole-2013-masters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/MAS241FourthteeCT.jpg" /></div><p>No. 4, a long par-3, played the most difficult at the 2013 Masters.</p><p>The 240-yard hole known as Flowering Crab Apple had an average of 3.39. The hole has played at 3.28 since cumulative statistics began in 1942, which makes it the fourth most difficult in tournament history.</p><p>No. 17, which lost the Eisenhower Tree over the weekend, played to an average of 4.22 in 2013. It was the sixth most difficult.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 15:13:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2575 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Plenty of Eisenhower reminders exist</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/plenty-eisenhower-reminders-exist</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/13608.jpg" /></div><p>The Eisenhower Tree no longer exists, but don't fret if you are a fan of former president Dwight D. Eisenhower and his love affair with Augusta. His memory lives on at Augusta National and around Augusta:</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;EISENHOWER&nbsp;CABIN: Built in 1953 by a group of 50&nbsp;Augusta&nbsp;National&nbsp;members who bought building certificates, the cabin was built to specifications of presidential security. Secret Service agents occupied the bottom floor, while the&nbsp;Eisenhower&nbsp;family had the rest of the spacious cabin to themselves during visits. Numerous family mementos are still in place, and the cabin is available to club members for use.&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;IKE'S POND: Now an integral part of the Par-3 course, the spring-fed pond occupies three acres. During his second visit to&nbsp;AugustaNational,&nbsp;Eisenhower&nbsp;was walking on the eastern part of the property and discovered what he thought would be an ideal spot for a fish pond.&nbsp;Eisenhower&nbsp;told Clifford Roberts about his discovery - he even had a suggestion for where the dam should be located - and the pond was promptly built.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;EISENHOWER&nbsp;CRACKER BARREL: Located in the pro shop, the barrel was presented by George M. Humphrey in 1957. Humphrey was a member of&nbsp;Eisenhower's&nbsp;Cabinet and was a fellow club member. The inscription reads: ``This wood was part of the White House roof erected about 1817 and removed in 1927.'' Plenty of other Eisenhower items are scattered throughout the clubhouse.</p><p>&nbsp; &nbsp; CHURCH TRIBUTE: At Reid Memorial Presbyterian Church in Augusta, &nbsp; Eisenhower usually sat on the third pew on the left, facing the altar. Across the aisle, a stained glass window features a likeness of him in a scene depicting the three wise men offering gifts to the baby Jesus. &nbsp;After&nbsp;Eisenhower's&nbsp;death, Reid honored the former president with a plaque on the pew where he and his family sat. Also at the service Feb. 6, 1972, the Redemption Window, in the church's balcony, was dedicated to his memory.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 17:07:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2573 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Masters a leader in tournament innovations</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/masters-leader-tournament-innovations</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p> The mandate for all Masters and Augusta National chairmen is the same: make it better.</p><p> Since the tournament began in 1934, the tournament has been a leader in golf innovations.</p><p> Over-under scoring, gallery control and advances in TV coverage are just some of the many contributions the Masters has made.</p><p> What will the Masters think of next </p><p> &nbsp;</p><p> &nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2014 22:33:17 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2569 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Applications open for practice round and daily tournament tickets</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/applications-open-practice-round-and-daily-tournament-tickets</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>Augusta National Golf Club has opened the application process for the 2014 Masters Tournament.</p><p>Individuals can apply for practice round tickets and/or daily tournament tickets.</p><p>The deadline for applying for daily tickets is May 31, and the deadline for practice rounds is June 30.</p><p>For more information, visit:</p><p>http://www.masters.com/en_US/tickets/index.html</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2013 15:20:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2503 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott on winning with a long putter: "It's inevitable big tournaments would be won with this equipment. I don't know if this going to have any impact on any decision upcoming."</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-winning-long-putter-its-inevitable-big-tournaments-would-be-won-equipment-i</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2487 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott: "Although Greg was an inspiration to me and a hero, my dad was always there."</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-although-greg-was-inspiration-me-and-hero-my-dad-was-always-there</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2486 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott on Cabrera: "His chip on the first playoff hole was just beautiful. Unlucky not to go in."</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-cabrera-his-chip-first-playoff-hole-was-just-beautiful-unlucky-not-go</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2483 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott: "18, I was pumped. It was a huge moment. I thought I had to seize it right there."</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-18-i-was-pumped-it-was-huge-moment-i-thought-i-had-seize-it-right-there</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:23:51 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2482 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott: "I think he's a gentleman. With limited ability to converse, we consider each other friends."</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-i-think-hes-gentleman-limited-ability-converse-we-consider-each-other-frien</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:22:20 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2481 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott: "I could barely see the cup with the darkness." Steve Williams told him the putt broke two cups. "He was my eyes for that putt."</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-i-could-barely-see-cup-darkness-steve-williams-told-him-putt-broke-two-cups</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:20:14 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2480 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott on birdie putt at 18: "That's the putt you've seen guys hole. O'Meara comes to mind. I told myself to go with instinct." #masters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-birdie-putt-18-thats-putt-youve-seen-guys-hole-omeara-comes-mind-i-told-mys</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:18:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2479 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott: "I played solid today, but I was very shaky on my putts with the speed."</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-i-played-solid-today-i-was-very-shaky-my-putts-speed</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:17:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2478 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott: I'm a proud Australian and I hope this sits real well back home</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-im-proud-australian-and-i-hope-sits-real-well-back-home</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2013 00:12:30 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2477 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott drains a 15-foot birdie putt, first Australian to win the Masters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-drains-15-foot-birdie-putt-first-australian-win-masters</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:38:45 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2472 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera just misses birdie putt at 10</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-just-misses-birdie-putt-10</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:37:05 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2471 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera, Scott each have about 20 feet for birdie at No. 10</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-scott-each-have-about-20-feet-birdie-no-10</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:33:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2470 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>#Masters fact: No sudden death playoff in tournament history has ever gone past two holes. </title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/masters-fact-no-sudden-death-playoff-tournament-history-has-ever-gone-past-two-ho</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:32:10 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2469 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>#Masters fact: No sudden death playoff in tournament history has ever gone past two holes. </title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/masters-fact-no-sudden-death-playoff-tournament-history-has-ever-gone-past-two--0</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:32:09 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2468 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott finds middle of fairway at No. 10, Cabrera hits into left fairway</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-finds-middle-fairway-no-10-cabrera-hits-left-fairway</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:29:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2467 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Playoff headed to second hole, will move to No. 10</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/playoff-headed-second-hole-will-move-no-10</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:25:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2466 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott chips third to three feet</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-chips-third-three-feet-0</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:24:31 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2465 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott chips third to three feet</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-chips-third-three-feet</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:24:11 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2464 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera almost holes out chip, 18 inches left for par</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-almost-holes-out-chip-18-inches-left-par</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:23:22 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2463 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera hits second shot short of the green</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-hits-second-shot-short-green</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:20:34 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2462 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott hits second shot just short of the green</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-hits-second-shot-just-short-green</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:19:42 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2461 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera, Scott each find fairway at No. 18.</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-scott-each-find-fairway-no-18</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:15:36 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2459 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera makes birdie, forces playoff with Scott at No. 18</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-makes-birdie-forces-playoff-scott-no-18</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 23:01:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2457 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera hits approach to four feet at 18, needs that for playoff</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-hits-approach-four-feet-18-needs-playoff</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 22:58:47 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2456 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Scott rolls in 30-foot birdie putt for a 1-shot lead over Cabrera</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/scott-rolls-30-foot-birdie-putt-1-shot-lead-over-cabrera</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 22:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2455 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Day pars 18, finishes at 7-under</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/day-pars-18-finishes-7-under</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 22:52:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2454 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera just misses a birdie putt at 17, will enter last hole tied at -8 with Scott.</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/blog/cabrera-just-misses-birdie-putt-17-will-enter-last-hole-tied-8-scott</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 22:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2450 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera just misses a birdie putt at 17, will enter last hole tied at -8 with Scott.</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/node/2451</link>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 22:43:40 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2451 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>