<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?><rss version="2.0" xml:base="http://www.augusta.com/mrss/feed/21" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>
<title></title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/feeds/featured.xml</link>
<description></description>
<language>en</language>
<item>
<title>Masters anniversaries: Arnold Palmer wins fourth title in 1964</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/masters-anniversaries-arnold-palmer-wins-fourth-title-1964</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/Arnold64.jpg" /></div><p>EDITOR'S NOTE: This is the story that ran in The Augusta Chronicle on April 13, 1964, following Arnold Palmer's fourth win at the Masters Tournament.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Arnold Palmer won the 28th Masters Tournament Sunday, just like everyone thought he would.</p><p>He did it without a great deal of drama. But, goodness! What glory! The great Pennsylvanian with the blacksmith arms shot a super closing round of 70 over the sunshine-sparkled greenery of Augusta National for a 72-hole score of 276 and his fourth Masters title.</p><p>He was a great big six strokes ahead of anyone else who tried in the 28th renewal of the world's finest sports spectacular.</p><p>Defending champion Jack Nicklaus, another blond bear in the crowd until Sunday, closed with a magnificent five-under-par 67 to tie young Dave Marr for second place at 282. Marr, right in the ring with the champion and his famous "Arnie's Army,&rdquo; shot a brilliant 70, including a tremendous 25-foot birdie putt from the outskirts of the 18th green.</p><p>But, regardless of what anyone else did, this day, and the entire tournament, belonged to the 34-year-old Palmer.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> Missed the record</p><p>Palmer finished two strokes above the existing 72-hole standard of 274 set by Ben Hogan in 1953. His margin of victory was the second biggest in Masters history, topped only by Cary Middlecoff's seven-stroke win in 1955. He became the first man to ever win four Masters titles, and this is the good part because this immensely proud fellow named Palmer wants championships and lots of them. But his $20,000 first prize check made him the first man to ever win over $500,000 in official money on the professional tour, and it also makes him the leading money winner of the PGA year.</p><p>He also is the 17th winner in 17 tournaments this year.</p><p>The PGA Tour has never seen such decisiveness.</p><p>Palmer led all the way, shooting rounds of 69-68-69-70 for his 276.</p><p>He was tied for the first round lead with four other players but he quickly changed that situation and went to win his first major championship in two years and his first tournament since the Whitemarsh Open last October.</p><p>Nicklaus and Marr each earned $10,100.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> Devlin finished 4th</p><p>Australian Bruce Devlin, in second place heading to Sunday's finale, shot a one-over par 73 to pull in fourth at 284. Four players were deadlocked at 286 including 1961 Masters champion Gary Player, who had to have his tonsils removed in St. Joseph Hospital here today. Player shot a closing 73 and was tied with Bill Casper, Jim Ferrier and Paul Harney.</p><p>Graybeard Hogan, who thrilled the biggest galleries in Masters history with a spirited run at his third Masters title, shot an even par 72 to pull in at 287 along with Tony Lema and Mike Souchak. Lema had a 69 and Souchak his second straight 70.</p><p>Peter Butler of England, Al Gelberger, Gene Littler, Johnny Pott and Dan Sikes were in at even par 288.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> Beman, Cowan tie</p><p>National Amateur champion Deane Beman and Canadian Gary Cowan tied for low amateur honors at 291. Palmer had his only three-putt green of the tournament Sunday, but made up for these two lapses with another string of birdies on the final nine, a winding, watery stretch of land that he's left thoroughly barraged and bombed with birdies all this lovely week.</p><p>Palmer shot his fourth consecutive one-under par 35 on the first nine holes, but three-putted the 10th green to get even par for the day. At this point, playing partner Marr, who one-putted six of the first nine greens, pulled up within three strokes of Palmer. Marr promptly hooked his drive at the 11th and plunked his tee shot in the water at 12 to dash his hopes.</p><p>Nicklaus, meanwhile, scored a birdie at 12 and almost made a double eagle at the 13th, and birdied the 15th to get within four strokes of Palmer. Nicklaus' second shot at the 13th hit the flag on the first bounce, spun out of the cup and stopped only two feet away from the cup.</p><p>Mr. Palmer went immediately to work.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> Pars No. 13</p><p>He laced a stirring three wood to the back of the green at 13 and almost holed a 70-foot eagle putt. He missed the comeback three-footer and had his par. But on the 14th Palmer had his putter warm, something it hasn't been through a winless winter until he arrived at the National the first of the week. He there ran in a 12-foot birdie putt and added another at the 520-yard 15th hole to go 12-under par for the tournament.</p><p>That ended anyone's hopes officially right there. But the tournament had probably been Palmer's all week anyway. Never has he played better.</p><p>He was under par on each nine every day of the tournament. His front nine card read 35-35-35-35, and the back showed 34-33-34-35.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p> Score his lowest</p><p>The 72-hole score was Palmer's lowest ever in the Masters and was a full 10 strokes lower than Nicklaus' winning score in 1963. Palmer started with a loud bang at the 220-yard fourth hole when he holed a lengthy 40-footer which went up a slope and curled down into the bottom of the cup. He bogeyed the very next hole but made this up with a five-foot birdie putt at seven.</p><p>Marr putted like a wizard on the first few holes and was making a real run at Palmer until the 11th and 12th holes. He knocked in a 15-footer for a par at the first hole, an eight-foot birdie at the second and a 20-foot birdie at the third. Marr, voted into the tournament by a poll of former Masters champions, turned in 33 and was back in 37, thanks to his tremendous putt on the final green that tied Nicklaus and made himself an extra $2,000, the difference in second and third money.</p><p>Nicklaus, the 24-year-old Ohioan, hit his most powerful tee shots of the tournament on the final day and, at the 520-yard 15th, he crashed a 355-yard tee shot and played the hole with a drive and seven iron. He turned in 34 which included a 15-foot birdie at the nine, the longest putt he made in the entire tournament.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 04:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2650 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jimmy Walker's slow start gains speed for Masters debut</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/jimmy-walkers-slow-start-gains-speed-masters-debut</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/Jimmy%20Walker%20Northern%20Trust.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>There's nothing flashy about Jimmy Walker as a golfer &ndash; until you realize what he's done in the past six months.</p><p>Walker, 35, joins former Augusta State University star Patrick Reed as the first players since 1985 to make their Masters Tournament debuts after winning three times on the PGA Tour over a 12-month stretch following the previous year's event. Neither Walker nor Reed, 23, had ever won before they went on their run.</p><p>Walker won the PGA Tour's 2013-14 season-opening Frys.com in October, followed that three months later with a victory in the Sony Open and won at Pebble Beach in February, which vaulted him atop the FedEx Cup standings.</p><p>According to Sal Johnson of Golfstats.com, Denis Watson, in 1984, is the only other person dating back to 1970 to win three times in the year before his Masters debut. Watson won the Buick Open, the NEC World Series and in Las Vegas before playing in the 1985 Masters, where he tied for 53rd place.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Walker's wins came after a solid, but winless seven-year career on the PGA Tour, which followed a stint on the Web.com Tour, where he won three times. He went 187 PGA Tour starts before his victory at the Frys.com.</p><p>"There are early bloomers and late bloomers,&rdquo; Walker said. "I definitely think I'm blooming. I feel good.&rdquo;</p><p>Walker said the victories are a "validation for me, a lot of years being out here and working hard. And to see it all kind of pay off, that's what I've been waiting for.&rdquo;</p><p>But he'll leave it for others to say if he's now among the game's elite.</p><p>"That's not up for me to decide,&rdquo; Walker said. "I just go out and play golf. This is what I want to do and I've worked really hard to do it, to be here, and to be in this position and it's really cool. I'll let you guys (the media) figure all that stuff out.&rdquo;</p><p>Walker will have an experienced hand showing him around Augusta National Golf Club during practice rounds. His instructor is Butch Harmon, the son of 1948 Masters champion Claude Harmon.</p><p>"I'm looking forward to getting out there and talking to him about the golf course,&rdquo; Walker said of Harmon, who is ranked as the No. 1 golf instructor by Golf Digest this year. "I've been out a couple of times and played it so we've (Walker and his caddie) been charting it a little bit.</p><p>"It's funny, it's a golf course that you feel as if you've played it a thousand times because you've watched it on TV so many times,&rdquo; Walker said.</p><p>Walker had a memorable experience at Augusta National in 2009 when a member helped get him and his father on the course as guests. The Walkers played two days and stayed in one of the cabins on the grounds.</p><p>&rdquo;We played in January or December,&rdquo; he said. "It was just a cool experience. The guy that took us was amazing. We had a great time. We played the par-3 course. We did it all. It was ridiculous.</p><p>"My dad birdied three out of four par-5s,&rdquo; Walker said. "We had a blast. I don't think it could have been any more special if I had played the tournament for the first time. It was me and my dad getting to do it, and it was really cool.&rdquo;</p><p>And chilly. Walker remembers it was 38 degrees when they started play the second day.</p><p>"I think that's the only place on the planet you will go out and play when it's 38 and drizzling,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>In his trips back since qualifying for the Masters, Walker said it has been "more (about) business. Just trying to read more of the greens and see more of the greens.&rdquo;</p><p>Officially, he earned his Masters invitation by winning the Frys.com in October. This is the first season that the event &ndash; which had been part of the Fall Series &ndash; offered full FedEx Cup points and a Masters invitation to the champion.</p><p>The tournament was proud of that, and let Walker know it when he looked closely at his prizes.</p><p>"They had gotten a Masters flag and they stitched on it &lsquo;2014, congratulations on going to the Masters' so it was fun,&rdquo; Walker said.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 20 Mar 2014 04:53:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2649 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Patrick Reed rides hot streak to Masters debut</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/patrick-reed-rides-hot-streak-masters-debut</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406ReedAPfile3.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Ever since he qualified for the Masters Tournament back in August, Patrick Reed has believed he'll be in contention for the green jacket until the end &ndash; even if this is his major-championship debut.</p><p>Now we know why.</p><p>Reed, who is in his second full season on the PGA Tour, backed up his pre-Masters confidence in early March by bursting into the national consciousness with his golf and his words.</p><p>After winning the Cadillac Championship at Doral in wire-to-wire fashion to become the youngest World Golf Championships winner, the 23-year-old former Augusta State University All-American said he thought he was a "top-five player in the world.&rdquo;</p><p>The victory, which came against a field that featured 49 of the world's top-50 players, was the native Texan's third in his past 14 starts and moved him up to 20th in the world golf ranking at the time.</p><p>"All these guys are going to be at Augusta, basically, and to go wire-to-wire, that definitely just gives me more confidence come Sunday that if I play how I'm supposed to at Augusta, that we'll be in the running,&rdquo; he said after winning Doral.</p><p>If he were to win the Masters, Reed would be only the fourth player to do so in his first appearance, joining Horton Smith (1934), Gene Sarazen (1935) and Fuzzy Zoeller (1979).</p><p>He'll come into Augusta on a hot streak that hasn't been seen in 45 years. According to GOLFstats.com. no one since 1969 has won three times on the PGA Tour before playing in his first major championship.</p><p>All of Reed's wins have had a dramatic flair. In the first one, at Greensboro, N.C., in mid-August, Reed hit one of the "shots of the year&rdquo; from an uneven lie to win a sudden-death playoff over 20-year-old Jordan Spieth, who went on to be the 2013 PGA Tour Rookie of the Year.</p><p>In his second win, Reed shot three consecutive 63s to open the Humana Challenge in mid-January, a PGA Tour record. That earned him a congratulatory phone call from former President Clinton, whose Clinton Foundation is the presenting sponsor for the Humana Challenge.</p><p>Then in March, Reed won the World Golf Championships-Cadillac Classic, handling conditions at Doral that included 36 mph winds in the second round.</p><p>While the victory at Doral moved Reed from 44th in the world ranking to 20th, he has no doubt he'll soon be higher.</p><p>"It's just one of those things that I feel like with how hard I've worked, I'm working my way up to become a top-five player in the world,&rdquo; said Reed, who was ranked 168th before he won in Greensboro in August. "But the thing is, it's just going to take a little time in the fact that I haven't been on the PGA Tour for very long.&rdquo;</p><p>After his win, Reed explained why he believes he's a top-five player.</p><p>"I've worked so hard,&rdquo; he said. "I've won a lot in my junior career. I did great in my amateur career. I went 6-0 in match play in NCAAs. We won NCAAs two years in a row (at Augusta State). I got third individually one year at NCAAs. Now, I have three wins on the PGA Tour. I just don't see a lot of guys who've done that, besides Tiger (Woods) and the other legends of the game. I believe in myself. I feel like I've proven myself.&rdquo;</p><p>Reed's top-five boast was a hot topic in the weeks leading up to the Masters.</p><p>In mid-March, two weeks after the "top-five&rdquo; comment, Reed stood by his remark at the Arnold Palmer Invitational, his first event since winning at Doral.</p><p>"I thought it was pretty funny; it was interesting to see how much of a stir that got,&rdquo; he said. "When it comes down to it, that's what I believe in. You have to have that belief in yourself. If you don't then you're not going to play like it, and you're definitely not going to be contending on Sundays.&rdquo;</p><p>Two-time Masters champion Tom Watson, who will captain the 2014 U.S. Ryder Cup team that Reed hopes to make, weighed in on the remark.</p><p>"When you win, you have that aura that you're at the top of your game and it's hard for anybody to beat you,&rdquo; Watson said. "That's a good place to be. As we all know, the game can turn on you and it will turn on you, and you'll go through the low spells.</p><p>"What Patrick said, I can understand him saying that, but after 14 events and winning three of them, I guess maybe he has a little bit of street cred. After my first event winning, I said I hope my goal was to be the best golfer in the world. After winning three out of the first 14, you've got to give the guy a little bit of credit.&rdquo;</p><p>Augusta National is less than 10 minutes from the campus of Augusta State (now known as Georgia Regents University), where Reed helped the team win NCAA Division I national titles in 2010 and 2011.</p><p>"That's going to be a treat walking down that first fairway at Augusta,&rdquo; Reed said.</p><p>The Jaguars were underdogs both years they won their national titles. It is an attitude Reed carried to the pro ranks. With no playing status, he made it through six of eight Monday qualifiers to get into PGA Tour events in 2012, often driving all night with his wife, Justine, and playing the 18-hole rounds with little sleep. He earned his PGA Tour card for 2013 through the 2012 Q-School (shooting a final-round 68 to get his card on the number).</p><p>"I always play to try to prove to everybody that I belong out here, not only out here on the PGA Tour but also with the best players in the world.&rdquo; Reed said.</p><p>Despite his Augusta ties, Reed isn't sure if he'll have much local support once the Masters starts.</p><p>"Maybe,&rdquo; he said of being a local fan favorite. "The main thing is I can't focus on that as much as what's happening inside the ropes and focus on my golf game. The more I try to be a crowd-pleaser and worry about everyone that is around you, you get distracted from your game. "I'm excited but at the same time I can't get ahead of myself,&rdquo; Reed said of his Masters debut. "It's my first major. If you get ahead of yourself, it's going to distract you and you're probably not going to play very well. I'm pretty sure we'll enjoy it Monday through Wednesday, but once the tournament comes, it's strictly business.&rdquo;</p><p>Reed loves to compete so much that he'd like to play almost every week leading up to the Masters. But, he decided to play just one time between Doral and the Masters.</p><p>"I know how important it is,&rdquo; he said of the Masters. "After Augusta I'm sure I'll be playing pretty hard up until May 26.&rdquo;</p><p>That is the due date for his wife, who had to give up caddying for her husband starting with the Tournament of Champions in early January. Justine's brother, Kessler Karain, has taken her place, but she plans to return in the future.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2014 05:08:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2645 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Snedeker's chances, not attitude, dampened by rain in final round</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/masters/snedekers-chances-not-attitude-dampened-rain-final-round</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/MAS7084SnedekerMH.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Who knows what might have happened if the rains hadn't come in the final round of the 2013 Masters Tournament  Maybe Brandt Snedeker would have a green jacket today.</p><p>Had the normally slick Augusta National greens stayed dry and fast that day, Snedeker might well have realized his lifelong dream of winning at Augusta National Golf Club.</p><p>"You think about that, but you've got to be able to adjust,&rdquo; Snedeker said about the rain.</p><p>Instead, Snedeker, who shot 70-70-69 in the first three rounds and was tied for the lead after 54 holes, couldn't get the pace down on the damp greens, struggled to 75 and finished tied for sixth place.</p><p>"The greens really messed me up. I was so used to how fast they were (in the third round) and I left every putt short out there. I could not get a putt to the hole. I did not do a good job of making adjustments. I wish it had played firm and fast like it did on Saturday, and it just didn't happen.&rdquo;</p><p>Snedeker started the final round strong, striking for birdie on the first hole, to take the tournament lead.</p><p>"I was confident; I was playing great. I liked my chances,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Snedeker was still even par for the round when the greens started to slow down because of the rain, which he said started early in the round. The water started slowing down the greens on the fifth hole, which he bogeyed.</p><p>Snedeker, whose strength is putting, "never had the speed,&rdquo; he said. "I did not putt the way you're supposed to putt around Augusta.&rdquo;</p><p>Snedeker bogeyed Nos. 10 and 11, then failed to birdie No. 13 after hitting into the tributary of Rae's Creek fronting the green. He then made bogey at No. 14 after an errant tee shot, and trailed Jason Day by four shots.</p><p>"I think that was the killer for me, when I bogeyed No. 14, which was a pretty tough one to take. I birdied No. 15 and kind of limped in from there,&rdquo; said Snedeker, who parred Nos. 16 and 17 before closing with a bogey on No. 18.</p><p>"If I had birdied 13 and parred 14, I would have had a chance,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>For the second time in his six starts in the Masters, Snedeker played in the final group in the closing round, a spot that had produced 19 of the previous 22 Masters champions.</p><p>In 2008, Snedeker played in the final group with eventual champion Trevor Immelman. He shot 77 and finished tied for third."I played really well for 54 holes,&rdquo; said Snedeker, referring to the 2013 Masters, where his 4-under-par 284 total tied his low score at Augusta National. "If I putt the way I normally do on Sunday, I think I have a really good chance of winning that golf tournament.&rdquo;</p><p>Before the final round, Snedeker had proclaimed that he was "not here to get a good finish. I'm not here to finish top five. I'm here to win.&rdquo;</p><p>After reflecting on last year's Masters, Snedeker found a lot to like about his play.</p><p>"I accomplished a lot of my goals that week,&rdquo; he said. "I got in the last group, which if you look at the tradition in the history of the Masters, it's a pretty good place to be. Your odds of winning increase dramatically if you're there. So I took a lot of really good stuff out of that.&rdquo;</p><p>He knows he has the game to win at Augusta National.</p><p>"It gives me some confidence to know if you keep banging on that door it's going to happen,&rdquo; he said. "I know it is. I believe it is. I did not feel overwhelmed at any point last year. I did not feel like I didn't have a chance. And I know my time is coming.&rdquo;</p><p>That's because he handled the pressure better in 2013 than he did in 2008.</p><p>"I felt like I didn't leave any shots out there,&rdquo; Snedeker said. "The last time, when I played poorly (in 2008), I felt like I left a few out there. I tried hard on every one of them. When I look back on it, I wouldn't have done anything differently than I did. You take some solace when you walk away from it.&rdquo;</p><p>Snedeker was healthy for the 2013 Masters, but his early-season momentum (a win, two runner-ups and a third in his first five events) had been slowed by a rib injury that forced him to sit out five weeks. He returned in mid-March and missed the cut in his two starts before the Masters.</p><p>In Snedeker's seven-year PGA Tour career, the only season he was injury-free was his first.</p><p>"It's very concerning,&rdquo; said Snedeker, who has had surgery on both hips to correct a degenerative problem and missed the 2012 U.S. Open because of a rib injury. In late 2013, he missed two months because he fell off a Segway scooter and injured his left knee.</p><p>"I don't consider myself that, but the evidence bears out that I am injury-prone,&rdquo; he said. "I've had way too many injuries for a guy my age, so I'm trying everything I can think of to counteract that, and diet is one of those things I can do. So we're trying it and see how it goes. And hopefully I can get through. If I get through a whole year without an injury, I'll probably stick to it. It's just something I've got to do. I've got to be proactive for the rest of my career.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2014 05:12:50 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2644 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Bobby Jones' vision for Augusta National, Masters continues to grow</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/bobby-jones-vision-augusta-national-masters-continues-grow</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/Pro5.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Bobby Jones might not recognize some aspects of the Masters Tournament and Augusta National Golf Club if he were still around.</p><p>But he would surely appreciate the role both play in golf today.</p><p>The golf legend, who was born on St. Patrick's Day in 1902, is the greatest amateur golfer of all time. His legacy continues with Augusta National and the Masters.</p><p>It was Jones and co-founder Clifford Roberts who had the vision for a magnificent golf course and the gathering of friends that became the game's signature event.</p><p>His grandson, Bob Jones IV, recalled the first time he visited Augusta National in the early 1970s. He arrived at night, so he wasn't able to take in the beauty of the course until the next morning.</p><p>"I got up and I went outside Jones Cabin and I saw Augusta National for the first time,&rdquo; Jones recalled in a 2010 interview. "And you could have knocked me over with a feather, because for the first time in my life I realized the magnitude of who my grandfather was.</p><p>"I realized this place existed in his mind before it was put on paper. It just blew me away, and I've never looked at him the same way since.&rdquo;</p><p>Bobby Jones died in December 1971, and he witnessed first-hand the growth of both club and tournament.</p><p>Both have prospered in the 40 years since his death, perhaps more than Jones could have imagined.</p><p>The course has been lengthened more than 500 yards to combat advances in golf technology, but at the same it retains the shot values that Jones intended when he helped Alister MacKenzie design the course more than 80 years ago.</p><p>The club has flourished financially, a far cry from the meager beginnings when Jones and Roberts practically begged prospective members to join. Now, Augusta National can afford to buy up huge chunks of real estate to offer patrons free parking.</p><p>And the tournament itself is larger than life, with interest from fans growing each year. At the time of Jones' death, TV coverage was limited to the final few holes and just for a few hours for the final two rounds. Although still limited, there is now TV coverage each round and plenty of online options as well.</p><p>Perhaps Jones would be most proud of the role the club and tournament is playing in helping grow the game. Through various initiatives, including the creation of amateur events in Asia and South America, the Masters is trying to "create heroes&rdquo; for future generations.</p><p>The tournament's foundation is taking that a step further this year with the Drive, Chip & Putt national finals that will take place April 6. Created for golfers ages 7-15, a total of 88 boys and girls will compete at Augusta National on the Sunday before Masters Week.</p><p>There's no doubt that Bobby Jones would approve.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 05:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2643 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Immelman ends winless spell, seeks consistency</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/immelman-ends-winless-spell-seeks-consistency</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406ImmelmanMastersFILE2.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Of all the tales of glory that might come up during the exclusive Champions Dinner, the Web.com Finals opener in Fort Wayne, Ind., would have to qualify as the least-likely conversation starter.</p><p>But 2008 Masters Tournament winner Trevor Immelman won't hesitate to talk up his victory at the Hotel Fitness Championship &ndash; his most significant accomplishment since donning the green jacket six years ago.</p><p>"It might not have been the biggest tournament in the world but it sure was big for me,&rdquo; Immelman said of the win that secured his PGA Tour card. "I'm fighting for my job and anybody who's been in that situation, whether it's business or sport, it's a big deal. So there was a lot of pressure for me and it felt comfortable and it felt great. I love it. I loved every minute of it.&rdquo;</p><p>It's been a rough run for Immelman since his breakthrough victory by three shots over Tiger Woods at Augusta National when he was a fresh 28. A wrist injury derailed him the next season and the subsequent loss in form led to a loss in confidence. Before he knew it, the five-year major championship exemption was set to expire.</p><p>It's a humbling experience.</p><p>"There's two ways to look at it,&rdquo; Immelman said. "From that standpoint (of winning Masters), yes it is (humbling). But this game owes nobody anything. Secondly, I've just got to play better. I can't really blame anybody other than myself for the situation that I'm in. I take full responsibility and I'm working my butt off to fix it.&rdquo;</p><p>The circumstances put Immelman in the 125-player pool gunning for 25 available spots in the inaugural four-event Web.com Finals. In the final round at Sycamore Hills Golf Club, he drained a 16-foot birdie putt to cap a round of 66 for a one-shot victory over Patrick Cantlay.</p><p>"It felt great and it felt natural, to be honest,&rdquo; he said of his first opportunity to win since the Masters. "I was wondering how I was going to react the Sunday. You could see with the strong finish I had and birdieing the last hole to win it &ndash; if you're timid or self-conscious or un-confident at that moment, you're probably not going to birdie that last hole. So it would be a testament for me feeling comfortable at that moment. But I've got to bring it out here now for an extended period of time, you know &rdquo;</p><p>It's a challenging exemption category on the PGA Tour that doesn't allow Immelman to set his usual schedule. And his success remains sporadic. It's been feast or famine.</p><p>He missed the cut in the three remaining Web.com Finals events, then tied for 21st in the PGA Tour wrap-around season opener in California. Another missed cut was followed by a tie for 20th at Sea Island. His tie for 10th at Torrey Pines was braced on each side by a pair of missed cuts.</p><p>"It seems like I put a good one together like once a month,&rdquo; Immelman said. "Then I miss a bunch of cuts, and I just don't feel like the best players in the world do that. At this point the challenge for me is to maintain it and keep it going. If you look at the best players in the world they have a consistent body of work that keeps them up there.</p><p>"A lot of that is self-belief if I'm going to be very honest with you. It's been a long, hard road and you get kicked in the gut enough times it's hard to keep fighting. But I see some light at the end of the tunnel and I'm happy with where everything is. Just going to keep fighting. I'm not going to retire at age 34. I really don't have another option.&rdquo;</p><p>For all his struggles, the Masters remains a safe haven for Immelman. He hasn't missed a cut at Augusta National since 2006 and posted three consecutive top-20 finishes after his 2008 triumph.</p><p>He shows up again feeling like he can still contend.</p><p>"Absolutely,&rdquo; he said. "It's always been the course that I've felt the most comfortable on. And I've always felt if I pitch up there with some form, then I've got a shot. Just because I know the course so well and have got a lot of great memories.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2014 07:08:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2641 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Marc Leishman learns from Masters experience</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/marc-leishman-learns-masters-experience</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406LeishmanDay1AustraliaJMS%2064.JPG" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Having a front row seat to Australian golf history wasn't exactly what Marc Leishman had in mind in the final round of the 2013 Masters Tournament, but it might be what he needed to eventually draft his own chapter.</p><p>Leishman was paired with fellow Aussie Adam Scott on Sunday and was in the hunt for the green jacket until the 15th hole. While he'd happily trade places with the Masters champion, he still savored the experience.</p><p>"It was great to be there and to be a part of something like that,&rdquo; Leishman said. "I think it's going to be good for my development, too.&rdquo;</p><p>In his second start at Augusta, Leishman made a big impression with a first-round 66 to share the lead with Sergio Garcia.</p><p>Leishman, however, didn't fade away. Rounds of 73-72 put him in the next-to-last pairing Masters Sunday.</p><p>"I got off to a good start, was leading after one round and then hung in there under that pretty intense pressure all week,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>"I know I can put it together for four rounds, probably a lot of guys didn't expect me to do what I did, and to do that was great.</p><p>"I didn't finish off the way I would have liked, but I have a lot of positives to take away from it.&rdquo;</p><p>Leishman was within two shots of the lead heading to the par-5 15th tee Sunday. Scott reached the green in two and made birdie to start his charge, while Leishman hit into the pond to make bogey and end his hopes. He finished fourth, tied with Tiger Woods.</p><p>"I missed getting a birdie on 13 and missed a holeable birdie putt on 14, then put all of my eggs in one basket on the 15th,&rdquo; Leishman said. "I was between 4- and 5-iron, and went for the 5 because the 4 would definitely have gone over the back. I ripped my 5 but just chunked it a little bit and came up short.</p><p>"But I was playing to win. Obviously I was disappointed I made a bogey, but I was glad that if I was going to make one, I made it attacking. I'm glad I stuffed up making bogey being aggressive rather than getting overly conservative.&rdquo;</p><p>What Leishman said he learned most from the experience is that winning a major requires consistency and execution when it counts.</p><p>"I saw what it takes to win a major,&rdquo; he said. "I got close myself and was right there. To see how Adam executed shots &ndash; obviously he did everything well but he didn't have to do anything spectacular. It was good to see that and see how it's done.&rdquo;</p><p>Leishman backed up his Masters performance with top-10s in his next two starts at Hilton Head Island and the Players Championship and parlayed his season's success into receiving one of Nick Price's captain's picks for the Presidents Cup.</p><p>"To get a pick off someone like (Price) definitely helped my confidence, just knowing that he knows a bit about golf and he obviously thought I had a bit of game, which never hurts,&rdquo; Leishman said. "I did play well in a few of the big tournaments and I think I deserved a pick.&rdquo;</p><p>Leishman got off to a strong start in 2014 with a fifth-place finish in Hawaii and a tie for second at Torrey Pines. Now he returns to Augusta trying to build on Australia's success after witnessing Scott's breakthrough.</p><p>"I have been asked about that a lot, but I don't get sick of talking about it,&rdquo; he said of his role as wingman. "It was such a big moment for Australia, for Australian sport. I had a good week myself. Scotty, obviously that was, I guess, a life changer for him. It's a really good memory and I enjoy talking about it.</p><p>"Hopefully I'll get one of my own at some stage.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sat, 15 Mar 2014 05:07:52 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2640 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Jason Day: I'm not going to quit until I win</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/jason-day-im-not-going-quit-until-i-win</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/04xxTOURChampionshipDayJMS%2027_0.JPG" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Jason Day has two career goals in golf: make it to world No. 1 and win the Masters Tournament.</p><p>"I'm not going to stop until I achieve that or if I injure myself and I'm done for the game,&rdquo; said Day, who is just 26.</p><p>One goal this season was to make it into the top five in the world ranking. Day, who was ranked 36th before last year's Masters, accomplished that in the 13th full-field event of the PGA Tour's 2013-14 wraparound season, which started in early October. He moved up to No. 4 in the ranking when he won the World Golf Championships-Match Play Championship in mid-February.</p><p>Day, who led the 2013 Masters after 69 holes before finishing third, now has his sights firmly on winning a green jacket.</p><p>"My game feels good,&rdquo; he said. "I've never been so focused in my life on competing and playing well than I have been this year. I've put in a lot of work on the golf course and I've put in a lot of work off the golf course on my body, everything. Ever since the World Cup win last year (with fellow Australian Adam Scott), it's been very motivating for me to go out and do the work and really push myself and see how far I can go.&rdquo;</p><p>Day had one less event to prepare for this year's Masters when he withdrew from the World Golf Championships-Cadillac Championship before the opening round because of an injury to his left thumb.</p><p>A Masters win might not move Day past Tiger Woods to No. 1 in the world ranking, but it would move him closer to the top.</p><p>"I know that Tiger is up there right now and there's a pretty big gap between me and him,&rdquo; Day said in March. "But you know, I think it's achievable if I put in the hard work, and first of all, win. That's the biggest thing &ndash; you have to come out and win, and win a lot. From there, we'll see how it goes.&rdquo;</p><p>For a while, it looked like Day, not Scott, would become the first Australian to win the Masters. After birdies on Nos. 13, 14 and 15, Day had taken the lead. But he bogeyed Nos. 16 and 17 and parred No. 18 to finish with 2-under-par 70, two shots out of the playoff with Scott and Angel Cabrera.</p><p>"I think if I had that opportunity again, I think I would have slowed everything down,&rdquo; Day said. "On No. 16, the pressure did get a little bit to me. Being in that situation was an amazing feeling going through my body. The rush that I got through my body after I birdied 15 was amazing.</p><p>"To have the lead there and go, &lsquo;Oh, man, I only have three holes left; if I can play well from here, I'll be the first Australian to win it.' It was an amazing feeling. I was so pumped and so amped that it got to me and I hit a 7-iron over the back there (on No. 16), which normally I would be hitting 7-iron just getting to the pin. I should have slowed down and just kind of talked to (caddie) Col Swatton a little bit more and really talked everything through so that all the information is gathered and I can execute the shot that I need to. And that's why you learn from it.&rdquo;</p><p>The difference between Day's loss at Augusta National and his Match Play Championship victory 10 months later was a matter of perseverance in the face of intense pressure.</p><p>"At the Masters, it just felt like I couldn't go on anymore,&rdquo; Day said.</p><p>At the Match Play Championship, Day lost a 3-up lead to France's Victor Dubuisson. He then beat Dubuisson, who was hitting magical recovery shots to stay in the match, on the 23rd hole of the scheduled 18-hole match.</p><p>"You get to a breaking point in your golf game where it can go either way,&rdquo; Day said. "You go, OK, I've had enough and I just need to sit down and chill out. Or you go, no, stuff that, I'm going to push through it and I'm not going to quit until I win.&rdquo;</p><p>Day's victory at the Match Play Championship was his second in his six-plus years on the PGA Tour (he won the 2010 Byron Nelson Championship).</p><p>After the latest victory, Day defended his record.</p><p>"I've heard things in the media saying he's only got one win,&rdquo; Day said. "At the end of the day, I've had a lot of consistent finishes in big events and obviously I said to myself I've got to keep working hard and work, work, work, work, work smart. As long as I don't give up and keep pushing through, it will happen again. And hopefully happen in bunches.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2014 05:38:54 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2638 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Snead outlasts Hogan, Patton to win 1954 Masters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/history/champions-through-ages-snead-outlasts-hogan-patton-win-1954-masters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406SneadHogan.jpg" /></div><p>NOTE: This story takes readers back through tournament champions, from the first tournament in 1934 every 10 years to present day. </p><p>For a more complete Masters history tour, visit our history section. &nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>There's no denying that the final round of the 1954 Masters Tournament was one of the most thrilling in golf's history.</p><p>An unheard-of amateur, Billy Joe Patton, almost stole the show. His heroics included a hole-in-one and the lead on the final nine before he found disaster on the incoming par-5 holes.</p><p>Almost lost in the shuffle is that Sam Snead and Ben Hogan wound up tied after 72 holes, with Patton alone in third just one shot back. The two golf legends would meet in an 18-hole playoff the next day.</p><p>Snead, Hogan and Byron Nelson formed a trio of American golfers that dominated the game from the mid-1930s to the mid-1950s. While Nelson had been retired from full-time competition for nearly a decade, Hogan and Snead were still at the top of their games. Hogan had won three majors in 1953, and Snead was eager to add to the six majors he had already won.</p><p>While that trio of golfers got the lion's share of attention, Patton came to Augusta with little fanfare. He earned his invitation on the basis of being an alternate on the 1953 Walker Cup squad. Other than a couple of regional victories, no one expected much from the North Carolina native.</p><p>Everyone, that is, except Patton. Right after getting his invitation, he ordered a new white jacket.</p><p>"You couldn't buy a cashmere jacket in Morganton, you had to order it,&rdquo; his brother, James Patton, said. "He said he wanted to look good at the presentation ceremony.&rdquo;</p><p>Patton started off with a bang, winning the long-driving contest held before the tournament, and shot 2-under 70 to share the first-round lead with Dutch Harrison. Patton slipped to 74 in the second round, but he still held the 36-hole lead.</p><p>"Everything's running my way,&rdquo; Patton told reporters. "I'm supposed to shoot 80 sometime in this tournament, you know, and I probably will.&rdquo;</p><p>It wasn't an 80, but Patton did shoot 75 in the third round. Hogan shot 69, the tournament's first sub-70 round, and he led Snead by three and Patton by five entering the final round. Cary Middlecoff and Tommy Bolt also were in the mix.</p><p>In 1954, the Masters didn't pair golfers by score. The leaders were often staggered, and there were not a lot of leaderboards around the course.</p><p>Patton was paired with three-time Masters winner Jimmy Demaret, and for five holes his round was uneventful. Then lightning struck, in the form of an ace, on the par-3 sixth.</p><p>Veteran golf writer Dan Jenkins was covering Ben Hogan for the Fort Worth Press, and he was hanging out with fellow writer Bob Drum.</p><p>"Drum and I are standing behind the sixth green, he's coming up, and I go away to get a Coke at the concession stand,&rdquo; Jenkins said. "I hear the roar. &lsquo;What happened ' &lsquo;Billy Joe made a one.' I said, &lsquo;What did it look like ' And, you know Drum, he was incredibly funny. I said, &lsquo;What did it look like, Bob ' He said, &lsquo;Here's the hole and here's the ball. That's a one.' I said, &lsquo;Did it bounce, did it fly ' &rdquo;</p><p>Patton added birdies at Nos. 8 and 9 to finish the front side in 32 and grab the lead, and by the time he reached No. 13 he was still in the thick of things. Hogan and Snead were not pulling away from the amateur.</p><p>Patton's tee shot at the par-5 13th was pushed to the edge of the fairway. Unsure of where he stood, Patton elected to go for the green in two.</p><p>"Bob Drum and I were standing right there on 13 and he was in the rough,&rdquo; Jenkins said. "Everyone wanted him to lay up. And he said, audibly so we could all hear it and quote it, &lsquo;I didn't get where I am by playing safe.' And he got in the water.&rdquo;</p><p>Patton found the tributary of Rae's Creek that fronted the green, and wound up with a double bogey.</p><p>He bounced back with a birdie at the 14th, but made another poor decision on the par-5 15th. From a questionable lie, he tried to hit the green in two but found the water again. This led to a bogey.</p><p>Up ahead, Snead had birdied the 13th and 15th to shoot even-par 72 and get in the clubhouse with a total of 1-over 289.</p><p>Patton parred the final three holes and missed an 18-foot birdie putt that would have tied him with Snead.</p><p>Hogan, playing behind the other two, struggled to 37 on the front nine. He fell behind on the 11th when his second shot found the pond guarding the green. That led to a double bogey and later prompted the famous quote from Hogan: "If you ever see me on the 11th green in two, you'll know I missed my second shot.&rdquo;</p><p>Hogan played the final seven holes in even par, but his 75 opened the door for Snead to tie. Just a few years removed from his near-fatal car accident, the last thing Hogan wanted was to have to walk another 18 holes.</p><p>After an epic final round, the Monday playoff between two of the all-time greats didn't come close to matching the excitement of the day before. But it was Hogan vs. Snead with a green jacket on the line, and that was enough for Jenkins.</p><p>The playoff was tight, and Snead took the lead on the 10th with an unlikely birdie.</p><p>"In the playoff he played so much better than Snead,&rdquo; Jenkins said of Hogan. "He missed two fairways and greens. Sam chips in on 10 with a 7-iron all the way across the damn green.&rdquo;</p><p>Snead gave back a stroke at the 12th, and they came to the par-5 13th all square again. Hogan elected to lay up and wound up with a par, while Snead hit the green in two and made birdie.</p><p>Hogan three-putted the 16th to fall two shots behind, and after Snead made a bogey on the final hole, the final tally was 70 to 71 in Snead's favor.</p><p>"I'm happy I was there,&rdquo; Jenkins said. "It was historic. Two of the greatest players in the world. The best-kept secret in golf was that they were really good friends. Ben and Sam were much better friends than Ben and Byron, who grew up together.</p><p>"Ben loved Sam's humor, and he admired his game. He always said Sam Snead's the greatest golfer in the world, he's got the greatest swing in history. He said if I could caddy for him he'd never lose a tournament.&rdquo;</p><p>Those lucky enough to have witnessed the playoff could not have guessed it would be the end of an era. Although both men would challenge for future majors, they would never win another major.</p><p>"Clairvoyant me, I wrote in the Fort Worth Press that this will be the last time we'll see these two giants contending for a major,&rdquo; Jenkins said. "I was a little bit wrong, because they did contend, but they never won another major.&rdquo;</p><p>Hogan, who also had lost an 18-hole Masters playoff to Byron Nelson in 1942, was gracious in defeat.</p><p>"He always gives you some good shots and a few chuckles,&rdquo; he said of Snead.</p><p>At the awards ceremony, Patton was on hand to receive his low amateur medal. With tournament co-founder Bobby Jones, Snead and Hogan all wearing their green jackets, Patton stood out with his white coat.</p><p>Years later, he said he didn't regret coming up short in his bid to become the first amateur to win the Masters.</p><p>"If I'd won that tournament, I'd had difficulty handling the money, the liquor would have been a problem, and with the women I didn't have a chance,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>1934</p><p>Horton Smith was the last man to beat Bobby Jones before his Grand Slam campaign of 1930, winning a tournament in Savannah, Ga. Four years later, Jones took the spotlight as he opened his new course for a new event.</p><p>Smith, though, held at least a share of the lead each day. On the final day, Smith came to the final three holes tied with Craig Wood. He birdied the 71st hole to edge Wood by a stroke.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>1944</p><p>The Masters was not held from 1943-45 because of World War II.</p><p>1964</p><p>Arnold Palmer became the first four-time Masters winner in dominant fashion, defeating Dave Marr and Jack Nicklaus by six shots.</p><p>Though neither Palmer nor his adoring public could have predicted it, the 1964 Masters would be his last victory in a major championship. He finished no worse than fourth the next three Masters, but after 1967 never seriously challenged again at Augusta National.</p><p>1974</p><p>By the time of Gary Player's second Masters triumph, he was well established as one of the game's top players and one of only four men to win all four of the game's major championships.</p><p>Starting with a pair of 71s, Player found himself five behind Dave Stockton at the midway point. A 66 in the third round, however, cut Player's deficit to just one stroke.</p><p>No less than half a dozen of the game's top players battled it out on Easter Sunday, but Player's closing 70 was good for the win. He punctuated his two-shot victory with a tap-in birdie at the 17th hole after hitting his 9-iron less than a foot from the hole.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>1984</p><p>Ben Crenshaw will always be remembered for being one of the greatest putters in golf history, but not even "Gentle Ben&rdquo; would have predicted he would make a 60-foot birdie putt on the 10th hole in the final round.</p><p>That unexpected birdie completed three in a row, and Crenshaw held on to win his first Masters by two shots.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>1994</p><p>Jose Maria Olazabal won his first major when he held off Tom Lehman for a two-shot win in Augusta.</p><p>Olazabal made an eagle on the 15th in the final round, and used his superb short game to join fellow Spaniard Seve Ballesteros as a Masters champion.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>2004</p><p>Phil Mickelson had played in 46 majors without a victory. He had his share of close calls, but he could hear the whispers that labeled him the best player to never win a major.</p><p>So when he made the turn in the final round of the 2004 Masters, Mickelson knew he was in the mix. Birdies at Nos. 12, 13, 14 and 16 put him into a tie with Ernie Els, who had already finished.</p><p>Mickelson came to the 18th hole needing a birdie for the outright win. His approach finished 18 feet past the hole, but playing partner Chris DiMarco was on a similar line and putted first.</p><p>With a good look at how the putt would break, Mickelson stepped up to his putt. His putt caught the lip of the cup and fell in, giving Lefty his first major victory and sending him skyward as he jumped for joy.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 13 Mar 2014 04:28:46 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2636 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Charl Schwartzel ready to embrace change</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/charl-schwartzel-ready-embrace-change</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406SchwartzelAP.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Charl Schwartzel failed family planning 101 for Masters champions &ndash; never risk a delivery date in early April.</p><p>The first child for Charl and Rosalind Schwartzel is due between April 3-8 &ndash; that latter date the Monday of Masters Tournament week. The 2011 Masters winner hopes his daughter doesn't start a habit of being fashionably late.</p><p>"If (Roz) reaches full term and it's before Masters, we'll probably induce (labor),&rdquo; Schwartzel said. "Hopefully she comes before by herself.&rdquo;</p><p>The South African will have to leave his wife and daughter behind at their home in South Florida while he tries to collect another green jacket. How the life-changing experience affects Schwartzel's game at Augusta is unknown.</p><p>"I think those sort of things can either work really in your favor or completely against you,&rdquo; he said. "It's very seldom where it's in-between in situations like that. I'm just really excited for our first child.&rdquo;</p><p>Schwartzel already senses how different life will be with an infant as they travel the world playing golf.</p><p>"It's a lot of luggage for a little person,&rdquo; he said. "I've been putting most of it up but I can see it's going to be a lot of luggage.&rdquo;</p><p>Fatherhood isn't the only upheaval in Schwartzel's life as he approaches his 30th birthday this summer. He cut ties with Chubby Chandler's management agency in February. Chandler had been looking out for Schwartzel since he was a 16-year-old amateur.</p><p>"Just felt like a change,&rdquo; Schwartzel said of his free-agent status as he shopped around for new management. "It was nothing personal, nothing anyone did wrong. &hellip; Sometimes in life you've got to maybe give yourself an opportunity to try something else.&rdquo;</p><p>His game, however, is in familiar form. For the second consecutive winter he won a tournament in Asia and the Alfred Dunhill Championship in his native South Africa. He's maintained a consistent top-20 ranking for all but a few months since he birdied the last four holes to win the 2011 Masters.</p><p>"I'm really feeling good,&rdquo; he said. "I think my strength for the last few months has really been my putting. I just don't have a nice feel for it at the moment playing on so many different greens. It doesn't feel bad and it's not something that I'm worried about. It's just I'm hitting a lot of putts that are going over edges. If I can change that I think I'll be OK.&rdquo;</p><p>Schwartzel let another decent chance at Augusta slip away last year. A pair of 71s had him among the top 10 a few strokes off the lead entering the weekend before rounds of 75-73 sent him tumbling to a tie for 25th.</p><p>"That golf course can very quickly get you,&rdquo; he said. "If it goes wrong it feels like it's really hard to stop. I just had one of those tough weekends. You feel like you're not hitting bad shots but getting bad results and then eventually you do hit a bad shot and get a really bad result. It was one of those weekends you maybe want to forget.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 03:58:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2623 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Henrik Stenson's on a great run and headed to Augusta</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/henrik-stensons-great-run-and-headed-augusta</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/04xxSundayTourChampionship%20Stenson%20JMS%2001.JPG" /></div><p>Following what he calls "the season of his life,&rdquo; Henrik Stenson has gone from one of the last players to qualify for the 2013 Masters Tournament to one of the world's top-ranked players and a favorite to win the green jacket this year.</p><p>At this time last year, the Swede was breaking out of a nearly two-year slump. He tied for eighth at Bay Hill in mid-March and then tied for second in Houston. The finish in Houston moved him into the top 50 in the world ranking at the cutoff date to make the Masters field.</p><p>He would finish in a tie for 18th at Augusta National Golf Club.</p><p>Stenson dominated play on both sides of the Atlantic over the summer and into late 2013. He became the first player to win the PGA Tour's FedEx Cup and European Tour's Race to Dubai in the same season. The former is a points race based on finishes, culminating in a playoff for the Cup; the latter is based on money earned, which Stenson wrapped up by winning the season-ending DP World Tour Championship by six shots at 25-under.</p><p>"I have managed to achieve something very special,&rdquo; he said of his double. "That's going to take some beating I guess in the future.&rdquo;</p><p>His world ranking skyrocketed from 222nd at the end of 2011 to third at the start of 2014.</p><p>"It was a dream year, a dream summer for me. I would be lying if I said I saw all that coming,&rdquo; said Stenson, who won the Deutsche Bank Championship and the Tour Championship on the PGA Tour and the DP World Tour Championship on the European Tour last season.</p><p>"One of the main things is it never stops,&rdquo; said Stenson, referring to expectations. "I had my great run starting from July to the end of the year, which I think is a very good achievement in its own to keep it going for such a long time playing at such a high level.&rdquo;</p><p>Indeed, from mid-July to the end of the season, Stenson had six top-three finishes and won twice.</p><p>That was quite a contrast to 2011. He was playing so poorly, due in part to viral pneumonia and a stomach bug, that he failed to qualify for the PGA Championship that year in August. So he played in his club championship at Barseback Golf Club in Sweden.</p><p>"I was playing in the club championship, and maybe you're not really up for it, and I finished second,&rdquo; he said with a chuckle.</p><p>With the help of instructor Pete Cowen, Stenson started to regain his form. It didn't happen overnight, though a good sign came when he won the South African Open in November 2012 for his first European Tour victory in five years.</p><p>"It is a lot of hard work,&rdquo; Stenson said of his return to golf's elite (he had been ranked as high as fifth in 2009 before his swoon). "It's not something you do in June. It's probably a year, year and a half in the making leading up to that point where I addressed 20 different processes, anything from scheduling to practicing. So many different things.</p><p>"One of the biggest things for me was sticking to the long-term process rather than chasing the quick fix,&rdquo; he said. "When you're down and out, it's so easy to look for something you want to work on tomorrow or this week instead of saying, &lsquo;Where are we at and where do we want to get to ' and put a plan in place and work.&rdquo;</p><p>Stenson accepted the fact a revival was going to take time &ndash; and patience.</p><p>"It's hard to do when most players out here would have an overhanging feeling of having to perform in terms of otherwise thinking &lsquo;I'm not going to make my money, I need to keep my card in order to stay on tour,' &rdquo; Stenson said. "It's hard to commit to the long term.&rdquo;</p><p>This will be Stenson's ninth Masters, where his best finish is a tie for 17th place in 2007 and 2008. He is best known for what he did in the first round of the 2012 Masters. He was leading the tournament at 5-under when he came to the 18th hole. He hit his drive left and eventually ended up taking a quadruple bogey 8 that left him at 71.</p><p>"In 2012, that (round) was more of a fluke with the putter,&rdquo; Stenson said. "I hit some good shots into two and eight and made some good putts for eagle and snuck another one in there, and then made a monster putt on 10.</p><p>"I wasn't playing that great,&rdquo; he said. "I don't think I hit a fairway on the back nine more or less. It all kind of ended quite abruptly with a quadruple up 18.&rdquo;</p><p>He ended up finishing tied for 40th in 2012, but he felt his best performance came in 2009 when he tied for 38th place.</p><p>"That was probably the year I played the best tee to green, but I wasn't putting good at all. You know you have to putt well around there to have much of a chance.&rdquo;</p><p>Looking at his body of work in the Masters, Stenson said, "I've done some half-decent tournaments, but nothing great. We're hoping to change that this year. It's a course I can see myself doing well at, absolutely.&rdquo;</p><p>When he got into the Masters at the 11th hour with his runner-up finish in Houston last year, Stenson had to wait two weeks before the Masters started, which he said didn't help.</p><p>"For me it would have probably been more beneficial to come straight from Houston into Augusta,&rdquo; Stenson said. "It would have been easier to carry a bit more momentum to go straight in there. I feel like I've got a good schedule leading up to the event this year.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2014 00:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2619 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Olesen's first Masters try pleases Denmark</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/olesens-first-masters-try-pleases-denmark</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406ThorbjornOlesen2.JPG" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Thorbjorn Olesen would have been easy to overlook at Augusta National last April.</p><p>At 5-foot-9, 152 pounds, the young Dane looks more like a kid on spring break than a Masters participant. His opening-round 78 was the most typical rookie thing about him.</p><p>What he did the next three days, however, should have turned some heads. Olesen recovered with rounds of 70-68-68 to finished tied for sixth, his 10-under par three-day tally the best of the field in the toughest conditions.</p><p>"After the round I felt like I played solid golf and shot 78,&rdquo; Olesen said. "It's just one of those courses where you can play great and shoot close to 80. It's so easy when you get a little too aggressive and hit the wrong spots on the greens to make bogeys and double bogeys. But when you get it going there you can make a lot of birdies.&rdquo;</p><p>If not for a couple of bad swings that led to a back-nine 41 on Thursday, Augusta might have been toasting the 23-year-old Dane instead of 32-year-old Australian Adam Scott on Sunday.</p><p>"It was just two bad shots really, and a couple of bad putts, and that's a couple of double bogeys&rdquo; on 10 and 18, Olesen said. "It's so easy on that golf course, when you don't know the course and you're being a little bit too aggressive and you get a few dodgy swings.</p><p>"The next three days I played the same pretty much and felt just really confident on the greens and the whole area. I absolutely love the place and am really looking forward to going back.&rdquo;</p><p>Despite his slight frame and inexperience, Olesen arrived at Augusta as a promising prodigy. He'd impressed as a 22-year-old when he held his own in a third-round matchup with Tiger Woods in the 2012 British Open at Royal Lytham & St. Annes.</p><p>It was Woods' Masters victory in 1997 that inspired Olesen to play golf.</p><p>"That was a big moment in my career,&rdquo; Olesen said about his British Open pairing with Woods. "Playing normal tournaments and all of the sudden being in a major on Saturday in one of the final groups with Tiger is very special.</p><p>"He's been my biggest idol by far and I was very pleased to be there. I was very nervous the first three or four holes but then I settled in and played really nice golf and he beat me by one. But it was a good round.&rdquo;</p><p>That performance started trending Olesen from outside the top 100 toward the top 50, which earned him a trip to Augusta. He got acquainted with the course in an unusual fashion.</p><p>"It was a fun experience when I came there on Sunday and just walked the course in the late afternoon with a putter in my hands,&rdquo; he said. "I think that really helped me a lot just getting the feel of the greens.&rdquo;</p><p>A couple of practice rounds with Danish veteran Thomas Bjorn mapped out the best places to hit or miss and he put together an effective game plan.</p><p>"I feel like the tee shots suit me and I'm hitting my irons pretty solid,&rdquo; Olesen said. "That's what makes it easier for me at the Masters, because I like to shape it both ways. I think that's very important at the Masters. I'm looking forward to getting back there and feel pretty confident.&rdquo;</p><p>Despite a couple of top-five finishes on the European Tour's desert swing, Olesen has slipped outside the top 60 in the world ranking. Playing full time on the PGA Tour will provide a new experience in his development, but he returns to Augusta with good thoughts.</p><p>"Obviously you need to play well and if you're not in good form coming into the tournament it's really tough,&rdquo; he said. "Last year I played really solid at the start of the year, I was close to winning a couple of tournaments on the desert swing in the European Tour. So obviously I had a lot of confidence going into the Masters.&rdquo;</p><p>His sixth-place finish was well received in Denmark, where the previous best result for a Dane at Augusta was a tie for 18th by Bjorn in 2002.</p><p>"It was the best result from a Danish guy in the Masters, so yeah, I got quite a lot of attention,&rdquo; Olesen said. "It was a major and Thomas has been close to winning a couple times. That's my big goal, to win a major sometime, and that was a good step in the right direction.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 05:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2616 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Cabrera got close, but not close enough</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/cabrera-got-close-not-close-enough</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/MAS7276ScottWinsADT.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>If you thought that his superlative play and a green jacket already hanging in his locker was consolation enough for Angel Cabrera after a playoff loss at last year's Masters Tournament, you would be grossly mistaken.</p><p>The two-time major champion from Argentina isn't satisfied with moral victories.</p><p>"For me there wasn't anything good,&rdquo; Cabrera said. "I came out second. I wanted to win. I was right there, I had the chance and for me, something good would have been to win.&rdquo;</p><p>From the moment he walked on the grounds at Augusta National Golf Club until the instant Adam Scott's birdie putt disappeared into the cup on the second playoff hole, Cabrera believed he was going to win a second green jacket.</p><p>"I felt good all week,&rdquo; Cabrera said. "I had a good feeling and I felt comfortable.&rdquo;</p><p>His swing coach Charlie Epps even predicted as much when they arrived in Augusta the Sunday before.</p><p>"You better watch out for him this week,&rdquo; Epps said.</p><p>Cabrera didn't make many missteps all week, shooting under-par every round. The steady rain on Sunday did nothing to diminish his resolve.</p><p>"I won twice in England and in England you play often with that weather,&rdquo; he said. "I won at Belfry and the weather there was worse than here &ndash; the rain, the wind, the cold. It was worse than that.&rdquo;</p><p>Perhaps his biggest disappointment was the par-5 13th hole, which he bogeyed both days on the weekend. His Sunday mistake there dropped him two shots behind leader Jason Day at the time.</p><p>"The shot that surprised me was the shot on 13 that he let it get away a few yards to the right and made bogey,&rdquo; Epps said.</p><p>When it counted, Cabrera stepped up with birdies on 16 and 18 in the final three rounds. No shot came under more pressure than his 7-iron approach from 163 yards on the 72nd hole after the concussive reaction to Scott's 28-foot birdie putt.</p><p>Cabrera ranks the shot he stuck to 4 feet to set up the tying birdie as one of the best of his career. It matches his drive on the final hole at Oakmont in the 2007 U.S. Open, which he won for his first major.</p><p>"At Augusta every shot is difficult, but there I didn't have another choice,&rdquo; he said. "I had to try to leave it close and make the putt. I didn't have other options.&rdquo;</p><p>The shot that impressed Epps the most was Cabrera's drive with a 3-iron off the 10th hole in the Masters playoff. With Scott already comfortably in the fairway after hitting 3-wood, Cabrera chased his iron stinger down to the bottom of the hill.</p><p>"The magical shot I thought was the 3-iron in the playoff off 10,&rdquo; Epps said. "He wanted to hit first into 10. In regular play he hit 3-wood through the fairway and made bogey. That's the shotmaker in Angel. Not many can hit a 3-iron quail-high 280 yards.&rdquo;</p><p>The level of golf by both players in the last hour of Sunday was superb. Cabrera is not the kind of player to dwell on all the shots that could have gone in and given him the win. He burned the lip of the cup for birdie on the 17th hole in regulation. His chip on the first playoff hole looked perfect until it slipped barely past the hole. His birdie attempt on the second playoff hole needed to break a fraction more and it would have put all the pressure on Scott to answer him.</p><p>"I hit them like I wanted but I went away with empty hands,&rdquo; Cabrera said with a shrug.</p><p>The week after the Masters, Cabrera returned to his home Cordoba Golf Club in Argentina for the Abierto del Centro. He chipped in for eagle on the 18th hole to cap a Sunday 64, rallying from six shots down to earn a berth in a playoff against Rafael Gmez. This time Cabrera won with a birdie on the first playoff hole.</p><p>"For me it is very important victory, here in Villa Allende, with my people, my house,&rdquo; Cabrera said. "And that it belongs to the PGA Tour Latinoamerica for me is an honor.&rdquo;</p><p>Things have been less positive for Cabrera since. Nursing a sore left shoulder that might eventually require surgery, Cabrera, now 44, has made only one cut in five starts this season on the PGA Tour. His five-year Tour exemption for winning the 2009 Masters runs out after this season, meaning Cabrera needs to finish in the top 125 on the FedEx Cup points list to retain his card.</p><p>He currently ranks 208th.</p><p>"Last year is gone,&rdquo; he said. "I'm going to practice. I still have many tournaments to play. I'll try to arrive at Augusta in the best shape possible as usual, and I will try to play well.&rdquo;</p><p>The Masters is a safe haven for him as he hasn't missed a cut at Augusta since 2005 and has six career top 10s. He remains a threat any time he shows up.</p><p>"When I stop wanting to go there, I won't go,&rdquo; he said.</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 06:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2614 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Barnbougle doesn't take back seat to great Aussie courses</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/barnbougle-doesnt-take-back-seat-great-aussie-courses</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>BRIDPORT, Tasmania - If the quality of the golf experience is proportional to the effort it takes to get there, Barnbougle is at the top of the destination golf food chain.</p> <p>Or perhaps the bottom, since Tasmania is south of Down Under.</p> <p>Barnbougle Dunes and its younger sister course, Lost Farm, have taken the Ban&shy;don Dunes experience to the rugged northwest coast of Australia's remote island state. And with the shrewd influence of Bandon's visionary Mike Keiser, Tasmanian potato and cattle farmer Richard Sattler has created a bucket-list golf experience that makes remote Oregon seem downright suburban in its proximity.</p> <p>The original Barnbougle Dunes course &ndash; designed by Tom Doak and Michael Clayton &ndash; opened in 2004 along the Bass Strait that separates Tassie from the Australian mainland. Barnbougle Lost Farm followed in 2010, a solo effort by Bill Coore without his usual partner Ben Crenshaw.</p> <p>Despite their youth, the two already reside in the hierarchy of great Australian courses in the company of the famed Sand Belt venues of Royal Melbourne and Kingston Heath. The two new links rank Nos. 4 and 6 respectively in Australia and Nos. 11 and 23 in Golf Digest's inaugural list of the world's 100 greatest courses.</p> <p>Having played six of Aus&shy;tralia's other eight top-10 courses on a recent trip Down Under, there's no arguing that Barnbougle's place among the greats is justified. It's worth the effort to get there to play in a place that boasts the cleanest air on the planet in a state that is 40 percent covered by parks and preserves.</p> <p>"It can hold its own with any of the iconic courses around the world,&rdquo; said Tasmania native Matthew Goggin, a PGA Tour pro.</p> <p>Remote destination golf is not necessarily a new phenomenon. Old Tom Morris expanded the Machrihanish links on a distant edge of Scotland's Kintyre Peninsula in 1879. It takes great effort to get there today, yet many still make the journey. Pinehurst wasn't exactly founded in the commercial epicenter of the South, yet it has thrived as a golf mecca for more than a century in the North Carolina sandhills.</p> <p>The best pieces of property aren't always the most accessible, but golfers will go to any lengths to seek out the perfect experience. The build-it-and-they-will-come mentality has taken off in the past couple decades. Sand Hills in the barren expanse of Nebraska opened in 1995 and soared to the top tier of the golf rankings. Bandon Dunes first brought attention to the rugged coastal cliffs and dunes of Oregon in 1999, and it has expanded to a full-service 85-hole resort that ranks as America's best despite the massive effort it requires to get there.</p> <p>New destination resorts are luring golfers to the coast of Nova Scotia (Cabot Links) and reclaimed phosphate mines in the desolate interior of Florida (Streamsong). The more remote the better, it seems.</p> <p>This is what Keiser sold Sattler on when he visited the site (at the persistent urging of Greg Ramsey, a Barn&shy;bougle neighbor) and talked the farmer into becoming a golf entrepreneur. The unpretentious Sattler was no stranger to the hotel business in Hobart, but his farming land and the heaving dunes that separated it from the sea was the draw.</p> <p>"Spuds are a better story,&rdquo; Sattler admits of his background that is part of the Barnbougle experience.</p> <p>It doesn't get more remote than Tasmania. By any standard, the island state south of Australia is about as far away as you can get. It's a 15-hour flight from Los Angeles to Sydney just to reach the proper time zone, and then you still have another body of water to pass over.</p> <p>Launceston, Tasmania, is only a 75-minute flight from Sydney (barely 60 minutes from Melbourne), and from the airport it's only a 90-minute drive to Barnbougle (which rhymes with Google). However, don't take the Google Maps suggested shortest route along the Tasman Highway (A3) through Scotts&shy;dale. It's certainly a scenic crossing over the Sideling Range, but it makes the famous Road to Hana in Maui seem like a Kansas interstate with its string of mountain switchbacks. Any passengers in your vehicle will thank you for taking the extra seven minutes on the relatively flat A8 route toward George Town before crossing over to Bridport on the B82.</p> <p>Once at Barnbougle, you'll be hard-pressed to find any reason to leave the property. The two courses are connected by an interior gravel road. There are cozy cabins and luxurious four-bedroom villas right along the first hole at the Dunes and a string of spacious hotel rooms right at the heart of Lost Farm.</p> <p>While the restaurant and bar at the Dunes clubhouse serves intermediate casual fare, the restaurant at Lost Farm situated atop the highest dune has the prettiest view of the course and Anderson Bay. It's a spectacular setting to watch the long, slow sunset over Bridport while you savor its prime Cape Grim beef with the perfect Aussie shiraz.</p> <p>Lost Farm also has a casual sports bar that serves a terrific house-made pizza and plenty of James Boags and Carlton Draught after your round. There's also a dune-top spa to rest your weary body after walking the 20-hole Lost Farm layout.</p> <p>But it's the golf that brings you there and leaves you thrilled that you made the trip. Both the Dunes and Lost Farm courses offer expansive fairways between the dunes. But all that room can turn claustrophobic when the wind blows &ndash; which it does pretty consistently in the afternoons. When 20-30 mph gusts start buffeting Lost Farm, the sprinklers get turned on only in the bunkers to keep the sand from blowing away.</p> <p>It's that kind of wind that turns the tiny par-3 fourth at Lost Farm or seventh at the Dunes into one of the most terrifying wedge holes. From only 100 meters on Lost Farm's fourth, a wedge aimed at the water on the right can end up lost in the grass wide left &ndash; 50 yards off the line it started on.</p> <p>If you miss the fairways or hundreds of scattered bunkers, the local rule is much more forgiving than the marrum grass that protects the dunes. A search is more likely to turn up a poisonous tiger snake or petite wallaby than your golf ball. So the rule anywhere is to drop at the nearest point to where your ball went in and play on with just a stroke penalty.</p> <p>The more established Dunes course offers two distinctly different nines. The front side meanders down through the dunes with a nice mix of short and long holes. The back is more exposed along the plateaus, with sweeping views on every hole of the sea or the Forrester River that separates the two courses.</p> <p>Lost Farm features larger dunes and more dramatic features &ndash; including bunkers you could get lost in. Its most famous hole features a blind drive over a massive dune to the dogleg fairway, which many liken to the famous Road Hole at St. Andrews. Its "back 11&rdquo; offers two extra short par-3s to give you even more bang for your buck.</p> <p>Sattler is considering adding a third links course on more of the adjacent dunes and perhaps a fourth inland course to offer visitors some relief from the coastal winds.</p> <p>Barnbougle has no real estate component and zero members, "because one member is too many,&rdquo; Sattler said. It's just an idyllic destination that scratches all the right itches for the golf traveler.</p> ]]></description>
<pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 05:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2595 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Aussies had plenty of close calls at Masters</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/aussies-had-plenty-close-calls-masters</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/GOLF_NOTES_NY151_4861147.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Greg Norman's list of close calls at the Masters Tournament is legendary.</p><p>There's 1986, when the popular Australian came to the 72nd hole tied with Jack Nicklaus. Norman pushed his approach far right on No. 18 and made bogey, and Nicklaus walked away with his sixth green jacket.</p><p>A year later, the Great White Shark found himself in a three-way playoff with Seve Ballesteros and Augusta native Larry Mize. The hometown boy holed a miraculous chip from 140 feet on the second playoff hole to leave Norman empty-handed again.</p><p>Those two close calls, however, were nothing compared with Norman's downfall in 1996. Like Ken Venturi's collapse 40 years earlier, Norman could blame no one but himself.</p><p>Norman was the top-ranked golfer in the world, and Nick Faldo wasn't far behind. The best days of Masters legends such as Nicklaus and Tom Watson were behind them, and no young superstars had emerged at Augusta National Golf Club. Tiger Woods, still an amateur, missed the cut that year.</p><p>All signs pointed to a "Norman conquest&rdquo; in 1996 as he opened the Masters with a record-tying 63. The score matched his good friend Nick Price's 9-under round in 1986 as the best in tournament history.</p><p>A 69 in the second round and a 71 in the third put Norman six ahead of Faldo and seven clear of Phil Mickelson going into the final round.</p><p>Norman's failure to hold 54-hole leads in majors had been duly noted by the press. After all, he achieved the "Saturday Slam&rdquo; in 1986: He led all four majors through three rounds, but won only the British Open that year. Still, veteran Augusta observers figured this would be the year Norman would get his green jacket. The headline in Sunday's Augusta Chronicle read, "Shark Smells Blood.&rdquo;</p><p>Even Faldo, who had won back-to-back Masters in 1989 and 1990 with impressive comebacks, figured it was Norman's year to win.</p><p>Norman and Faldo teed off under perfect conditions that Sunday, and it didn't take long for Norman to show signs of vulnerability. He bogeyed the first hole but came back with birdie at No. 2, then made bogeys on Nos. 4 and 9 for a 38. Faldo played the front in 2-under 34, and as the two set off on the final nine, the margin had been reduced to two.</p><p>The pressure was now squarely on Norman, who promptly made bogeys on Nos. 10 and 11 to see the rest of his lead disappear.</p><p>Faldo &ndash; the cool, calculating Brit &ndash; applied more pressure on the 12th when he hit the green with his tee shot. Now it was Norman's turn, and his iron shot hung out to the right. The ball hit the bank and trickled into Rae's Creek, leading to a double bogey. Augusta's patrons, not to mention millions of television viewers, were in shock: Norman now trailed by two.</p><p>Norman matched Faldo over the next three holes with two birdies and a par, but came to the 16th still trailing. He hooked his tee shot so far left that it found the pond that guards the green, and the resulting double bogey left him down four. After that tee shot, Norman bent over at the waist and stared at the ground, and the resulting image became the cover shot for the following week's Sports Illustrated.</p><p>It was over, and Norman's day of celebration had gone worse than anyone could have imagined. His 78 to Faldo's 67 left him five behind, and it set a record for futility as the biggest blown lead in major championship history.</p><p>"Nick played good golf, and I played poorly,&rdquo; Norman said. "You can make up a lot of shots when that happens. It's not the end of the world for me. I'm not going to fall off the edge of the world because of what happened.&rdquo;</p><p>It also extended Norman's misery at Augusta. Only Tom Weiskopf finished as runner-up in the Masters more times (four) without winning than Norman.</p><p>Norman was gracious in defeat, and he put it in perspective in his session with reporters after the round.</p><p>"I let this one get away,&rdquo; Norman said. "I'll wake up tomorrow morning still breathing, I hope.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>BRUCE CRAMPTON</p><p>Bruce Crampton achieved a lot in his 19 appearances at the Masters Tournament.</p><p>He won the Par-3 Contest in 1962.</p><p>He set a record for most eagles in a single tournament with four in 1974.</p><p>But the Australian never would slip on the green jacket that goes to the winner. His best showing came in 1972, when he tied for second behind Jack Nicklaus.</p><p>It was the best showing by an Australian in the Masters, and it foreshadowed what was to come for golfers from Down Under until Adam Scott's victory in Augusta in 2013.</p><p>Nicklaus won his fourth green jacket that year despite scores that became progressively worse with each day of the tournament.</p><p>Crampton fell eight shots behind Nicklaus after opening with rounds of 72 and 75.</p><p>But the Australian cut that deficit in half with a 69 in the third round, and he shot 73 to Nicklaus's 74 in the final round.</p><p>"This is one of my greatest thrills,&rdquo; Crampton said after the final round in 1972. "But I have to rank winning the Australian Open in my own native land as my top thrill. If I ever came in first here, I would probably have to change my mind.&rdquo;</p><p>The native of Sydney would go on to win 42 tournaments worldwide, including 14 on the PGA Tour, but he never broke through to win a major championship.</p><p>For that he can blame Nicklaus.</p><p>Two months after his runner-up finish at the Masters, Crampton was second to Nicklaus again at the 1972 U.S. Open.</p><p>Then, in 1973 and 1975, Crampton was second in the PGA Championship. The winner of both of those majors also was Nicklaus.</p><p>But Crampton said after the 1972 Masters that he didn't regret his decision to come to the United States in the 1950s.</p><p>"I came to America to play against the best players in the world,&rdquo; he said. "It's the equivalent of playing in the Super Bowl every week. Only this week (the Masters), it's the Super-Super Bowl.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>JIM FERRIER</p><p>Before Peter Thomson's dominance in the British Open in the 1950s, and way before Greg Norman's near misses at Augusta, there was Jim Ferrier.</p><p>The Australian golfer isn't a household name for most golf fans. Born in Sydney, Ferrier dominated the amateur scene in Australia in the 1930s before deciding that he would turn professional and move to the United States.</p><p>That was in the 1940s, and because of World War II Ferrier and his wife had to take jobs in the defense industry in order to become American citizens, according to one biography. Perhaps that is why Ferrier isn't listed as an Australian in the Masters media guide.</p><p>Ferrier is credited as the first Australian to win a major, and it came at the 1947 PGA. In those days the PGA was contested at match play, and Ferrier beat Chick Harbert 2 and 1 in the finals.</p><p>Ferrier went on to win 18 PGA Tour events, and he claimed victory in another 10 tournaments on the Australasian tour.</p><p>At the Masters, Ferrier played 15 times between 1940 and 1965. From 1946 to 1952, he only finished out of the top 10 once.</p><p>In 1950, Ferrier was in excellent position to become the first foreign-born golfer to win at Augusta National. Tied with Ben Hogan for the 54-hole lead, Ferrier played the first nine holes in 34. Victory appeared imminent for the big Australian.</p><p>With Hogan on his way to 76, Ferrier's only other pursuer was Jimmy Demaret. The two-time Masters champion was playing well ahead of Ferrier and posted 69 to take the clubhouse lead.</p><p>With six holes to play, Ferrier had a two-shot cushion. But things started to fall apart at the par-5 13th, when he made bogey. A 3-putt at the 14th cost him another shot. He did par the 15th, but he closed with three consecutive bogeys for an inward nine of 41 and a final round of 75.</p><p>Ferrier's collapse allowed Demaret to become the first three-time winner of the Masters.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>JACK NEWTON</p><p>Jack Newton (right) could hardly believe what he was seeing.</p><p>Playing alongside Seve Ballesteros in the final round of the 1980 Masters Tournament, Newton found himself 10 shots behind as the two played the front nine.</p><p>Then the young Spaniard, who had a chance to establish the 72-hole scoring record, began unraveling. Ballesteros played Nos. 10-13 in 4-over fashion.</p><p>Newton, meanwhile, reeled off birdies at all three holes of Amen Corner. Suddenly, he was only three behind with five to play.</p><p>"I never really thought I had a chance on the front side,&rdquo; Newton said. "I knew I had a chance on the back, but I felt like I had to do something like eagle 13 or 15.&rdquo;</p><p>But the Australian missed his eagle putt on the 13th, and then three-putted the 15th after hitting the par-5 hole in two shots. Ballesteros birdied the 15th, and order was restored as he cruised to a four-shot win over Newton and Gibby Gilbert.</p><p>"I really think I needed to make the eagle putt on 13,&rdquo; Newton said after the round. "When I three-putted 15 that was the end of it.&rdquo;</p><p>Newton had never fared particularly well in three previous trips to the Masters, but in 1980 he figured out Augusta National with three rounds in the 60s.</p><p>He also wasn't afraid of Ballesteros, who became the youngest Masters winner at the time.</p><p>"I felt that I played well enough all week to push him, but that's the way golf is,&rdquo; Newton said. "It was his week to win.&rdquo;</p><p>Newton won nine times in his professional career. Prior to the 1980 Masters, his best chance to win a major came at the 1975 British Open. He lost an 18-hole playoff to Tom Watson at Carnoustie.</p><p>Newton's playing career was cut short when he suffered a horrific accident in the summer of 1983. A propeller hit Newton as he tried to board an airplane, costing him his right arm and eye, and he suffered abdominal injuries that were life-threatening.</p><p>Newton recovered, even learning to play the game one-handed, and went on to have a successful career as a TV analyst.</p><p>He said the pinnacle of his career was winning the 1979 Australian Open. But his performance at the 1980 Masters also was a highlight.</p><p>"I'm very satisfied with this, too,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p></p><p>JASON DAY</p><p>With three runner-up finishes in major championships, Jason Day figures it's just a matter of time before he breaks through.</p><p>"As long as I keep knocking on the door, I think I'll win a major here soon,&rdquo; the 25-year-old Australian said.</p><p>His peers, and most experts, would agree.</p><p>Day's latest brush with a major came in June at the U.S. Open. He tied for second, two shots behind winner Justin Rose, at Merion Golf Club.</p><p>Day made bogey on the difficult closing hole, while Rose was able to make par.</p><p>"I think I've just got to keep putting myself in position to win,&rdquo; Day said. "And I feel that my game is in a really good spot right now. I'm doing the right things. I'm doing the little things that count.&rdquo;</p><p>Day earned his other runner-up finishes in majors in 2011. At the Masters Tournament, he and countryman Adam Scott were two shots behind Charl Schwartzel. At the U.S. Open, Day was a distant second as Rory McIlroy romped to an eight-shot victory.</p><p>"I've been close so many times now in majors, especially at a young age, which is nice,&rdquo; Day said at Merion. "I'm still 25. I turn 26 at the end of the year. I've got plenty of majors to play in and hopefully I can keep doing the same as I'm doing, and hopefully win one soon.&rdquo;</p><p>Day has had a couple of close calls at Augusta National Golf Club. In the second round in 2011, Day blitzed the layout with an 8-under-par 64 that was one stroke off the course record.</p><p>Paired in the final round with Scott, the two Aussies posted impressive scores but ultimately lost to Schwartzel's historic finish.</p><p>"I didn't expect that Charl would come back with four birdies to finish it off,&rdquo; Day said. "But hats off to him. I'm very happy with the way I handled myself out there.&rdquo;</p><p>At last year's Masters, both Day and Scott were in the mix in the final round. Day seized the lead with birdies at Nos. 13, 14 and 15 in the final round.</p><p>But he gave two shots back with bogeys at Nos. 16 and 17, and missed out on the playoff between Scott and Angel Cabrera. All Day could do was sit and cheer his countryman as Scott birdied the second hole of a sudden-death playoff to give Australia its first green jacket.</p><p>Day said that whether he wins a major is up to him.</p><p>"If I want it enough and I'm willing to do the hard work and practice and keep myself dedicated, I think it will happen,&rdquo; Day said. "If I slack off and don't do the work then it won't happen. And that's just plain and simple.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>DAVID GRAHAM</p><p>David Graham wasn't surprised at how Australia reacted when Adam Scott won the Masters Tournament.</p><p>After all, Graham was the first Aussie to take home the U.S. Open title. He achieved that feat in 1981 at Merion Golf Club outside Philadelphia.</p><p>Graham remembers a similar celebration for him back home. He also was happy to see his countryman bounce back after squandering a big lead at the British Open in 2012.</p><p>"I think that everybody that plays competitively, and we all saw what happened to Adam Scott at the Open Championship, we all dreaded that ever happening to us,&rdquo; Graham said at last year's U.S. Open. "And to see someone that's got the golf game and the fortitude and the heart and the guts and the desire to put that behind them and come back and win a major championship is a true testament to his abilities mentally and skill-wise.&rdquo;</p><p>Graham, now 67, enjoyed a career with 38 worldwide wins and two major championships. He won the 1979 PGA Championship to go along with his victory at Merion.</p><p>The Australian came of age when golfers were just becoming more comfortable with competing overseas on a regular basis.</p><p>"I think that it's great that golf has become such a global sport,&rdquo; Graham said. "And I think that you've got to look back to when (Arnold) Palmer and (Jack) Nicklaus and Player &ndash; Gary Player won seven Australian Opens in the late &lsquo;60s through the mid-'70s. I mean traveling from South Africa. We didn't have nonstop flights from Joburg to Sydney in those days. (Lee) Trevino came and played in Australia. That's where guys of my era, that's where we saw the best players play. Jack Nicklaus won six Australian Opens in the late '60s and '70s.&rdquo;</p><p>While Graham never seriously contended for a Masters title &ndash; his best finish was fifth in 1980 &ndash; he understood the value of playing around the world. He collected wins on the PGA Tour, European Tour, Japan Golf Tour and PGA Tour of Australasia.</p><p>"It's great that we see modern day players continuing to make it a global sport by going overseas and showing the world what great golf is,&rdquo; Graham said. "It's a wonderful thing to see.&rdquo;</p><p>The current state of the game astonishes Graham.</p><p>"I never thought I would see in my lifetime where I think six of the top 10 players were from Europe,&rdquo; he said. "And if you would have told me that 30 years ago, I would have said you've got to be kidding. No one envisioned the game would grow as much as it has and it's great for the sport.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2014 23:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2594 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>2013 Masters featured plenty of firsts</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/2013-masters-featured-plenty-firsts</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/MAS6012GuanADT.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>The 2013 Masters Tournament was filled with firsts &ndash; headed by Adam Scott becoming the first Australian to don the green jacket.</p><p>Scott birdied two of his final four holes in regulation for 3-under-par 69 and beat 2009 winner Angel Cabrera, of Argentina, on the second hole of sudden death.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Scott was the first golfer to win the Masters using an anchored putting stroke. He could also be the last. Just over a month after the 2013 Masters, the U.S. Golf Association banned anchoring starting January 2016, meaning there are only two more years where anchoring will be allowed in the Masters.</p><p>Australians had won 15 major championships, but none at Augusta National until Scott did it, though they had numerous runner-up finishes, including three by Greg Norman.</p><p>"It's amazing that it's my destiny to be the first Aussie to win. It's incredible,&rdquo; Scott said.</p><p>Scott called himself a "proud Au&shy;stral&shy;ian&rdquo; after closing out a 6-under weekend with rounds of 69-69. He ended up leading the field in greens in regulation, hitting 55 of 72 for a 76.39 percentage.</p><p>The first Aus&shy;tralian winner at Augusta Na&shy;tional came in a year when the number of participants from that country was down. Only four Aussies qualified, the fewest since the same number played in 2002.</p><p>It was a strong group, though. Scott won; Day, who led after 36 holes, finished third; and first-round co-leader Marc Leishman tied for fourth. John Sen&shy;den, the other Aussie, tied for 35th, but he was one shot out of the lead at one point during the second round.</p><p>Late in the final round, Day appeared on track to be the first Australian winner, but he bogeyed two of his final three holes for 70 to finish two shots out of the playoff.</p><p>Scott said he received "incredible support from everyone in the crowd&rdquo; in the final round.</p><p>"I really felt they were on my side a little bit in regulation coming down the last couple holes,&rdquo; he said. "They wanted me to do something, and that's a great feeling. I didn't want to disappoint them, either.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott didn't. On the 18th hole, he rolled in a 28-foot birdie putt to take a one-shot lead over Cabrera, who was in the group behind him and watching from the fairway. Scott had seen Mark O'Meara in 1998 make a similar putt to win the Mas&shy;ters.</p><p>"You've seen the read,&rdquo; Scott said. "You know it goes a bit right to left. I just told myself to go with instinct; just put it out there and hit it. Show everyone how much you want it. This is the chance, put all the pressure on the guy back down the fairway.&rdquo;</p><p>Cabrera answered with a birdie of his own to shoot 70 and force the playoff. After both men parred the first playoff hole, No. 18, they headed down No. 10, the same hole that Cabrera made par to beat Kenny Perry in their 2009 playoff.</p><p>It was on the 10th fairway that Scott felt the gallery's support again.</p><p>"I think going down the 10th fairway was almost deafening, and the crowd wasn't close,&rdquo; he said. "It was a great feeling, and again, I felt like they were really, really pulling for me out there.&rdquo;</p><p>Those fans were able to celebrate with Scott soon enough. Both men hit the green on No. 10. After Cabrera barely missed his 15-footer for birdie, Scott, with an assist on the read from caddie Steve Williams, rolled in his 12-foot birdie putt for the win.</p><p>"I said, &lsquo;Do you think it's just more than a cup ' &rdquo; Scott said. "He said, &lsquo;It's at least two cups; it's going to break more than you think.' &hellip; He was my eyes on that putt. An unbelievable read.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott contended in two of the majors after the Masters, tying for third at the British Open and tied for fifth in the PGA Championship. In his next start after the PGA, in late August, he won The Barclays, moving up to a career-best No. 2 ranking in the world. He finished fourth in the FedEx Cup playoffs after tying for 14th place in the season-ending Tour Championship.</p><p>Earlier in the week, before Scott's heroics, the Masters field had to share some of the spotlight with a teenager who finished 58th.</p><p>That someone, of course, was China's Tianlang Guan, who at age 14 became the youngest-ever Masters participant. Guan, the lone amateur to make the cut, shot 73-75-77-75.</p><p>In still another first, Guan received the first slow-play penalty in tournament history. He was given a one-stroke penalty on the 17th hole in the second round, turning a par into a bogey and 74 into 75.</p><p>He still made the cut on the number (4-over 148) thanks to his stellar work on the greens. Guan would end up tying for the fewest putts in the tournament with 108, including a 60-foot par putt on the 18th hole to close out his third round.</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2014 16:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2591 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Mayor's Masters Reception won't be held this year</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/mayors-masters-reception-wont-be-held-year</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>The Mayor's Masters Reception will not be held this year, organizer Wayne Hawkins confirmed Tuesday.</p><p>The annual event, which was held Monday of Masters Week, could not find a Masters Tournament participant who would commit to attend. The event began in 1999 and had been held for 15 consecutive years.</p><p>"We never could get a yes,&rdquo; Hawkins said. "Got a whole lot of nos, and we ran out of time.&rdquo;</p><p>The reception featured a prominent golfer who was given a key to the city, and the event included a sampling of food from area businesses and restaurants.</p><p>Past participants included Arnold Palmer, Jack Nicklaus and Gary Player, and the 2013 honoree was Craig Stadler.</p><p>The Mayor's Masters Reception featured multiple golfers at its beginning, then shifted its format to honor a single golfer beginning in 2004, Hawkins said.</p><p>"There's not that many of the old ones left,&rdquo; Hawkins said.</p><p>He said he will try again for 2015 and will discuss with the committee at an upcoming meeting.</p><p>"We'll discuss what direction we want to go in,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>&nbsp;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Tue, 04 Mar 2014 21:49:07 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2588 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Climax of 2013 Masters brought drama, sportsmanship</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/climax-2013-masters-brought-drama-sportsmanship</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0406ScottLeishman.jpg" /></div><p>&nbsp;</p><p>Golf relishes its tales of sportsmanship and cherishes moments of major drama. Rarely, however, do the two collide.</p><p>The epic head-to-head final-round showdown between Tom Watson and Jack Nick&shy;laus in the 1977 British Open at Turnberry has long been the sport's gold standard for combining great golf with great sportsmanship.</p><p>"This is what it's all about,&rdquo; Watson famously said to Nicklaus as the pair stood tied on the 16th tee, 10 clear of the rest of the field.</p><p>"You bet it is,&rdquo; Nicklaus responded.</p><p>That famous Duel in the Sun might have to share the podium with last April's Duel in the Rain.</p><p>The final holes of regulation and playoff between Adam Scott and Angel Ca&shy;bre&shy;ra at the 2013 Masters Tourna&shy;ment were a rare confluence of brilliance and respect under the most intense pressure. The last pair standing as the rain and darkness fell down upon Augusta National elevated their performance and set a lasting example for how the game should be played.</p><p>"I think what we saw that week is guys who couldn't play harder trying to beat each other acknowledge that you can still play with sportsmanship,&rdquo; said Phil Scott, Adam's father.</p><p>Above all the great shots and clutch putts that propelled Scott and Cabrera into a thrilling battle for the green jacket, the moment of the Masters came in the middle of the second playoff hole.</p><p>The often gruff-looking Ca&shy;brera had already hit his approach shot to the 10th green to 15 feet below the pin to set up a birdie opportunity when Scott delivered a matching 6-iron that settled hole high 12 feet right of the flag. As the two walked down opposite sides of the fairway, Cabrera turned and held a thumbs-up to acknowledge Scott's shot. The Aussie returned the gesture.</p><p>"The sportsmanship is to be expected from a guy like him,&rdquo; Scott said of Cabrera. "He's all class. It came across really great when he gave me the thumbs-up and I did it back to him. The atmosphere was so loud at that point that saying something, you wouldn't be able to hear what they said anyway. So it was down to hand signals. But still, to make a gesture at that moment shows what a classy guy he is.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>SCOTT AND CABRERA were paired with Sergio Garcia in the first two rounds, and it was obvious that the 2009 champion would need to be reckoned with.</p><p>"I think he wanted it bad,&rdquo; Scott said of Cabrera. "I had this thought back to Friday. I was playing with Angel the first two days, and he ripped one over the trees on 13 on Fri&shy;day and got on a nice little run around the turn, and he couldn't have had more than a 9-iron to the green. I just thought I saw a little flicker in his eye and he could feel it this week and really wanted it.</p><p>"There's no doubt you could see that at the end &ndash; a guy who wants it bad but he was loving every moment of it. That's a guy you really have to beat because he's going for broke and he has nothing to lose. He's got a green jacket already. He's got a U.S. Open. So the level of golf was outstanding. The shots that were played were brilliant.&rdquo;</p><p>On Sunday afternoon, they were playing in consecutive groups at the back of the field, and as the holes ran out Cabrera was literally chasing Scott's lead once Australian Jason Day faltered with two bogeys down the stretch.</p><p>Scott birdied No. 15 after a brilliant 4-iron reached the green to get to 8-under par. Cabrera answered with a birdie on No. 16 to tie.</p><p>Cabrera scorched the lip of the cup for a birdie chance on No. 17 and went to the 18th tee all square.</p><p>It was from his spot in the center of the 18th fairway, 163 yards away, that Cabrera stood under his umbrella and watched Scott sink his 28-foot birdie putt that sparked a raucous celebration on the green. But the two-time major winner didn't wilt in the moment.</p><p>With the hardest rain of the day pelting down, Cabrera delivered a dart of a 9-iron that checked up less than 3 feet from the pin.</p><p>He flashed a smile and fist-bumped his son, Angelito, who was carrying the bag.</p><p>"There really wasn't much conversation,&rdquo; Cabrera said of his deliberations in the fairway. "I saw Scott make his 3, and I said, &lsquo;OK, we've got to make 3.' That's about all that was said.&rdquo;</p><p>A few minutes later, he calmly drained the putt to force the playoff.</p><p>If there was any fear that Aus&shy;tralia was destined to have another green jacket stolen away, it didn't register for long with Scott.</p><p>"I felt like I'd done everything I could to win and he was going to make that putt, so I think I was instantly gutted,&rdquo; Scott said. "But I thought, you know, you don't get handed majors. You've got to earn it. Now it's down to me and him in a sudden-death playoff. My odds are 50/50, so I may as well go for it. Again, it was an excitement thing. If you're not excited about that, then you're not doing the right thing. That's really what I want.&rdquo;</p><p>"I was in the scorer's room with Scotty when (Cabrera) hit that shot, and his reaction showed me that he was ready to go another hole,&rdquo; fellow Aus&shy;sie Marc Leishman said. "He thought he'd won it on the 18th, but when I saw his reaction it was like, &lsquo;All right, we're going another hole.' It wasn't like, &lsquo;Oh no.' He was ready to go.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>THE SHOWDOWN resumed head-to-head in sudden death. More often than not, Mas&shy;ters playoffs have been anticlimactic as the tension mounts. Five of the previous nine sudden-death playoffs in the Masters were won with a par or bogey. Another was extended by a missed 30-inch putt by Scott Hoch.</p><p>This one was different.</p><p>"The golf was amazing, and because Angel played so good it made it look even better,&rdquo; Scott said. "The golf over the last three or four holes and the playoff was first class. That doesn't always happen under that kind of pressure, but it just did that day.&rdquo;</p><p>Both striped perfect drives down the narrow 18th fairway. Between clubs, both hit approaches that sucked back off the front of the green within 8 feet of each other. Cabrera hit a chip that once again peeked into the hole before slipping a foot past.</p><p>"I was standing on the edge of the green, and it really did have that look where it could go in,&rdquo; Scott said. "A massive sense of relief went through me as it just slipped by the edge of the hole. I basically thought I got given a life there and don't be a hero and try to hole it yourself now. It's not the time.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott skidded his chip to 3 feet and made the knee-knocker to send the playoff to the downhill 10th hole.</p><p>Once again both players found the fairway, Scott with a driver and Cabrera with a 3-iron stinger that traveled almost as far. They hit matching 6-irons so purely under the circumstances that it needed to be acknowledged with the mutual thumbs-up.</p><p>"OMG, both players thumbs up &hellip; so classy. Now I want both to win,&rdquo; tweeted tennis legend Chris Evert, echoing the trending sentiment from golf fans.</p><p>Cabrera said his gesture was no big deal.</p><p>"Golf is a sport and not a war,&rdquo; he said. "Whoever I play with, if he hits a good shot, I tell him good shot.&rdquo;</p><p>Cabrera putted first and threatened the cup, with the big right-to-left breaker holding its line less than a ball above the hole. He tapped in and left the damp and darkened floor to Scott to either win it or bring them back Monday to finish.</p><p>"Angel hit an unbelievable putt again that looked like it could go in, and I thought this is my time, this is the moment,&rdquo; Scott said. "I don't think we were going to play another hole that night. I think we were going to go home and sleep and it would have been no sleep there. It was then or never in my mind.&rdquo;</p><p>Facing the putt of his life, Scott leaned on faith in his caddie, Steve Williams. The New Zealander won 13 majors with Tiger Woods and had patrolled Augusta with the likes of Greg Norman and Ray Floyd before that. So Scott called on him for the read.</p><p>"It was pretty dark down there, and my eyesight at that point really wasn't the best,&rdquo; Scott said. "I said I think it's a cup to the right at good speed, and he said it's two cups to the right at good speed. He's been going there 30-something years so I didn't have much grounds to argue with him. I figured he must have seen the putt a little bit. Again, it's one of those situations where you just have to will the ball into the hole and show how much you want it. Managed to put a good stroke on it, and in it went.&rdquo;</p><p>&nbsp;</p><p>THE BIRDIE EVOKED a second unbridled celebration from Scott, who delivered victory not just for himself but also for his country, which had endured so many Masters heartbreaks.</p><p>In that moment, yet another gesture of sportsmanship broke through.</p><p>Cabrera let Scott enjoy the moment before clutching him in a warm embrace and whispering something to his Pres&shy;idents Cup teammate. Despite his personal disappointment, his manner illustrated a measure of pride in his opponent.</p><p>"That I was happy for him; that I know that he deserved it, and that he was going to eventually win it like he did right now,&rdquo; Cabrera said. "It was just a matter of time. &hellip; He's a great person, a great player.&rdquo;</p><p>Scott appreciated the friendly remarks.</p><p>"I think it was very genuine,&rdquo; he said. "He must have been gutted. I couldn't imagine how I would have felt if I'd lost down there on the 10th green. He said he was so happy for me.&rdquo;</p><p>Said Scott's father: "Whatever Angel felt at that moment, he's got some class to have done what he did. I'm sure he was proud of how he played, and maybe there was enough there that he needs to think, &lsquo;I didn't lose this thing.'&rdquo;</p><p>Cabrera's only disappointment was not winning and not with his effort.</p><p>"I hit them like I wanted, but I went away with empty hands,&rdquo; he said.</p><p>Before the Masters, a Ti&shy;ger Woods commercial debuted with the message that "winning takes care of everything.&rdquo; That was not the message Scott and Cabrera delivered with their mutual skill and grace under pressure.</p><p>"Perhaps one of the great things that we will always remember is that bit of sportsmanship that made people realize that you can play as hard as you want and try to beat the other guy up and you can actually still be nice,&rdquo; Phil Scott said. "Maybe there's been too much emphasis on winning is everything. Of course everyone wants to win, but it's how you win. That's an old-fashioned adage that's perhaps forgotten a bit.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2014 23:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2585 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Ike gets his wish thanks to Mother Nature</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/ike-gets-his-wish-thanks-mother-nature</link>
<description><![CDATA[<p>After nearly 60 years, the late Dwight D. Eisenhower appealed to a higher authority and finally got his wish.</p><p>Mother Nature did what original club chairman Clifford Roberts refused to do and tore down the most famous pine at Augusta National Golf Club &ndash; the Eisenhower Tree.</p><p>Masters Tournament chairman Billy Payne confirmed the news Sunday evening that the damage suffered from last week's major ice storm was too much for the nearly 125-year-old tree to handle.</p><p>With trees damaged all over Augusta by this week's destructive ice storm, it stood to reason that even Augusta National would not be immune to the harsh consequences.</p><p>"Like so many of our family, friends and neighbors in this community, Augusta National Golf Club has been busy cleaning up after the historic ice storm last week,&rdquo; Payne said. "Everyone affected remains in our hearts and prayers, and we likewise hope for a speedy and complete recovery for all.&rdquo;</p><p>Despite initial reports of minor damage, a picture surfaced over the weekend that showed significant damage to the majestic loblolly pine that guarded the left half of the 17th fairway.</p><p>It's a picture only the former President himself &ndash; who famously hated the tree that bore his name &ndash; might smile about.</p><p>Club workers are pictured cleaning up broken and pruned limbs from the loblolly pine that is the most defining feature of the 17th hole. Standing roughly 65 feet tall and situated about 210 yards from the Masters tee, the wide pine stood sentinel on the course throughout its history.</p><p>While the top-most branch seemed to be intact, gaping sections were missing from its once broad canopy &ndash; particularly on the left side which was almost stripped of all of its branches. The aging pine has been held together for years by numerous cables, but the latest scars were stark.</p><p>The damage proved too extensive for the club to salvage and the landmark was removed over the weekend.</p><p>Sources have claimed for years that Augusta National already has a reserve loblolly pine picked out and awaiting the call at an undisclosed location in Georgia. But whether the backup tree survived the ice storm intact is unknown, as are the club's plans for the 17th hole.</p><p>"We have begun deliberations of the best way to address the future of the 17th hole and to pay tribute to this iconic symbol of our history &ndash; rest assured, we will do both appropriately,&rdquo; Payne said.</p><p>Payne said "the golf course sustained no major damage otherwise. We are now open for member play and we will be unaffected in our preparations for the 2014 Masters Tournament.&rdquo;</p><p>The famous pine tree on No. 17 got its name from Eisenhower, who was a club member from 1948 until his death in 1969. Eisenhower reportedly hit into the tree so often that he campaigned to have it removed. At the club's 1956 governors meeting, the sitting president proposed cutting it down only to have Roberts promptly rule him out of order and adjourn the meeting. The pine has been known as Eisenhower's Tree ever since.</p><p>The tree has played a role in the outcome of many Masters through the years. Tommy Aaron, the 1973 Masters champion, once hit his drive into the top of the tree and never saw it come down, forcing him to take a lost-ball penalty. The next day, his marked Pinnacle fell out of the tree as he was walking past it.</p><p>Jose Maria Olazabal famously punched a 5-iron onto the green from under the tree to preserve his win in 1999.</p><p>The tree's most recent impact occurred in 2011 when Tiger Woods' drive got snagged by the tree and he injured his Achilles tendon hitting his recovery shot from an awkward stance in the pine straw underneath the low-hanging branches.</p><p>One of the first player reactions to the news regarding Ike's Tree came from 2012 Masters champion Bubba Watson after he won Sunday at Riviera: "Let's be honest, that tree was never in my way.&rdquo;</p>]]></description>
<pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2014 07:03:01 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2572 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>Augusta National's Eisenhower Tree removed after storm damage</title>
<link>http://www.augusta.com/masters/story/news/latest-news/augusta-nationals-eisenhower-tree-removed-after-storm-damage</link>
<description><![CDATA[<div class="media_box"><img src="http://www.augusta.com/sites/default/files/imagecache/590_wide/0217IkesTree1.jpg" /></div>Golf's most famous pine tree is no longer guarding the 17th hole at Augusta National Golf Club.&nbsp;The Eisenhower Tree suffered major damage in an ice storm and was removed over the weekend, the club confirmed Sunday.&nbsp;Photos showed major limb damage, particularly on the left side and top of the tree.&nbsp;"The loss of the Eisen&shy;hower Tree is difficult news to accept,&rdquo; Augusta National and Masters Chairman Billy Payne said in a prepared statement. "We obtained opinions from the best arborists available and, unfortunately, were advised that no recovery was possible.&rdquo;&nbsp;The Masters landmark, also known as Ike's Tree, was about 210 yards from the tee on the left side of the par-4 hole. The loblolly pine stood 65 feet high and was believed to be 100 to 125 years old.&nbsp;The tree was named because the former president and Augusta National member often hit into it, and at a club meeting in 1956 he proposed cutting it down. Masters co-founder Clifford Roberts ruled him out of order and adjourned the meeting, and the tree has been linked to Eisenhower ever since.&nbsp;"We have begun deliberations of the best way to address the future of the 17th hole and to pay tribute to this iconic symbol of our history &ndash; rest assured, we will do both appropriately,&rdquo; Payne said.&nbsp;Sleet and freezing rain began pelting the Augusta area Tuesday night and continued throughout Wednesday, and photos of Magnolia Lane showed several limbs and branches down as nearly an inch of ice accumulated.&nbsp;Payne said that Augusta National's layout did not receive any other major damage, and is open for member play.&nbsp;Six-time Masters winner Jack Nicklaus issued a statement Sunday about the loss of the tree."The Eisenhower Tree is such an iconic fixture and symbol of tradition at Au&shy;gus&shy;ta National,&rdquo; he said. "It was such an integral part of the game and one that will be sorely missed &hellip; I hit it so many times over the years that I don't care to comment on the names I called myself and the names I might have called the tree. &lsquo;Ike's Tree' was a kind choice. But looking back, Ike's Tree will be greatly missed.&rdquo;&nbsp;Ike's Tree isn't the only notable landmark created by Mother Nature at Augusta National.&nbsp;The magnolia trees that line the club's famous entrance date to the late 1850s, as does the "big oak tree&rdquo; behind the clubhouse. It's a popular gathering spot during Masters Week for players, officials and club members.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;CLUB STATEMENT&nbsp;Billy Payne, chairman of Augusta National and the Masters, released a statement Sunday:&nbsp;"Like so many of our family, friends and neighbors in this community, Augusta National Golf Club has been busy cleaning up after the historic ice storm last week. Everyone affected remains in our hearts and prayers, and we likewise hope for a speedy and complete recovery for all.&nbsp;"The loss of the Eisenhower Tree is difficult news to accept. We obtained opinions from the best arborists available and, unfortunately, were advised that no recovery was possible.&nbsp;"We have begun deliberations of the best way to address the future of the 17th hole and to pay tribute to this iconic symbol of our history &ndash; rest assured, we will do both appropriately.&nbsp;"I can report that the golf course sustained no major damage otherwise. We are now open for Member play and we will be unaffected in our preparations for the 2014 Masters Tournament.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;VIGNETTES ABOUT IKE'S TREE&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;LOST BALL&nbsp;1973 Masters champion Tommy Aaron had a memorable encounter with the tree one year.&nbsp;Here's Aaron's story:&nbsp;"I hit a drive there, and it hit in top of the Eisenhower pine and pollen went everywhere. And nobody moved. So I said, &lsquo;That ball stayed in the tree.' The local caddie with us said they don't stay in the tree. And I said, &lsquo;That ball stayed in the tree.'&nbsp;So we couldn't find it. We looked around, and I go back and I play another under the lost ball rule. And the next day we're walking by the tree and a ball drops out of the tree, and I know it's my ball because it had a marking on it and it was a Pinnacle.&nbsp;"So I know it was my ball. Someone told Jack Nicklaus that story and he said, &lsquo;I'm not sure I believe it.'&nbsp;But I've got a witness, my caddie, Rhett Sinclair.&rdquo;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;TIGER'S INJURY&nbsp;Tiger Woods, a four-time Masters winner, was sidelined for much of 2011 by injuries to his left knee and left Achilles tendon. He suffered those injuries while squatting to hit a shot under the Eisenhower Tree on the 17th hole in the third round of the Masters.&nbsp;His left foot got caught in the pine straw as the momentum of the swing carried him backward, he said. Woods' shot wound up in the front bunker and he saved par,&nbsp;Woods held a share of the lead in the final round and finished tied for fourth.]]></description>
<pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2014 22:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
<guid>2571 at http://www.augusta.com</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>